The following movie contains scenes
with intense lighting changes
Please illuminate the room and
watch it from a distance
Subtitles by ShanHua, January 2011
KAIJÛ DAISENSÔ
THE GIANT WAR OF MONSTERS
Produced by
TOMOYUKI TANAKA
Written by
SHIN’ICHI SEKIZAWA
Photography, Art, Sound, Lighting
H KOIZUMI, T KITA, W KONUMA, S KOJIMA
Music and Sound Arrangement
AKIRA IFUKUBE, HISASHI SHIMONAGA
Associate producers
KÔJI KAJITA, M SUZUKI, T KOIKE
Editing RYÔHEI FUJII
Composition HIROSHI MUKÔYAMA
Sound Editor SADAMASA NISHIMOTO
Developing TÔKYÔ DEVELOPING OFFICE
Directors of Photography
T ARIKAWA, S TOMIOKA, Y SHINNODA, S IIZUKA
Lighting KUICHIRÔ KISHIDA
Stunt Director FUMIO NAKADAI
Art Director A WATANABE
Associate producer SHÔ NAKANO
Staring
AKIRA TAKARADA
NICK ADAMS
KUMI MIZUNO, KEIKO SAWAI, JUN TAZAKI
YOSHIO TSUCHIYA, AKIRA KUBO
TAKAMARU SASAKI, FUYUKI MURAKAMI
YOSHIFUMI TAJIMA, KENZO TABU
NORIKO SENGOKU,
SENSHÔ MATSUMOTO, GEN SHIMIZU
TÔRU IBUKI, KAZUO SUZUKI
YASUHISA TSUTSUMI, NADAO KIRINO
TOKI SHIOZAWA, MITSUO TSUDA
TAKUZÔ KUMAGAI, KÔJI UNO
MASAAKI TACHIBANA, YUTAKA OKA
RINSAKU OGATA, TADASHI OKABE
RYÔJI SHIMIZU, HIDEKI FURUKAWA
KAMAYUKI TSUBONO, MINORU ITÔ
HARUO NAKAJIMA
MASAKI SHINOHARA, SHÔICHI HIROSE
Computer voice by
GORÔ NAYA
Special Art Director
HIDEJI TSUMURAYA
Directed by
ISHIRÔ HONDA
In 196X an unknown celestial body
occurred in the Milky Way
Earth launched an exploration
of this so called Planet X...
Fuji, call World Space Authority (W.S.A.)
Okay, Glen
World Space Authority
Spaceship P-1 calling
W.S.A here, report your position
Spaceship P-1, coordinates are
X 254
Y 3300
Z 002
Current speed is 1000 m/s
Time remaining 23h:59m:34s
Correct speed to 0.005
Keep it there until further notice
Speed corrected to 0.005
How is it going, everything alright?
Yes, food and accommodation are fine
We could do with some exercises, though
Well, you'll have plenty of it on Planet X
Professor?
Yes?
Is my sister Haron around?
Haron....eh?
Can't spot her
Please, can you take a message for her?
Tell her not to make a foolish decisions
Foolish what...?
Indeed!
Tell her to stop being so naive!
End of transmission
What's so funny?
Blow me, you're sure being her brother?!
You don't know her like me
Thank you
What's that all about between Fuji and you?
My brother has old fashioned
ideas about partnership
He wants me to move within
the boundaries of our family
making him sometimes behaving...
Sorry bothering you with my problems
Oh, that's not a problem for me!
It seems you brother has problems
to accept your recent partner?
Indeed
So, we found you eventually!
Sorry, forgotten!
Don't worry...
Professor, press waiting for some time...
I see, this way, please
Your friend, what's he doing anyway?
He is an inventor
Inventor?
Tetsuo, stop it, its unbearable!
You'll make the baby cry!
Is this sound loud enough?
It's heard from the other end of the road!
You make yourself heard, even so
why can't I find someone to buy you?
Tetsuo, Tetsuo!
I've turned it off already!
Someone's for you on the phone!
Coming!
If this 'Lady guard' shrieks
similar to her, things are sorted!
Thanks
No problem
Hello
Tetsuo Toori, that's me...
...a sales contract?
According to you Professor Sakurai
this new planet was found behind Jupiter
Yes
Why wasn't it discovered before?
Unknown objects shortly coming and
going is not unusual our galaxy
That one was not a bright one either,
hence difficult to detect
We calculated this body orbits
the sun once every 17.000 year
We also received artificial waves which
we could track down to this new planet
Does this indicate intelligent life forms?
We don't know yet, there could be
other reasons for these signals
So we have to rely on the P-1 crew
to ascertain more information
Tetsuo...
Seems to be very posh here,
how can you afford it?
Don't worry I've got good news,
I sold my invention!
Really?
I am going to sign a contract soon
Whom you sold it to?
A so called World Education Corporation
A big company, produces toys for education...
Oh, and I supposed...
What?
Are you Tetsuo Toori?
Yes, that's me
Sorry for keeping you waiting I'm
Namikawa, World Education Corporation
Here our contract, including the
licence fee agreement which we
will pay once it's on the market
Looks fine to me
Or...?
Of course...
Is this your wife?
No, but I am working on it...
May I introduce to you, Fuji Hano
Nice to meet you
You work for the W.S.A, don't you?
And your brother is Fuji, one of
the astronauts there...?
You know him?
No, but everybody is interested
in his recent task in space...
Well... mmh?
Isn't this strange?
What do you mean?
All of the sudden, a simple gadget
is worth a fortune, very suspicious!
Big universe keeps your family
busy, so don't look down on those
who make a living from small universal ideas
You lost touch to the ground...
Don't exaggerate!
Exaggerating?
You're brother thinks I am useless
Let's see what he thinks now
My success will teach him some devotion!
Glen, I think there is something wrong!
Wrong?
My fault, navigation error
We need to make a 180 degree turn
O dear!
Look Fuji, Jupiter...
Planet X will be just behind it
Look, there it is!
W.S.A.
P-1 calling
W.S.A here, pass your message
P-1 approaching Planet X
I want you to be very careful
Of course
Shall we explore the landing area?
I cannot object from down here
P-1?
Are your reading?
Affirm, nothing to worry
Like my father, business before pleasure!
We lost contact, they are on
the dark side of Jupiter
Glen, can you see anything?
mmh..., ya...
Rocks, possibly an ocean and ice...
Let's get ready, check the instruments
The radar-thermometer reads 15 degrees
15?
Far too warm, keeping in mind
this planet's distance from the sun
The universe still bears secrets...
Radiation check...
Negative
Okay!
Hey, is it safe?
Okay, fine!
Glen, have a look
I'll put the flag on that ridge
In the meantime I'll adjust the telemeter
Fuji!
2/3 of Earth's gravity
0.5 of Earth's pressure
Mmh..., half of Earth's pressure?!
Fuji, what the hell was that?
A lightning most likely
Strange, lightning but no clouds
Everything alright with you?
Yes
Fine...
Glen, I can see footprints!
They're not from animals
They are from humans!
Glen?
Do you read me, Glen?
Glen!
Where are you, Glen?!
Fuji, get in here!
Move in here immediately!
Who are you?
You have to rush!
This is a dangerous area!
For your own safety
move into this shuttle immediately!
Who are you?!
We are, using Earth's terms,
the life forms of Planet X
Aah...
We are sorry but get in here!
Glen and P-1 are already here
Okay!
Professor, we've lost contact with P-1
Check the emergency channel!
Negative, no signal
Professor!
Don't worry, I have faith in them
We also lost no lives for 3 decades
I am sure both are alright
Follow that light in front of you
Glen..., Glen!
Are you alright?
Ya, what about you?
Ah, I'm fine
Stay where you are...
We apologize for any inconvenience,
please make yourself comfortable
I am the commander of this planet
I've got an issue to discuss with you
The reason we made this arrangement
Arrangement? What is the topic?
Where is our ship P-1?
You don't need to worry
It is in this area, perfectly safe
Incident report!
Monster Zero striking again!
Monster Zero...
All units, take defensive positions!
Comply!
What is Monster Zero?
A dreadful space monster terrifies
our world since 12.000 years
Since that time the underground
is the only safe place on this planet
Monster Zero is striking!
Report location!
At position C3-M7, I repat C3-M7!
Clear area!
I'll show you Monster Zero...
Look!
King Ghidorah!
Indeed
That's how you name it on earth
Here we like to enumerate them
Why can't you get rid of it?
We tried everything,
obviously without success...
That's why you are here and
we'd appreciate your input!
What do you gonna do about it now?
We have to persevere until it leaves
Surface collapse at Sector 16!
Move there, area clearing procedure!
Emergency! Emergency!
Incident at sector 15
The hydrogen-dioxide plant is damaged!
Evacuate sector 15!
Affirm...
Obviously, something serious happened
And they don't want us around
All nations have securities to hide...
Hydrogen-dioxide, that's H-2-O-2...
a chemical resembling water...
That's right!
Nothing to worry about...
Monster Zero has vanished
You had an incident at the water plant?
A minor industrial accident...
I am sorry leaving you here, but
that was for concerns of your safety
Well...where did we leave off?
17000 years ago, on our last visit
in your solar system, we found on Earth
depauperate humans and two giant creatures,
We need now to destroy Monster Zero
Monster One and Monster Two...
You call them Godzilla and Rodan
Godzilla and Rodan?
Indeed!
King Ghidorah can only be overpowered
if Godzilla and Rodan merge their strength
So, will you support us?
Well, I can't tell you
about their whereabout on Earth
Anyway, how can you catch them
and move them up to your planet?
Godzilla in Lake Miojin, Japan
Rodan in Washikazawa, Japan
We need permission to land on Earth
also for catching and removing
them to this planet
We will be very grateful in return
Mankind suffers an incurable disease, cancer...
We will share the knowledge of healing it
Explain our situation to your people
why we need Earth's support
You have our empathy and we will
try to convince them
I hope you manage that in time
We wish you decent journey home
It was our pleasure to meet you
Fools...
"P-1 returns from Planet X"
"Uneventful flight"
Without a doubt, the content of
Fuji's and Glen's report is incredible!
A new planet discovered, natives found
with advanced knowledge of
technology and medicine
Seeking confidence, friendship
and help from the Earth people
The World Council has to discuss
a proposal of Planet X regarding
their application of enter Earth
They promised us an ultimate
therapy for cancer in return
It will be interesting to
find out know how it works...
Which chances this drug bears
on other severe illnesses...
The people from Planet X need help
in a state of utmost emergency
As a matter of humanity we have
to give all support needed
So, there is only one conclusion...
The World Council grants permission
the people of Planet X to move
Godzilla and Rodan up to their planet
Search units are already on their
way to the named locations
Sorry for keeping you waiting...
Namikawa is out of town,
maybe I can help you?
It's about my invention, the 'Lady Guard'
Your progress of going on the market...
Aah, we still need more tests on it
It's already in working condition!
I demand to see your manager!
Boss!
He's gone?
Not yet, he insists to see you
He might become a problem for us
Get rid of him
decently...
My brother wants to meet us today
regarding your invention and so...
I don't want to see him today
Don't be rude
The World Education Corporation
takes care of you
Your sister's late, huh?
She always late
You can't bear someone stolen
her heart?
Coffee, please
You've got an arrangement?
Actually, I'm waiting for someone
This Japanese girl?!
Race doesn't matter for you?
If only a girl's past is important to you
you'll probably never fall in love!
I am concerned whether Planet X
may suffer a severe water shortage
after that plant accident...
That's what I am thinking either
I'm also concerned whether we
should trust them anyway
Sorry for keeping you waiting...
Are you always late?
Good evening, Glen
This way, please
Tetsuo, your invention, going well?
Eh, yes!
'Lady Guard'...
I am be surprised that someone
is willing to pay you so much
I haven't received any money, yet
That's what I supposed anyway...
I know my sister and I can't think
a dreamer will make her happy!
Well, of course...
Tetsuo, don't surrender to him!
Glen, tell me, isn't mutual faith
in relationships superior to money?
I think so, actually it is inevitable
Glen, why don't you mind your business?
Hang on, I am simply answering a question!
Faith only won't fed neither of them
Well, but faith has got a higher
value in everyday life than money
As ususal, supporting the ladies...
Excuse me, please
Oh, you wanna go?
I've got an arrangement
I know him, stubborn as a mule,
so better use a decent whip!
Oh, it's Namikawa!
Look at this!
So that's his arrangement...
Glen is an adult, which does not
apply to both of you, unfortunately!
Wait...
What shall we do now?
I'll go and find out why Glen's date
couldn't see me earlier today...
It's increasing!
Captain!
What's the matter?
Radiation levels are increasing
Serious?
Alarming radioactivity Lake Myôjin floor!
Godzilla located, Tôkyô his target again?
According to Planet X people,
Rodan's detection only a matter of time
Professor, did they find Godzilla?
They found him at the bottom of the lake
The commander from Planet X was
right about Rodan's whereby too
Hey, what's wrong?
You take the wheel
Hey Glen, what are you on about?
Doesn't this road lead to Lake Miojin?
Ya, went this road with my date
Do you have something to confess?
Listen, I am serious now
I think these guys from Planet X
are already on Earth
You mean they came prior to our consent?
We spend the night in a bungalow there
I woke up in the night and saw
them standing in front of me
That was a dream!
That's what I thought initially either
Well, did they say anything?
Yes, 'All things done and nothing
to worry about'
I wonder what it refers to?
I can't tell you, but what did the girl say?
The only thing she noticed was my snoring
I'm concerned whether we had too
much faith in Planet's X people
with unforseen consequences...
It is possible they don't have
any water up there at all, thus
considering moving down to the earth
Alright, let's go and check that bungalow!
Go on!
Stop!
We are on behalf of the W.S.A
Commander!
I'm Fuji, we are from the W.S.A
I'm Glen
We'd like to examine that bungalow
You must be joking, look over there!
Godzilla!
Take defence position!
Defence position!
Hurry!
A flying saucer!
Glen!
I see, they'd been here already!
Gosh darnit!
General, all units on standby...
Shall we open fire?
Wait!
They are not from the earth...
These are the people from Planet X...
They're coming towards us...
The one in the middle is the commander
We are going to tie a strong galactic bondage
between Earth and Planet X
We are grateful for your support
and we shall be grateful for that
Shall our friendship last forever
'Feign' speech is understatement
We appreciate what you are saying,
though, doesn't that include
an obligation for disclosing
all kind of information too?
You came to our planet, hiding
in this lake thus disregarding
our authority and rights to object...
My apologies for this intrusion,
but we had the concern that
all of the sudden Godzilla and
Rodan may start to damage Earth
How'd you gonna move Godzilla
and Rodan anyway?
We've got a special nuclear field
which can carry items
of any size and weight through space
You doubt it?
These two flying saucers will
be the transport vessels
This one is heading for Washikazawa
All units, follow that saucer
and keep me informed
Move on! Move on!
There it is!
Godzilla, it's Godzilla!
Glen!
You wouldn't believe it!
Incredible!
Glen...
Time to go
Okay
This is Rodan!
Rodan!
Are they alright?
Yes, they won't notice this as
they won't their space travel
Soon we will get the secret drug formula
Is Glen joining you?
Yes, so does Professor Sakurai
What do you think, Glen dating Namikawa?
Don't ask me, ask Glen
Glen, I can't let you go!
Listen Namikawa, I'll be back soon
Glen, you don't know what you will face!
So what, nobody can predict the future...
Take care
I promise to marry you once I'm back
Follow that car!
Please, make your way in...
Take your seats, please
May I ask you doing us a favour?
What are you after?
We'd like to see the control room
That's where you in right now!
This is it?
Only my brainwaves are needed to
operate and navigate the entire ship
So, feeding your thoughts into the computer
navigates the ship into the right direction?
That is correct
Can you do that with everything?
Almost...
You got a high intellectual mind
I shall feed that into the
memory board of our computer
Backup status?
Backup terminated!
You seem to be impressed?
No vibrations at all, what an
advantage in compare to our ships
How can you pass the orbit
with Godzilla and Rodan?
They are entirely safe in these vessels
Not feeling anything
Speed according to our calculations
450000000 m/h
What, 450 million per hour ?
Affirm
That will take us only 4 hours, 30 minutes
At the moment, we are restricted
to 1/10 of light speed
The speed of light?
Soon we will be able to sped
same as the light does...
You wanted to have a word with me?
You became far to engaged with
the human called Glen
It's not my fault being a woman
No feelings, no emotions!
Only obedience to commanders!
I will comply!
The inventor named Tetsuo is on the island
What?!
Yet another project you've handled poorly!
We shall be landing soon
Glen, be cautious...
You too, mate!
Monster One and Monster Two on approach!
All units on standby
Standby, roger!
What are those pipes for?
They are part of our water pumps
Water is very rare here, thus very precious
All units, prepare!
Monster Zero is approaching!
You see, Professor Sakurai...
This time Monster Zero will face
an equal opponent
And that was only possible
because of Earth's support
I am very grateful for that
What so many generations waited for...
Monster Zero has been driven out
Where have your companions gone?
I haven't got a clue...
Security, person allocation!
We don’t know where to start....
We need to find out what the
commander is on about
I don't have a high opinion of him
Let's go back, we soon gonna be missed...
That's what we are already...
Gotcha, get in!
Too late, lets' inform the commander!
Let's see where it leads us to...
It's air-conditioned, so we could stay here!
This yellowish stuff is...Gold!
That's why gold isn't as precious as water
The more when ground-water lacks too
Someone is coming...
Namikawa!
Glen, Glen!
Namikawa, how did you get here?
I see, you are one of them, and
I was your target, isn't it?!
Glen, we ought to go!
You can take down your hands
It is a matter of great concern,
walking around without permission
Well, your limited sightseeing tour
left us with curiosity behind
Anything of importance found?
Seems to be more gold than fluids
Well, we are not really short of both
Plenty of water will be soon applicable
Really, and how?
That's not your business...
Actually, why do all the women on
Planet X look the same?
Aren't they are all very beautiful?
Yes, but beauty is more than a skin layer...
Beauty is what's in the heart
Let's not argue about this
Seriously, you both broke our rules
As a matter of hospitality this will not
have consequences for you this time
Have our apologies...
Now to our part of the deal
This tape contains the information
for the cure of cancer
It is yours...
Thank you so much!
Your spaceship is waiting for you
There is P-1!
That's not our P-1!
On your last visit, our computer
stored each detail of your P-1
This ship was reassembled
based on these data taken
Look, Godzilla and Rodan!
Both seem to be alright...
Professor, I wonder if we're
doing the right thing
What do you mean?
Look at Godzilla and Rodan
We can't leave them behind...
Come on, we had too much
trouble with them anyway...
But don't worry, they'll
find their way home
Everything ready for take off?
Okay!
This copy of P-1 is working very well
You soon will find out that this is more
than a simple duplicate of the original ship
Well, have a safe journey home
Nice to see you again, have a seat!
Thank you
Have you heard something of Tetsuo?
Tetsuo?
Ah, the one who inquired several
times regarding his invention...
Actually, we haven't seen him for a while...
Are your sure?
Yes, what are you concerned about?
The day my brother and Glen
departed to Planet X he wanted
to meet you and hasn't come back yet...
Hey, how long gonna keeping me here?
You will understand soon...
What will I understand?!
We will change the future of Earth
Changing the future?
The commander wants your attendance
Yes!
Hey, wait!
Hey, hey, who is the commander?!
This is Earth control
Commander speaking
Your orders, please!
Schedule #5 - Plan #2 - Items #4
Confirming!
Affirm!
P-1 on landing procedure
Put it on the monitor!
The gentlemen have arrived
Welcome home, you've got something for us...
This tape contains the data for the cancer cure
Maybe the device is broken?
I don't think so...
Their audio records maybe taped different?
According to them, it should be
I am the commander of Planet X
People of the Earth, take my orders!
Earth will become a colony of Planet X
Disobedience will not be accepted,
otherwise every human shall be destroyed
You have 24 hours to subordinate!
Double-crossed bastards...
Scumbags!
We expect you to comply to our rules
entirely and without any setbacks!
"This horrifying broadcast"
"caused uproars around the world"
"Some wanted to accept for the
sake of peace"
"but the majority wanted to fight"
"Even violence erupted between
those two fractions"
Glen...
Things getting clearer now...
Yes, I am a citizen of Planet-X and
you probably confused because you saw
my female look alikes on Planet X
Go on, Namikawa
Glen,
I was bound to my commander's instructions!
Including an arranged marriage?
No!
Glen, believe me!
You mean more to me than anything!
Well, then take this uniform off
and get out us out the place!
I can't, they all will perish here,
we both can only survive on Planet X!
Look Namikawa, how can we live there?
We are no emotionless robots!
what value has love if supervised?
We will fight for our freedom
despite all possible human losses
Your conscience, controlled by a computer?
Namikawa, if you ever loved me -
is there a way of avoiding this war?
You better let me know, now!
Think, not only ours, all joy
in this world will be doomed!
It's this world which created love in you
Glen, it's not only beyond my limits
it's too late either...
Are you concealing anything?!
Glen...
It's indeed too late!
You breached our conducts and
I'll take you under arrest!
Glen...
Glen!
Run, they gonna torture you!
What have you done?
You are this planet's scum!
We only rely on calculations
and not on emotions!
Whatever brakes the law has
to be destroyed!
Fuji!
W.S.A reports several objects approaching
What is that?
King Gidorah seems to be one of it
Any good news?
Not really, the politicians are
still considering whereas
the armed forces urging for using
all sorts of nuclear weapons
The radioactive fall out will make
all life impossible, eventually!
The usual out of the frying pan
into the fire stuff...
Fuji...?
Did you speak to Glen?
I couldn't find him anywhere!
For heaven's sake, where is he?
They coming, they coming!
Until now you have not complied
with the orders of Planet X
As you may have noticed we already
made preparations to conquer Earth
We will be supported by King Ghidorah!
All the time Ghidorah was their weapon!
King Ghidorah, Godzilla and Rodan
are under our Alpha wave control
Damn!
Subordinate until tomorrow or
mankind will be annihilated...
No chances left then
Allegedly they tame the monster
through Alpha waves...
Yes, is that significant?
We made some experiments a while ago, here...
'Using Alpha waves in practise', incredible!
Indeed!
What, not you again...
So it looks like...
A nice location for a meeting!
Indeed, a weird place...
Pointless, already checked each cell square
No hatch to escape...
Soundproofed?!
The walls are soundproof so are
the bars and the entire rest
New orders do apply
Humankind is destined
to become extinct in 20 hours!
No prisoners!
Fifteen hours left, suggestions?
The only chance is using
our entire nuclear power!
Maybe it's time for worshipping?
I can't see how prayers can help us
At least our souls will be save...
With due respect, options left are
Fight or doom!
Wait a minute!
The is one other chance, but
we need some more time
What are you talking about?
They use Alpha waves to
control the monster
That's where they maybe vulnerable
If we stop or interfere their waves
we will save the earth!
This is not the time for experiments!
Except final test procedures
our device will be in working in time!
Alright, that looks convincing
Any problems within the A-cycle?
This way please
Fuji! Yes?
How is it going on?
Well it seems working well but
We don't have much time left
I know, I know
Well, what are we on now?
At the moment, this tape recorder
is powered by magnetic waves
from these two devices
Haron, please turn it off
Okay
Switch it on again!
We need to interfere their signal
prior the monster receiving them
Like a lead plate can block waves
we developed a mobile transducer
interfering and cutting of waves
on intersection their direction
Are you sure it will work?
Yes, although we do not know
which frequency the enemy uses
to control Godzilla and Rodan
So we should transmit on all
possible frequencies at once
What, if they use a frequency
beyond our bandwidth?
Well, lets cross fingers
that won't be the case...
10 hours left!
All earth units on standby!
Earth control, report!
All tasks accomplished!
Its so quiet here
aah...
Give it up, there is no way out!
Glen, seems to be yours...
What's it?
This is a letter from Namikawa!
Offering you a 'contract' either?
Read...
"Glen, by the time you read this"
"I have perished for having emotions"
"But I have no regrets!"
"Through you I found love beyond
all these circuit boards"
"Get in contact with Tetsuo Toori,
he invented a strong weapon"
"This distorted noise, unbearable
not only for earthlings"
"Farewell, Glen!"
Hang on, that's why this cell is soundproofed!
Yeah...
And that's why my invention was suppressed!
That thing creates such a sound?
Yeah!
Actually, it can drive you nuts!
Listen to this...
Ah, stop it, stop it!
It works, it works!
Hurry, get the keys!
Okay!
That way to the lake!
Commander!
What's up?
The prisoners have escaped!
What?!
All stations...
Red alert!
The prisoners have escaped!
Mission accomplished, return to base!
That was close
Yeah, but they may soon
investigate the remains!
So where are we heading now?
Don't wait for a ferry, swim!
5 hours to go
Everything as scheduled
Affirm
Brother, look...
Ya...
Hi, we are back...
Glen, where have you been?!
Look at this, the A-cycle light ray
This device will intercept their waves!
Aah...
Eh..., what are you doing here?
No reason to be rude...
Listen, only his invention will save us!
Eh...?
His miniature sound transmitter
will cause vital physical harm!
Are you serious...?
We owe our lives its existence!
Simply amplify and broadcast
this sound via ordinary radios
making it for the aliens
inevitable to hear it!
Well, then lets try it
No time to loose, only 3 hours left!
Okay!
Commander!
Our computer analysed a danger!
Computer?
Calculations are running!
Unknown error!
Affirm
In this case, new orders do apply
Offense against Earth starts now!
Increasing likelihoods?
No, rather adverse!
Attention!
Monster One and Monster Two
to be released!
Professor, the aliens started
their offensive prematurely!
Eh...?
They probably became aware...
of our new weapon...
Go on, support Glen and Tetsuo!
Yes!
Calculations still running...
Affirm
All units get ready!
Clear for attack!
Fallback, all withdrawing!
Revaluations successful!
Mmh...
We need to destroy all their
machinery and equipment
Mmh...?
Brother...
Ya...
Glen, how far are you?!
Severe losses of artillery trucks!
Don't have better news...
We are in the final stages
of the broadcast procedures
Good, Earth's fate depends on that!
Okay!
Let's continue...
Error reports?
Negative!
Monster Zero clear for attack!
This way! This way!
Some men should stay in the tunnel
Second division, hold your position!
Further orders to follow!
Roger! Roger!
Please use this device...
Thank you!
Attention, this is an emergency broadcast!
Subsequently to this announcement
a distorted sound will be aired
This is an intentional broadcast,
your cooperation is highly required
Do not switch off but turn up
to the highest volume levels!
Professor, its on the air!
Time for you striking!
Offense position!
Yes!
Our next target will be their base at the lake...
Okay
"Attention please, this aired
sound is fully on purpose!"
"It is absolutely vital that it
can be heard in all areas, so"
"do not switch off your radio
but turn the volume up!"
Danger!
Impossible!
Time to attack!
Yes!
Attack, attack!
Forward!
Any new observing?
Unaltered situation...
Look, there is one of their ships!
Time for frequency interference
Affirm, start intersection!
Yes!
Ignition!
We need new calculations!
Commander...
Commander?
Emergency, Emergency!
Stop this horrid sound!
Time for our A-cycle block
Okay, start intersection!
Artillery units, ignition!
Professor, it works!
Commander!
Error report!
We lost control of both monster!
I'll do it...!
What's going on down there?
Earth control?!...
Earth control...!?
Commander!
Retreat, we are doomed!
No, computers don't fail!
We need new calculations, now!
Total annihilation!
Evacuate!
Evacuate...!
Look, their ship caught fire!
Yeah...
Earth control!
Retreat, we have failed!
What fails has to be destroyed!
We will be revenged one day, though!
We made it!
Yeah!
Let's go!
Yes!
Retraction!
What's up?
Have a look there!
Ah...
Godzilla and Rodan, dead...?
No, rather unlikely...
Look Fuji, any objections?
Mmh...
I surrender...
And we deserve a holiday!
Not you!
Ah?
You have to fly to Planet X again!
Sorry...?
It's still needs to be further explored!
This is a reward that
keeps you grounded...
END
Subtitles by ShanHua in 2011
Edit me but credit me...