- Sea Without Exit -
"Alert! Quickly StandBy!"
"Alert!"
Hurry Up! Hurry Up!
Alert!
Hurry Up!
Are you okay?
Yes.
"To Your Positions!"
Are you okay?
Yes.
Ito, pull yourself up!
Alert!
Are we going to be okay?
Do not worry!
Commander.
Sub-Lieutenant Namiki, pull yourself up!
Alert!
80m under the surface,
Goto Depthcharge Defense!
Don't move! Stay calm!
There's no problem.
Hard To Port! Full Speed Ahead!
Hard To Port!
Full Speed Ahead!
Are we being found?
Damn it! Not here!
Calm down!
(external water sounds are heard on headphones)
It seems they ran out of depth charges.
Where is the enemy direction now?
They are just above us.
above...
On the aft left side 30°
two enemy ships.
After they mark our submarine,
they will call another ship over.
Ah! this will be a long fight.
Stop Engines. Run Silent.
We've been discovered.
Are you guys okay?
Yes.
Turn it down, or they will hear you.
We can only wait here quietly.
Radiators and fans can not be used,
so we will become hot.
available oxygen will reduce,
and it will be for quite some time.
If you feel unwell contact a medic - okay?
Yes...
Ito coming.
Sub-Lieutenant Namiki, you dropped this.
Thanks.
Officer Ito, are the Kaiten' all right?
I worry about them too.
I really want to go out and check them.
Yes.
This will be for a long time, you know.
Let's just lie down.
(Kaiten were manned torpedo suicide craft,
used by the Imperial Japanese Navy...)
(... during the final stages of the war).
Okita!
How's the temperature now?
40°C
Just like sleeping in a steam bath.
"Namiki, throw a strike out!"
"Go, Namiki !"
Meiji University team vs
Waseda University team
What do you think you're doing!
I thought it would be a strike.
Why not pitch a straight ball ?
Why change strategy ?
Stop it.
Don't argue here!
You guys did OK -  well done!
The Opponents Win!
You know my shoulder is unable to throw
that simple straight ball needed to win.
Don't make excuses!
When I pitch a straight ball like this,
there is no need to use a strong wrist,
after a second the ball will curve.
Yet in the end it still failed.
It is easy to hit,
because it does not have speed.
But pitch the ball away from the catcher,
like today's game, it can be easily missed.
That's why I want the batter to think
I'm gonna pitch a straight ball.
Throw the ball to his chest
and suddenly it's a strike.
Do you mean like drop your aim ?
Well no.
Iit's like this, bend over
the middle finger.
The index finger and ring
finger on each other side.
See the batter directly, then pitch
a fast ball that will keep rotating;
but on the last second it
drops towards the catcher.
If you do it right,
the ball will disappear in a blink.
As theory - it really works ?
Sawamura Eiji
could pitch a sinking curve ball.
The ball seems to fly on three sections.
Go... go... go...
Nonsense!
Sawamura is a pitcher that
even Babe Ruth couldn't hit...
... are you at the same level as him?
Are you still upset?
If he follows my instructions,
we can win the game.
Here we go again.
with Namiki holding
a pain injury on his shoulder;
you should consider that too.
Rather than doing baseball...
Isn't it better to practice
throwing grenades ?
You are Kita the athletics runner, right ?
I've already quit on athletics.
Were your feet injured  too ?
It gets boring.
What do you want to say?
Just because you quit athletics,
you want us to give up baseball too?
For six baseball universities,
Autumn Games are called off, right?
That's because there's movement
from hostile countries.
So how about your marathon tournament?
the London Olympic was canceled, right?
You're blaming that to quit athletics?
Olympics...
Simply no longer matters to me.
I gave up running because...
There's no way to run.
I'm dehydrated !
I can't stand this anymore!
How long has this been ?
Three and half hours.
Why has the enemy not given up yet ?
Chihara!
Give me water!
Yes.
We've found them.
On the aft left side 20°
there are three ships.
No, there's four.
They are coming.
Full Speed, 10° right side,
there's another enemy ship in action.
Depth charges dropped!!!
Depthcharge - Defense!
Damn it! Are we gonna die here
even before we launch "Kaiten" ?
Hey, quick!
fix this!
Chihara, bring out more towels!
Yess.
Can't we go deeper - to 100 meters ?
No - not possible.
The "Kaiten" safety depth limit is 80m.
We can't dive deeper than this depth.
Until the last moment, keep on course.
Yes.
I don't want to die here.
Let's ask the captain to launch us out.
There's no other way.
Let's use the "Kaiten" to kill the enemy.
Wait, no matter how you think,
that's a rush decision.
With the submarine moving,
How will they launch "Kaiten" ?
So, it's okay for you to die here?
I definitely don't want it.
I'm sorry.
But could you all please be quite.
What's happening ?
The submarine is rising.
What?
How we gonna fight while moving up?
Listen!
The submarine is coming
up to a depth of 40 m.
Will we be okay doing that?
Enemy depth charge explosions
are at 80 meters
As long as we keep track on the explosions,
we could avoid them by rising until
they explode below us.
Then we'll find a way to escape.
So we have to receive it either way?
Our Captain -
is god of the submarine service.
He is from Sanuki Province, so
he has "Konpira-sama" with him.
It will be fine. Leave it to us.
Slow speed ahead!
Present depth 65 meters.
Depth 55 meters.
At this level, keep floating up.
The sound of that explosion
came from below.
Are we safe now?
On the aft right side 20°
there are three enemy ships.
In addition, two more
on the aft left side 30°.
gradually moving away.
They gonna keep chasing us or not...
Now we can only rely on "Konpira-sama".
Are you okay?
Uh huh -
Just went to empty my bladder.
"Young Japanese Empire students -"
"leave the school enthusiastic,
and embark on the journey."
"Rush ahead full-force to the enemy".
"Years of hard and rigorous
learning and training,"
"will be dedicated to a glorious mission",
"to come forward...
... and wipe out our enemies."
"Long live the Emperor..."
"... Long live !    Long live !"
Hey.
Welcome.
Sir, are there empty seats?
Ah, just come in and try to find one.
Give us four cups of coffee.
Okay.
We're about to leave.
Hey, your clothes not wet?
You didn't come to the ceremony?
I already signed up to join the army.
So there's no need to
go to the Jingu Gaien Stadium.
What service did you enroll?
Navy.
Rather than being forcibly ordered,
I choose to volunteer on my own.
Today I just had to taste this
bad coffee before I go.
Give a good fight.
When we win the war,
you can participate in the Olympics again.
There's no way I'm coming home alive.
Maybe I should be a soldier too.
Becoming a soldier is not the only way
to make a contribution to the country.
We as college students
have our own mission.
Because of this, up to now we
have not been given a chance.
It seems I made a mistake going to college.
I simply can't stay still
and just read at school.
But I can't become a formal soldier.
Not just me, you too Gouhara,
Tabakura, also Namiki.
Listen, Obata.
Last month when I return home,
I went to visit my junior high school,
I met former teachers there.
Later I found the
4th & 5th grade classrooms empty.
On each table of empty seats
there's a tag called "expedite".
They have become
Naval Flight Preparatory trainees.
They are just junior high students.
There's a lot of students younger than us
already prepared to face battle.
If my right-man catcher is gone,
how can I create my magic ball.
Magic ball?
You still hold on to that hope ?
There are no more games.
You're not answering my question.
Are you going to walk out as my partner
even before the ball is complete?
The kind of ball you can't pitch?
We will never know if we don't try.
Just give up!
There's no such thing as a magic ball.
If you have so much energy thinking it,
then best use that for the country.
Now Japan is at war with the US!
I will join the army.
Even if I have to die,
I will die as a brave man.
You...
just because of a few simple sweet words
you are ready to give up baseball?
Baseball is just a childish game.
Childish game?
Are you seriously saying that?
Then how about the war?
Just try to take away each other lands.
Is that so great?!
Are you too, seriously saying that?
Stop it!
You guys don't know who might hear this.
I need to think by myself.
Sir, you too will get into
trouble for playing "Bolero".
France is also our enemy.
If the military found it wrong,
I will tell them that Ravel was German.
[Nakano, Tokyo]
boy:  "Sachiko"
girl replies:   "Welcome Home!"
I'm back.
Brother!
Hey, you should reply "welcome back".
We have a guest.
Wah, you're very be-coming.
Minako-san just came from
Jingu Gaien Stadium, too.
What? When it was raining?
I was searching for you Koji-san,
but didn't see you.
So I thought I'd come here to say hi.
Your clothes must have gotten wet.
We asked her to change.
Minako-san, the dress she's wearing
is pretty, right?
It was mom's dress when she was young.
It's been a long time since wearing skirts,
I feel little uncomfortable.
Welcome back.
You must be all wet!
Hurry up change the clothes,
or you will get cold.
Thank you, Mom.
Minako-san, we will eat dinner soon.
Yes.
Sachi, help me.
Those taro...
... father's students planted at school.
Well, although small, they taste good.
There are so many kinds of taro.
The one given by the government
are not sweet at all.
They only appear big in size;
but nothing inside.
Are you talking about me?
No one said that.
Koji, there's more if you want.
No, I'm full.
You do not look happy.
Are you cold?
Father.
What happened?
I'm going to volunteer.
Say it one more time.
I want to join the Navy.
There is no other choice.
I think I should go.
But, you haven't received notice yet.
This thing - there is no need to hurry.
The result is still the same,
it will come eventually.
The college will send the notice.
Father, is this okay?
Think about it wisely.
Then your own goodness will decide.
Tea...
Could you pour another one?
Navy surely fits you, Koji-san.
Especially those white naval uniforms.
Actually whether Army or Navy
it is fine for me;
but I have a  feeling that our Navy
treat their comrades better.
However, you're immediately
going to the front-line, right?
Well first, Marine regiment training
will take 4 months,
to learn the basics as a soldier.
Then I  become a Navy Reserve student,
if you pass the test.
I can enter a specialized
technical school.
Navy reserve student?
Students who pass the test,
have prospects to become an officer.
"Reserve" - means I become a spare one.
So, after you graduate from school,
then the front-line?
Because Japan has started losing the war,
they do need more troops.
Japan is losing?
No, but it's impossible
to win every battle.
Koji-san.
What?
Could you give me this photo?
What are you going to do with it?
I will put this photo on
my desk and sing to it,
for encouraging you, Koji-san.
What song?
♪ Hana mo tsubomi no waka sakura ♪
Covered with flower buds cherry,
♪ Goshaku no inochi hissagete ♪
Carry on tenacious of life,
♪ Kuni no daijini junzuru wa ♪
To take care of the country,
♪ Warera gakuto no menboku zo ♪
is our responsibility as the students.
♪ Aa kurenai no chi wa moyuru ♪
Ah, my red crimson blood is burning,
Ah, my red crimson blood is burning.
Mom, I put the rest here.
Hmm.
♪ Go ni tsuzuke to ani no koe ♪
Voice of my brothers keep on and continue.
♪ Ima koso fude o nageuchi te ♪
Now is the time to rush to the front.
♪ Shouri yuruga nu sei... ♪
Grab the victory without...
Tok! Tok!
Mom said Minako-san's grandma will worry,
if she is not home soon.
I will walk with you to the station.
Your mother gave it to me.
Hmm?
Lipstick.
I'm still shy to use it.
This morning when I stepped out,
I said I might visit Koji-san's home,
then grandma told me something.
Hmm... what was it?
Koji-san is "national treasure".
What she mean by that?
That's why I should not like you very much.
My grandfather was killed
in the Russo-Japanese War.
Maybe she does not want me to have the same
lonely and tough life as her.
But..
I don't care even if she scolds me.
Mina-chan...
(Air Raid Sirens)
Come with me, hurry up!
Go inside the shelter!
Come on, hurry inside!
Come! Run quickly into the shelter!
Hurry up! Hurry up! Go inside!
"Hurry up!"
Excuse me.
The cook told me to send some fruit over.
- Please eat.
- Thank you.
Please eat.
Thank you.
Captain, surface noises have disappeared.
The enemy has gone.
Come to depth of 18 meters, and rise - quiet.
Floating!
Rising!
Down!
Okay, Surface!
Come to Surface!
Continue up!
Listen now! submarine point inspection!
The submarine has successfully
evaded enemy destroyers!
We made it!
Hurry - check up on the "Kaiten".
Yes.
Chihara! Chihara!
We made it!
Chihara!
Yes.
Quickly help me check the "Kaiten".
Go!
Tamano, be quick!
Sub-Lieutenant Namiki, let's
go up and check the craft.
Okay.
Open the hatch!
Yes.
Aargh...
How is it? Is there anything unusual?
No problem on the surface.
I will check inside.
Captain Kita.
Fourth boat severely damaged.
Hey, how about the no. 2 "Kaiten"?
There's no problem.
My "Kaiten's" outside seems also okay.
Now checking inside.
How about first one?
There's no problem.
Why?
Why my "boat"...
Chihara, do something.
Chihara, fix my craft!
Fix my "boat"....
Fix my "Kaiten"!
Yokosuka Navy's Antisubmarine School
Salute!
There was a rumor going around.
But today we convened all over
to covince everyone;
that Japan's front-line officers & soldiers
are fighting courageously now.
But in facing strong enemy resistance,
the battle field has deteriorated further.
In order to cope with
this adverse situation,
we have developed special weapons
to annihilate the enemy.
These special weapons
will deal the enemy a devastating blow.
Because of their nature,
their use involves a high degree of danger.
Therefore, we need a fine soldier,
and a dynamic motivated pilot.
Those who wish to go into the
battle aboard this weapon,
please write your name
and draw two circles.
Those with no preference,
just name and one circle.
If you do not wish to volunteer,
write only your name.
Despite this critical moment for Japan,
we look forward to your contribution.
That's all. You are finished.
Salute!
You have two hours to consider.
Those who want to volunteer,
fill out your slips and put into this box.
There is plenty of time!
You can decide elsewhere,
go to the living room or to the toilet.
"These special weapons..."
"will deal the enemy a devastating blow."
"Because of their nature,
their use involves a high degree of danger."
♪ Hana mo tsubomi no waka sakura ♪
Covered with flower buds cherry,
♪ Goshaku no inochi hissagete ♪
Carry on tenacious of life.
♪ Kuni no daijini junzuru wa ♪
To take care of the country,
♪ Warera gakuto no menboku zo ♪
is our responsibility as the students
♪ Aa kurenai no chi wa moyuru ♪
Ah, my red crimson blood is burning,
♪ Hana mo tsubomi no waka sakura ♪
Covered with flower buds cherry,
♪ Goshaku no inochi hissagete ♪
Carry on tenacious of life.
Namiki!
Ball!
Strike! However, nothing changed!
I've only come to the Navy as a candidate.
I could not circle my slip.
Form Ranks!
Ready!
Turn Left... Move!
Ready! Run!
They said -
"Kaiten" are  really torpedoes.
How could we ride it?
How about a one hit launch to heaven?
Shut up! Concentrate on training!
Too slow! --- faster!!
Stop... now!
We are going through the factory,
so keep it quiet!
Keep in line!
Yes.
Stop... Now!
Turn Right... Move!
Next you all...
are going to observe the Weapon.
Turn Left... Move!
Later you are all going to
board this boat.
"The Return To Heaven"
will change the situation of the war.
That is why we called it "Kaiten".
There are 1.6 tons of explosives
in the front, packed inside.
It can blow up and sink
an aircraft carrier.
The "Kaiten" can make dozens, even hundreds
of enemy ships sink to the seabed.
Chief Officer Toyama will
explain the details.
Length of this craft is 14.75 meters,
with a trunk diameter of 1.3 meter.
Engine has a double prop,
with 550 hp (horse power).
Normal speed 12 knots for 78 km range.
Maximum speed is 30 knots (56 km/hr).
Power control is based on the
renowned Type-93 oxygen torpedo.
With pure oxygen -
instead of air for fuel combustion,
it will not leave air bubbles on the sea.
This is the world's first
high-performance weapon.
However, use of hydrophones by the US,
allows hearing of motors underwater.
this makes effective use of torpedos difficult.
That's why we made an improvement
to the Type-93 guidance controls.
With human control inside,
not only direction, but depth, and speed
can be changed with this craft.
You can avoid early detection, and it's use
against the enemy, now becomes possible.
I will say the most important thing is...
... That in the "Kaiten" -
there is no way to escape.
That's all!
Complete your observations!
Kaiten is a device that uses
pure oxygen and oil.
Therefore it will produce a more powerful
high-pressure steam than usual.
This high-pressure steam will
set the piston in motion.
The disadvantage of high heat
generated when ignited,
could cause the piston and
cylinder to sieze by accident.
In order to prevent this mishap,
gradually increase the concentration
of oxygen and oil as needed.
However - if you reduce the burning of fuel,
and slow back
"Kaiten" will stop !
Simply put, once your Kaiten
has launched...
Until it hits the enemy ship and explodes,
it cannot  be stopped !!!
And of course this propulsion can't be
rotated in the reverse direction.
Which means, "Kaiten" cannot
go backwards .
It can only move forward.
Ensign Namiki.
My name is Ito.
You are the one who was sitting
inside the Kaiten, right?
What do you need from me?
You... Ensign is...
the Meiji University baseball
pitcher Namiki Koji, right?!
Do you know me?
Of course.
On the radio I kept following your winning
games during Summers at Koshien Univ.
When I was in Junior High School, I saw
the Ensign's heroic game at Jingu Stadium.
You won 3 to nothing versus the Keio team,
Totally mind blowing.
You like baseball?
Very much.
I played first base in Junior High,
also did clean-up batting.
Really!
To be able to play
at Koshien Stadium was my dream.
and to see you is an honor.
I'm sorry to bother your learning time.
You are called Officer Ito, right?!
Yes.
Another time,
let's talk about baseball more.
Yes.
Also I was a major in literature;
but I am having trouble trying to
understand the structure of those devices.
Next time, please help me.
I will do anything I can.
I must go now.
Start the electric vertical steering gear.
Open the operating empty plug valve.
Open the vertical steering gear valve.
Open the vertical steering
gear exhaust valve.
Open the lubricants guide valve.
You won't able to set sail.
Huh?
You forgot to close vertical
steering gear relief valve.
You will die even before you hit the enemy.
Once more from the start.
Yes.
Start the electric vertical steering gear.
Open the operating empty plug valve.
Open the vertical steering gear valve.
Open the vertical steering
gear exhaust valve.
Close the vertical steering
gear relief valve.
Open the lubricants guide valve.
Hand rudder control...
It's on center.
Open the depth guide valve.
Depth gauge, no problem.
Depth zero meters.
Regulator 5 kilometers.
Height zero meters.
Open the fuel intermediate valve.
Opening the valve...
Ah, that's too rough to open the valve.
Your way could cause an explosion,
you will be finished by then.
Listen carefully, there's
pure oxygen inside.
A point you should clearly put into your head.
Yes.
Okay, once more from the start.
Start the electric vertical steering gear.
Open the operating empty plug valve.
The longitudinal steering gear exhaust...
no,  not right.
Open the vertical steering gear valve.
Open the vertical steering
gear exhaust valve.
Close the vertical steering
gear relief valve.
Open the lubricants guide valve.
Hand rudder control... on the center...
Ensign Namiki.
I thought I would find you here.
What about that?
With my fellow comrade from Tokyo,
both of us secretly brought them here.
I want to catch Ensign Namiki's pitch.
Can we see the ball in this moonlight?
Leave it to me.
It's really been a long time.
Please don't pitch the fast ball!
Makes me nervous.
My shoulder had been injured.
I couldn't pitch the ball as
fast as my pitch in the Jingu games.
So now I have to challenge
myself with new throws.
Then I will catch your new stuff.
It's not complete yet.
Ah!
You are Kita!
So, you're really Namiki.
I heard you were assigned here.
When did you get here?
I arrived yesterday from Kinosuke.
So, we are on same mission?
Right, as "Kaiten" pilots.
How is the training going?
Controlling "Kaiten" is difficult, right?
Do it right!
Hey, Kita!
What?
Now you're still running?
I only run because...
as a soldier I have to keep my
body ready to face the mission.
Listen, I'm a Navy Sub-Lieutenant in here.
Beware of your language.
Do you know Sub-Lieutenant Kita?
Yeah...
We were classmates at the University.
Sub-Lieutenant Kita went
on a mission last month.
But his boat was unable
to launch due to...
...mechanical problems, then
he ended up here.
Really... he already went on a mission.
Listen!
From now on this is the most critical part.
When the enemy is just one kilometer away,
with the periscope make a last observation.
After checking  final position and speed,
and from a depth of 4 meters,
hit the central part of the
enemy ship using full maximum speed.
In other words after the final observation,
it will depend on your own
judgement to set course and cruise speed.
This training, sooner or later, will give
you a sense of the biggest problems.
With fuel consumption,
your boat will gradually become lighter.
and slowly it will lose its depth.
So you will need to regularly
monitor the oxygen meter,
and  inject sea water,
to adjust the buoyancy to keep from rising.
If you fail to do this, then your Kaiten
will begin to nose up and down...
Commonly known as the "Dolphin" Movement.
If the nose gets out of the water,
the enemy can see  it.
On the contrary, if the nose
goes down too deep,
your Kaiten will not be able to pull out.
You will just continue down...
...sink to the bottom and wait to die.
Idiots !!!
Don't be dazing around!
Didn't you  hear me?
Yes!
Report, Ensign Namiki will
depart for onboard training.
Using Unit No.35, from
sea base to target base.
Speed limited to 20 knots.
Training project is to set sail
then proceed to course,
increase and decrease speed,
and to secretly sneak into target area.
Training time 30 minutes.
Estimated time on start 08.30 am.
To have finished 9:00am.
This is your first time?
Yes.
Solo?
No instructor onboard during this training?
Yes.
Be very cautious!
No matter what happens, do not panic!
Yes.
Go!
When the hatch is closed
I'll give signal "gong-gong-gong".
If there is no problem with your
boat, I'll give another "gong-gong-gong".
Then you will reply with
your signal "gong-gong-gong".
After 10 seconds, we will release the boat.
Start the electric vertical steering gear.
Open the operating empty plug valve.
Open the vertical steering gear valve.
Open the vertical steering
gear exhaust valve.
Close the vertical steering
gear relief valve.
Open the lubricants guide valve.
Full right on rudder!
Full right on rudder.
Full left on rudder!
Full left on rudder.
Back home rudder!
Hand rudder control on center.
Open the depth guide valve,
Okay.
Depth gauge, no problem.
Depth zero meters.
Regulator...
5 kilometers.
Height zero meters.
Open the fuel intermediate valve.
Okay.
Open the starting valve.
Set bow orientation 180°.
Confirm after the hatch is closed.
Send signal to launch the boat.
Answer the signal!
I heard the signal.
For now - concentrate on your boat.
Be careful. I pray for your safety.
(♪ Humming Maurice Ravel's 'Bolero' ♪)
Turn right after reaching Sejima base,
full right  rudder for 30 seconds,
then full right rudder for 50 seconds.
Proceed to destination...
Report, Okay Status
to launch Unit No.35
Keep your eyes on that Kaiten!
Yes.
5...4...3...2...1... launch!
Pull the the operating empty plug valve...
or vertical steering gear valve...
Starting valve?
Regulators section...
Fast! Too fast!
What is he doing suddenly!
He have might set the regulator too high.
Catch up with him!
What's wrong with him?
"Quick - dive down!"
Okay, I am diving down.
Keep this up for 5 minutes...
Depth of 15 meters?
This is bad, very bad!
Ah, this is bad!
Ah, the 'Dolphin' Movement!
This is dangerous.
Turn full right! Full speed!
Ah, I am finally going up!
Okay.
There's no Sejima base?
Strange.
Was my direction wrong?
Okay, let's turn right.
Found the Kaiten!
On the right, 70°, sailing
towards the base.
Full right on the rudder!
Reaching Sejima Base in 3 minutes.
Okay!
It's about to hit!
Idiot!
Resound gunshot two times!
Yes.
Stop? It's a stop signal!
Aaagh!
Hey.
Report, Ensign Namiki has completed
Kaiten control training.
You made us worry!
Just a bit more inepttitude
and it would have caused your death!
You damn fool!
I'm really sorry.
Damn!
I only practiced once or twice,
how could you remember it all.
Aaargh!
Mom!
What's the matter?
It's me!
I was just thinking of you.
I thought this was a dream.
Fool...
Welcome back.
Hmm.
Hurry come inside.
Okay.
You look so fine.
I will follow you soon.
Hmm.
Brother, you look handsome
in the uniform.
Eh... you really grew a lot.
Brother too.
I won't grow taller than this.
Eh... but you do become taller.
What are you younger ones doing?
You must be surprised
everywhere was burned.
Shimada-san's, Tsumi-san's,
Kogure-san's house all burned down.
Hmm...
bombing raids really are frightening.
Right, I need to send a telegram.
To who?
Of course for Minako-san.
Do you know, Minako-san's house
also got hit from a bombing raid.
So she lives temporarily with
relatives in Hachioji now.
Mom, please give the money
to send a telegram.
Hey, Sachi...
Sachi!
What?
Brother has only one night at home.
Heh... one night only?!
I could only come to Tokyo for a day.
That's why you don't have
to call Mina-chan and...
On the contrary, that's exactly
why we should call her.
If we don't message her, she
certainly will hate you.
I'm going.
- So -
We have 'suiton' dumpling soup for dinner.
Sorry, even when you
specially come back home...
We don't have white rice to cook.
I already asked everywhere to buy some,
but they said no.
Here.
Brother, this is for you.
Ah, Obata's glove.
It's a momento... of Obata-san.
What?
The transport ship he was riding,
got hit by US submarine torpedoes.
The ship carried about 1,000 Japanese army,
Obata-san is one of them.
Early last month, his sister come here...
She said "it is because my brother..."
"...really liked Namiki as a friend."
"He must hope that Namiki will keep it."
Strike! However, nothing's changed!
He was really a considerate kind boy.
Always grinning happily.
I only came to the Navy as a candidate.
I could not draw a circle.
Hey, let's just eat for now.
I wonder what happened with Minako-san.
The telegram should
have been sent.
Are there any bombing raids in Hachioji?
I listen to the news on the radio,
seems there hasn't been any lately.
Recently there are air raid sirens
every night,
We could not even change to
pajamas and have a good sleep.
You must always stay alert
in your clothes.
Brother, why don't we go to Hachioji?!
It's better not to meet.
Why?
Did you lose your feeling for Minako-san?
That's not the case... I love her.
So why...
No matter what happens,
you do want to meet with her, right?
It's so strange.
Since you came home, you don't
care whether to see her or not.
Sachi, Koji is a soldier now.
The one who dedicates his
life to the country.
He does not know when it's
time to give his life.
That is why...
It would be better not to meet.
That's exactly why!
If this is really the last time, then they
should do anything to meet again.
Just because you are going to die,
you just give up.
If my lover did this...
I will loudly scold him,
"you betray me".
This is just nonsense.
Don't you feel sorry for Minako-san?
Father, it's Koji.
Hmm.
Father, this is the watch
you gave me.
I give it back to you.
It will be a waste if I keep it.
You are really going?
I must do it for Obata's sake.
But also to protect you Father,
Mom and Sachi.
And to protect everyone from the enemy.
When you say 'the enemy', you mean
the US and UK people?
China, France, Netherlands,
all are our enemies.
Have you ever seen the enemy?
When you father was in junior high school,
there was this American teacher
called "McBain".
A fine man, he had a great sense of humor.
This is not about each individual person.
This is a war between countries.
Koji.
I wonder what they mean
to called it a country.
Country is the state.
Like Japan, the United States,
France, the United Kingdom...
You don't have to return it.
Keep it.
Keep it as an amulet.
I will be the one who tells your Mother.
So it's true. You are really going...
For the country's sake.
"No. 5 Train, from Tokyo to
Osaka, will depart soon."
"All train passengers please enter
through the nearest entrance".
I will be going.
Keep your body healthy.
Where is Minako-san...
I already told her the place and
time when you leave on the telegram.
Maybe something happened.
I will look for her.
Mom, I will write you a letter.
Yes, you must write me.
If I do not receive your letter,
I will be very worried about you.
"Mother!"
"Brother!"
"Excuse me."
You are very mean!
Why leave before seeing me?
That's not what I meant to do.
Mina-chan.
I am very worried. Could you tell me...
There are headlines
appearing in the newspapers.
You're not joining
a 'Kamikaze team', right?
Ah, is that true?
The military information is secret;
but I will be fine.
You will take some boat?
So it's not dangerous?
I feel more comfortable now.
There was labor mobilization
in the factory.
That's why I could not see you last night.
We will meet again, right?
Yes.
Promise me, you must inform me
when you're back home.
I love you, Mina-chan!
How is the crew doing?
Joking around and playing trump card.
One day we will encounter the enemy soon.
Then we would commit "Kaiten" to attack.
Honestly, it won't be easy.
Because we know that they are going to die.
They certainly have
parents and siblings too.
I don't have children, so I don't really
understand how parent's feel,
But I keep thinking they are dear to me.
Ah... this feels good.
Hey, Okita.
You haven't eaten anything since morning.
You will just ruin yourself.
Leave him be.
To comfort him this time,
is just adding salt to the wound.
Rise up!
What is so fun about
looking into a mirror like that?
I feel more and more like my mother.
How about your father?
My father's face looks like a crab.
I really don't want to look like him.
Think about it, my mother is a beauty.
It's a good thing my face resembles hers.
But gradually I become a man
who will look like his mother.
You're a fool...
I don't care who you resemble the most,
stop this useless conversation.
Hey, Okita, you are pretty good at singing.
Sing a song.
Oh... right.
I miss hearing you sing.
Sing! That is an order!
Yes.
I will sing.
Okay, great, Okita!
♪ Hana tsumamu nobe ni hi wa ochite ♪
Gathering flowers in the field at sunset,
♪ Minna de kata o gumi nagara ♪
Our arms around each others’ shoulders,
♪ Uta o utatta kaeri michi ♪
We sang on the way home,
♪ Osananajimi no ano tomo kono tomo ♪
The many friends surrounding my childhood,
♪ Aaaa... tare ka kokyou o omowazaru ♪
Oh, can’t help but think of my old home,
♪ Hitori no ane ga totsugu yoru ni ♪
The evening that my sister gets married,
Those guys are just singing along.
Hometown...
They can not go back home.
Even for us there's no guarantee
we will return home safely.
That's true.
Because of Konpira-sama's blessing,
we have stayed alive until now...
Captain...
Everyone Standby!
Enemy to the right 10°, distance 6000m.
♪ Namida ni mune... ♪
Tears stain my...
"Everyone To Your Positions!"
"Enemy to the right 10°, distance 6000m!"
"Prepare For Kaiten Release!"
Finally!
Let's go!
Pilots Into Their Boats!
Matsuura, replace me.
Yes.
Okita.
I'm glad I could hear your
singing for the last time.
Don't give up. Keep your spirit high.
Farewell.
I definitely will follow you all later.
Let's go.
Thank you for taking care of me until now.
I pray for your success.
Thank you.
I'm really glad I could meet you.
We also talked a lot about baseball.
Can you hear me clearly, Namiki?
Sub-Lieutenant Namiki, can you hear us?
Very clear.
Prepare For Set Sail!
First boat, ready for set sail! Okay!
Second boat, ready for set sail! Okay!
Third boat, ready for set sail! Okay!
The enemy is a large transport ship
off the bow.
From the right 70°, distance 5000m,
speed ​​of 14 knots.
An azimuth of 100°.
Latitude 290°.
Speed of 20 knots for 12 minutes.
The target is a large transport ship -
off the bow.
Only one ship... who will go?
First boat will be sent.
Lieutenant Kita,
We wish you bring us victory.
First boat, We wish you bring us victory.
Kita...
First boat set sail!
Go!
First boat set sail! Go!
Kita...
What happened? Answer me, Kita!
Lieutenant Kita, please answer!
Set sail...
Failed.
First boat, set sail failed.
Got it! First boat, set sail failed!
Captain, please let me go! Captain!
Second Boat Set Sail! Go!
"Mother..."
"Aaaargh!"
Target hit confirmed!
Captain! Please tell me the next target!
Enemy transport ship has sank.
There's no more enemy?
Captain, third boat wants
to search for the enemy.
Tell him to calm down.
Attack mission has ended.
Tell Kita and Namiki to
return to submarine.
For now keep the transport
drainage tubes clear.
Down!
I have something I want to ask you.
What about?
If it's about Kaiten, I will listen.
Please change your boat with me.
Don't do something stupid.
Then give me your pity.
We could force your boat to
accommodate two people.
Let me go along with you.
Keep your sense!
That's just dying in vain.
You can proudly strike back
on the next mission.
Too late.
What do you mean?
Japan is losing.
So there won't be much
opportunity to attack.
When the war comes to an end,
I will be living in disgrace,
I already went
on two missions, and still returned alive.
How am I  suppose to face
my subordinates, my superior...
the people in my hometown as well.
I'm begging you.
Just do it out of sympathy.
You're really strange.
Keep your head up!
Now is my only chance to become a war hero!
War hero?
Being in Special Attack Corps
is the highest honor.
I could become a hero.
Do you really want to achieve that?
I was raised on a poor tenant farm,
unlike you.
So it doesn't matter how -
I must provide for my family.
I was to become a marathon runner
for the same reason.
However, that dream got shattered too.
Dream?
Now my only way is to become a war hero.
I'm begging you.
Kita, calm down.
Calm down and think about it clearly.
Your way will be the same as suicide.
Is a suicidal person a war hero?
It's wrong, right?
Remember what for we went through
- such hard work on Kaiten training.
Only to have a useless death?
Kita!
It's wrong, right?
"Enemy ships sighted!"
"Everyone to your position!"
"To your positions!"
Hurry! Hurry!
Hurry up!
Prepare Next Kaiten!
Pilot Into His Boat!
Prepare For Kaiten! Pilot Into His Boat!
I will go.
Third boat, Namiki here.
The enemy is a fleet of 5 ships
off the bow.
From the right 25°, distance 8000m.
Wait for my command before setting sail.
Start speed at 12 knots.
Azimuth of 90°, latitude of 170°.
Keep speed at 20 knots for 14 minutes.
Namiki.
Any last words?
Namiki!
Thank you for keeping me me safe upto now.
- I wish for you all -
to have a peaceful life.
Third Boat, Prepare For Set Sail!
Third boat, ready for set sail! Okay!
Third Boat Set Sail! Go!
Namiki!
Could you set sail?
Answer, Namiki!
Third boat, please answer!
It Failed to launch!
We've been discovered by the enemy!
Abort the attack!
Order Namiki exit Kaiten
and return here immediately!
We've been discovered by the enemy!
Abort the attack!
Sub-Lieutenant Namiki, your ball...
What are you laughing at!
I'm sorry!
with no aircraft to cover them.>
<as I'm the one who caused Sub-Lt. Namiki
Sub-Lieutenant Namiki.
Let's play catch.
(Obata's Glove)
Sub-Lieutenant.
Ito, when the war comes to an end
what are you going to do?
I will become a teacher,
Return to my high school and
teach kids to play baseball.
You want to go to Koshien.
That's a good one.
Germany has already surrendered.
Yes.
Japan will surrender as well.
Why would you say that?
Have you ever seen what
the enemy looks like?
No.
We label them "the enemy" but...
Even their sailors love
to play baseball.
They also have family and
lovers waiting for them.
Sinking the enemy ship means
taking that away from them.
Sorry.
Sub-Lieutenant...
You're not really thinking that,
...because Japan will soon surrender,
we don't need to launch "Kaiten".
By the time Japan loses the war,
I will already be dead.
Hey! pass the ball over.
But we created "Kaiten" as special
weapons to defend the country.
To protect the country, to win the war
that's the purpose for riding "Kaiten".
Don't you think so?
That's impossible.
So why is Sub-Lieutenant Namiki doing this?
If you ask me...
You want to know why I need to die, right?
That's the problem...
I will die in order to convey...
the meaning of "Kaiten" to others.
This special weapon
called the "human torpedo",
has a real person as part of the weapon.
I will die for people to
understand these sad facts.
That's enough for me.
This is just my personal reason.
Okay, I will change the pitch.
Hey, did you see that?
It curved!
Yes.
That's it! That's my magic ball!
Yes!
Ito, that was my magic ball!
This has been a long time dream!
Hurry up!
Come on! Let's go!
Namiki-san.
Namiki-san!
Why?
Why did you have to die?
Probably because I will
lose consciousness soon...
Outside it is probably a very sunny day,
or it is already night.
And of what color the skies might be?
I keep thinking these things in my mind...
Ito-kun, on the last mission I struck you.
I feel very guilty and sad.
But truthfully,
at that time, I was relieved.
I who had a determination to die,
- actually -
...was really very scared.
When I saw your smiling face,
I felt as tho you could see thru
to what was inside my heart.
Who I really wanted to strike - was myself.
I am the one who is to be sorry.
Trying to keep consciousness,
I don't even realize what
I have written.
<I would like you to find a good husband
and have overflowing happiness.>
Who you guys think will win the finals
of Nippon Professional Baseball?
Chiba Lotte, definitely Chiba Lotte.
Ah... I really want to see that game!
So envious that Matsui and Ichiro can go.
Ebizo Ichikawa as Koji Namiki
Juri Ueno as Minako Narumi
Meiji Baseball Team:
Yuki Kuroda as Obata Hiroyuki
Hiroyuki Hirayama as Gouhara
Yasuhito Shimao as Shibada
(the catcher)
Mitsunori Isaki as Hiroyuki Okita
(Kaiten Pilot 4th)
Shuuji Kashiwabara as Yasukichi Sakuma
(Kaiten Pilot 2nd)
Yusuke Iseya as Katsuya Kita
(Kaiten Pilot 1st)
Shun Shioya as Nobuo Ito
(as Kaiten Technician)
>>
(whose images do not appear)
Yuuko Kotegawa as Mitsue Namiki
(the Mother)
Anna Odaka as Sachiyo Namiki
(the Sister)
Tomokazu Miura as Toshiaki Namiki
(the Father)
Teruyuki Kagawa as Captain Kashima
(Submarine)
Toshiyuki Nagashima as Captain Baba
(Hikari Base)
Sei Hiraizumi as School Principal Sato
(Ito as an old man)
Theme Song: "Henshin"
Composer and Lyrics: Mariya Takeuchi
Arrangement:  Tatsuro Yamashita
Arrangement Performed by:  Mariya Takeuchi
Warner Music Japan
Director: Kiyoshi Sasabe
Writer: Hideo Yokoyama
Screenplay: Yoji Yamada
Motofumi Tomikawa
Production: Shochiku Films (2006)
English Subtitles Revised
CAHazard 10-20-2014 (and again 05-18-2020)
Oh  well ...
and so it goes... and so it goes...