I'm Gon, 12 years old!
ヒソカ サミル
I became a Hunter to meet my father Ging,
and made precious friends in the Hunter Exam.
I'm Killua, 12 years old like him!
I'm from the Zoldyck family
of professional assassins.
I wonder if I could become Gon's friend?
Obviously! We're friends!
And,
next comes Kurapika!
He's trying to catch the Genei Ryodan
that killed his entire Kuruta clan,
and get back their red eyes that got stolen.
But the Ryodan are amazing Nen users,
and can't be caught that easily.
And then,
this guy is Leorio.
At first he seemed to want to
become a Hunter just to get rich,
but actually his dream is to become
a doctor and help those in need.
These three are my friends,
but let's introduce just one more person.
Hisoka.
A strong and creepy magician
we met in the Hunter Exam.
He's an acquaintance of my
older brother Illumi too,
and a super shady guy.
Hisoka lives for fighting strong people,
and to fight Kuroro,
the boss of the Ryodan,
he took out the previous
number 4 and became one of them.
That's creepy.
And now! Time to start
the Hunter x Hunter movie!
What are you thinking about?
Big brother.
When did you get there?
Isn't it obvious?
I've always been here.
I'm always watching you.
Since it's my cute little brother's important job.
I'm fine on my own.
That won't do.
It's my duty as your big brother to
raise you into a perfect assassin.
Their ride's here.
Don't show your blood thirst
until the moment you kill them.
Think of yourself as nothing
but an object until then.
Yeah.
Are you scared?
Not really.
This is what makes you
one of the Zoldycks.
Hey! Pass the ball!
Just for a reminder,
you don't need friends.
Even if you made one,
you would only betray them.
And even if you didn't betray your friend,
they would betray you.
And one day,
you will kill that friend.
Like this.
Stop it!
Stooop!
Is something wrong, mister?
No, it's nothing.
It'll take some time still until we
arrive in Shanha City so please sleep well.
Yes, thank you.
Excuse me then.
I would never...
betray Gon.
Killua, is something wrong?
Like what?
Weren't you staring at my face?
I wasn't.
You're lying!
I'm not.
Something's suspicious...
What is?!
I wasn't looking at you or anything!
Gentlemen,
some passengers are still
sleeping so please keep it down.
Yeah, got it.
Thank you very much.
You were snoring.
Snoring?
You were grinding your
teeth in your sleep too.
I was?
Don't lie!
Aren't you the liar here?
What?!
Weren't you the one
who was lying just now!
Shut up!
It's because you were
saying stupid stuff!
It's not stupid! It was true!
I said I wasn't looking at you!
Gentlemen!
Stay on your seats...
please.
Yes.
Excuse us.
Finally we got here!
Hey!
Gon, Killua!
Leorio!
A survivor of the Kuruta clan?
Yeah.
There was someone in this
city who appeared that way.
But didn't the Kuruta clan...
The Genei Ryodan annihilated
them five years ago, right?
There was a good chance it was fake,
but I contacted Kurapika to go make
sure just in case.
I tagged along.
Why?
"Why"?
That guy can get reckless when
the Kuruta clan is involved,
so he needed someone
level-headed like me with him.
You really care about
him, don't you?
Shut up, that's embarrassing.
So how did it go?
Well...
Finding someone I only
saw once proved hard.
When we were about to give
up and return to the hotel,
we met a boy Kurapika seemed to know.
Impossible..!
That voice...
Kurapika?
Pairo...
You survived..?
Kurapika...
Is that Kurapika?
Come closer.
Show me your face.
Pairo...
Me eyes show nothing but darkness.
I did my best to help but,
in the end his eyes got stolen.
What happened to Kurapika?
I gave him first-aid and now
he's in a hospital at the hilltop.
Kurapika!
His life's not in danger for now,
but he won't wake up.
Why?
Who knows.
Kurapika...
Leorio, Kurapika is...!
What?
Kurapika!
Did he regain consciousness?
Kurapika...
Is it Gon?
Kurapika! Thank God...
I'm sorry.
You all came for me?
Leorio, after that, what did I..?
You've been sleeping since then.
It's been exactly three days.
I see.
Don't overdo it!
You didn't break any bones,
but your whole body took a beating.
You have fissures too.
But if I don't go now...
You couldn't do anything
about that Pairo guy anyway.
Your eyes were his goal from the start.
I don't believe it.
That someone like that
would be the real Pairo...
Kurapika...
No...
Just maybe,
Pairo really escaped that tragedy...
- Wrong!
If that Pairo was really your friend,
he wouldn't do something this cruel!
That's right...
I want to think so too.
Hey.
Could you tell us more about Pairo?
He's from the Kuruta clan like you, right?
Pairo was my irreplaceable
best friend who shared my dream.
Shared your dream?
Back then,
the beautiful forest I lived in with my
128 brethren was the whole world for me.
Until I read that book.
The book a woman named Sheila
gave us after we helped her.
It had stories about the adventures of a Hunter.
Using a dictionary, we got absorbed in reading
it and dreaming about the outside world.
But in reality you had to take a
test to go to the outside world.
After passing the tests on language and common
knowledge I took part in the last exam but...
The last part is a test on self-control.
We'll send you to do some
shopping in the nearest town.
Nearest town?
We're going to the outside world?
Remember that it's for the test.
Your job is to do the shopping
and return within one day
without using your red eyes.
But you'll share the responsibility
with a partner and go together.
Choose someone carefully.
Partner?
I choose Pairo!
Don't you understand?
This is shopping for a huge amount of daily
goods for the clan and takes a lot of strength!
If you take Pairo with
the disabled eyes with you...
Even so, I'm fine with Pairo.
If it's with him I
won't regret any result.
Whatever.
I did it!
Pairo, we can go together!
Am I really okay?
Of course!
It can't be anyone but you.
Well then, I'm going to put
this medicine in your eyes.
Once this medicine is in effect, if your eyes
go red even once during the next 24 hours,
even if you managed to calm down your eyes
won't turn back for the remainings hours.
If your eyes turn red in the middle of the day,
you'll have to stop doing the
errands and return immediately.
Well then, take the medicine now.
Yes.
Pairo, let me...
It's fine. I can search for it myself.
As your partner, I'll
do what I can on my own.
Found it!
Look out, you brat.
You made a fucking mess.
Pairo!
Are you alright? Are you hurt?
I'm fine. I just stumbled a little.
Are you with that brat?
Look, my important suit
is ruined with wine.
What'cha gonna do about it?
You liars!
I was watching.
It was you guys who-
Be prepared for
consequences if you talk.
So, what were you saying?
No, umm...
I'm sorry. It was my fault.
I don't need your apologies.
Gimme money.
What?!
Wait.
Um, if it's just money...
We only have this much.
That's...
It's Pairo's savings...
Hey, what's this?
They're all one Jenny coins.
You can't get shit with this pitiful sum.
Bastard!
No, Kurapika!
Let's just apologise and
ask them to let us go.
I'm sorry, please forgive us.
I'm sorry. Please forgive us.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry...
Sorry, please forgive us.
Just forgive them already.
They're only children.
Shut up. You picking a fight?
Here, Pairo.
Thank you, Kurapika.
You got it tough too.
Looking after a cripple.
Gotta suck to live like you.
For real.
You brat..!
Get up.
Get up!
I'm telling you to get up!
Forgive me...
Stop it, Kurapika!
Let me go, Pairo!
That's enough, just stop!
Let us go, we were just told to do this!
What?
What do you mean?!
Yesterday a weird pops
told us to anger you.
An old man with pointy hair?
Y-yes!
It's grandpa!
About Pairo too?
Did the old man tell you
to insult Pairo's body too?
No, that was just in a whim...
Sorry.
Forgive us-
As if that'd justify it!
Kurapika!
Granny...
A red-eyed monster!
What's with that colour?
I've never seen eyes like that.
What if he's a devil's envoy?
Are you for real?
Keep away, devil!
Get out from this city!
Get out!
Maybe we shouldn't go to
the outside world after all.
That's not true.
But I ended up with those eyes.
Kurapika, look.
They're back to their normal colour!
What are those?
I switched it with grandpa's medicine.
When I pretended to have dropped it.
That time?
So, I...
You pass.
After I had passed,
I went on a journey to the outside world
to find a doctor who could fix Pairo's eyes.
During those six weeks,
the news of the Kuruta clan
getting mass murdered came out.
Mass murdered...
All 128 forest dwellers were killed,
and on the murder scene there was a
message the culprit supposedly left behind.
"We reject no one."
"So don't take a thing from us."
So that was the Genei Ryodan...
Kurapika...
I can see something!
What?!
Your beauty excites me.
To the point it makes me sick.
I'm going up a staircase...
Kurapika.
What do you see now?
A sunset.
Sunset?
It's not very far away.
Could you be more specific?
We might be able to identify the place.
Yeah...
Before the horizon...
A line of mountains...
There's a strange rocky
mountain with a round hole in it.
What else?
A river...
I see a river on the right.
Wait...
Someone appeared.
What?
Is it the culprit?
What do they look like?
There's a piercing near his mouth and his
clothes are black and resemble a priest.
Now, go to sleep.
On his palm...
a spider tattoo!
A spider...
tattoo...
I can't see anymore.
A spider tattoo is the
Genei Ryodan's symbol, right?
Moreover,
the number on it was 4 just like Hisoka's.
Why are there two number fours...
Does that mean they
changed Hisoka to a new #4?
Hold on.
Getting Kurapika's eyes back comes first.
Let's find a location with this
scenery and we'll find the guy.
What's this? I mean...
It's so bad I don't understand anything.
But it's alright! At times like this...
Let's use the information
site for Hunters!
The correct choice.
What's that?
The search is ready.
The results are too broad like this...
We need to narrow down
the conditions more...
What if you only display places that are
about 10 minutes away from our location?
That's right.
Totoria district?
Is that man's headquarters
somewhere there?
Yeah...
This is still pretty broad but we have
no choice but search them one by one.
With this amount of matches
it'll work out somehow!
I guess.
I'd want to come with you but...
You stay here looking after Kurapika.
Yeah, leave it to me.
Killua, let's leave right away!
Yeah!
You're forgetting your Hunter's license!
You can hold onto it!
I guess I have no choice.
Well then, here goes!
I'm counting on you!
I'll call you if something new comes up!
OK!
We'll definitely find the place!
Is everything visible from here
part of the Totori district?
Yeah.
Even if we go through the places
one by one it'll take two or three days.
Let's hurry.
I'll look from that town.
Then I'll start from there.
So, where should we reunite?
You see that clock tower
in the middle of that city?
Yeah.
How about there at six tonight?
Got it.
Not here, huh...
This one's wrong too...
Amazing!
Thank you!
Look out!
Oh dear!
Are you okay?
Thank you.
See you, kind misters!
Sorry 'bout that, lad.
No worries!
Let me express my gratitude again.
Thank you!
I'm Retz, a doll maker.
I'm Gon.
Your show just now was amazing!
It looked like the doll was alive.
Thanks...
What's wrong?
Nothing.
"Gon" is an interesting name.
So is "Retz".
Is it?
They're both short and easy to remember.
Since they're two syllables long.
That's right!
Do you know this area well?
Pretty well, I guess...
I'm looking for a location...
Do you know this place?
Maybe I'll go back to Gon for now.
Killua!
How did it go?
What about you?
I couldn't find it.
I see.
Same here.
I'll introduce you, Killua.
This is Retz the doll maker.
We met earlier and became friends.
Nice to meet you.
Friends?
Retz is amazing! The doll
looks like it's alive-
Rather than that,
don't we have work to do?
That's right.
I asked Retz about it too.
He had a hunch of the place,
so we searched together.
We searched around quite a lot,
but couldn't find anything today.
Really?
But no worries!
He said he'll help me tomorrow, too.
Umm...
It's getting late so I thought we'd
check the remaining locations tomorrow...
Sounds like a shady story.
Gon. Why did you bring
someone like this along?
What?!
The "having a hunch" part
sounds suspicious too.
You could be a pilferer or something.
Killua!
What's your problem?!
I'm helping because Gon asked me to!
Why are you so rude?!
Apologise!
Shut up!
Retz!
Are you alright?
Did you get hurt?
Stop that already, Killua!
You...
could you be...
A girl?
A girl?!
It wasn't my intention
to fool you or anything.
It's dangerous for a
girl to travel alone,
so I pretend to be a
boy when I'm on tour.
I see.
That happens a lot anyway.
Acting like you knew all along.
You didn't know at first either.
Shut up.
You two are really close.
That's enviable.
Not really.
So you travel all alone?
My big brother is a doll maker too,
but I wanted to become
a professional one myself,
so I'm practising with street performances
while travelling alone for now.
So maybe this guy is my best friend.
Could it be...
that that doll..?
I made him myself, of course!
That's amazing!
You'll definitely become
a great doll maker!
Thanks!
That doll has beautiful eyes.
Gon and Killua too.
Gon's eyes are thoroughly transparent.
Killua's are tinged
with darkness, yet pure.
Stop it. That's creepy.
You're embarrassed, aren't you!
No way!
Making eyes for a doll
is the most difficult.
Whether it lives or dies depends
on the quality of its eyes.
If you manage to make a
doll with perfect eyes,
it will gain a soul.
Or that's how they say.
A soul?
This person...
Could she really..?
Killua.
Is something wrong?
It's nothing.
Alright, let's eat and
hit the bed for today.
Woa, this is delicious!
That's mine!
Pairo...
I'll definitely find a
doctor who can cure your eyes.
Then we'll watch the outside
world as much as we want together.
I'm with you, Pairo.
From now on and always...
Always!
Who's there?
You are..!
How lovely.
The smell of antiseptics and your blood.
Hisoka!
You fucker! What are you doing here?
Could you stay quiet?
It's alright.
If that's what he wanted, Hisoka
could have killed me any time.
But he hasn't so he's
got no killing intention.
Correct.
Why did you come here?
I thought I'd tell you about
the guy who took your eyes.
What?!
That's..!
Uvogin?!
But Kurapika took him down!
What's going on?
Found you!
You're looking for the chain
bastard's eyes, aren't you?
How does he know?
Come down here!
Idiot!
As if!
Crap!
No way!
Let's run!
Hurry!
Big Bang...
...Impact!
Are you okay, Retz?
Escape, Retz!
But...
Don't dawdle!
Hurry!
Yeah...
Why has he revived?
I don't know but if he's
involved with Kurapika's eyes,
we just gotta do it.
Yeah.
I sure can't get enough
of this sensation!
Let's go all out!
First we gotta measure
the opponent's strength!
Intensify your aura on
the arms for protection.
Ren!
He's crazy strong!
That's not just some muscle idiot!
Here I come!
That tickles.
You flies!
He's coming!
Rock Storm!
Killua...
Gon...
Fighting him is...
impossible...
Don't fight against
opponents you can't beat.
This can't be all there is to you.
First we gotta do
something about his punch.
Run.
Are you listening to me, Killua?
Let's attack his right
arm simulatenously!
Got it!
His bones should
have shattered from that but...
It won't work.
We really can't...
beat him.
This is definitely the best!
You should run!
Now then...
About the time to finish things off!
Hurry!
Drop dead!
You brats,
what are you doing having such
a hard time against a mere doll?
Nobunaga..!
Doll?
My body is made of steel.
Your katana won't reach my core.
Shut your trap, you fucking puppet.
I can taste the joy of fighting
once more thanks to this.
I'm instructed to kill
anyone who got on my way.
Even if the opponent
was a former partner.
I told you to shut your trap.
En, huh?
Unfortunately it won't
have any effect on me.
What's wrong?
You just gonna run?
You were strong back
when we fought as a team.
Big Bang...
You never had such an
opening at this point.
Impact-
Your powers would be
nothing without Uvo's eyes.
I'm glad.
To die by being cut by you-
I did tell you to shut your trap.
You sure are making fun of
the former Ryodan members.
You're there, aren't you?
Omokage.
Omo...
kage..?
His name is Omokage.
"Omokage"?
I told you, right?
Two or three years ago,
I joined the Ryodan by switching
with the guy who was #4.
Yeah.
That's the guy who stole your eyes.
He's a Specialist who calls
himself the doll maker of gods.
He sneaks his way into people's minds,
and makes dolls according
to their innermost feelings.
Dolls?
The dolls become servants that
strictly follow Omokage's orders.
But even while being controlled by him,
they won't lose memories
of their lifetime.
Memories of their lifetime..?
The dolls capture the
real ones' souls too.
Therefore,
the dolls also have a will of their own
while they have to follow Omokage's orders.
It seems he can't get
enough of such tragedy.
So this Omokage person
directed us to a doll of Pairo,
in order to steal Kurapika's eyes?
Probably.
Since he's a collector.
For such a ridiculous hobby...
he used my best friend..!
The Omokage I defeated in
order to become the new #4
was a doll of him.
You bastard..!
You knew that and yet...
Why did I let him go alive?
Do you know what it means?
It'd be a waste to put an end to
such an entertaining guy right away.
Your taste is awful as always.
Why are you sharing
this information with us?
Because together with Gon,
you're also precious unripe fruits.
I won't allow you to get
snatched before you ripen.
Stop saying creepy shit like that.
Be careful.
Omokage is a fearsome opponent.
You asshole...
How dare you show your face to me?
Even though I brought
Uvo back to life...
what unfortunate words.
I was expecting you to be grateful.
Shithead..!
Anger is a sign of being alive.
But...
The Injuu?
That son of a bitch...
He's even using Paku..!
Are you the one who
stole Kurapika's eyes?!
If you are,
give them back!
Gon!
Eventually,
I'll add your eyes to my collection too.
Enjoy the short life you have left.
Wait!
We are your opponents, brats.
We are instructed to steal your eyes.
Nen threads!
Enough of the shitty tricks!
Rest in peace now.
What's that?
That fucking Omokage...
he dug up Uvo's grave
and stole his eyes.
And he created a Paku
one on top of that.
This means it's not over yet.
Let's go.
Sure.
You seem to be after Omokage too, but...
you better not get on our way.
Spiders should finish
off what spiders start.
There it is!
Everything's fine, it's not broken.
That's great, Retz!
Gon.
Let's hurry and leave.
Yeah...
But...
we should do something
about Retz's clothes...
Wonderful!
Perfection for the Heavens Angels!
Beautiful!
Very very excellent right?
It's been a long while since my
stylist's heart has been burning up!
You're lovely, mademoiselle.
You're just like a doll.
Is there some problem?
Umm...
Not really...
Well then, take your time.
Isn't this great?
It suits you.
It's a little embarrassing.
I've never dressed like this before.
Who cares about that.
Just tell about that place
you've got a hunch of already.
Shut up! I'll guide you there now.
It'll be dangerous
again if you follow us,
so just tell us the place!
I'll be fine.
You might end up dead!
You might turn like this!
That would be better than
nothing ever starting.
I'm not living real everyday life.
I've always wondered when the day
comes that I really start living.
What are you talking about?
You don't... really live?
When I'm with you two,
I feel like something's about to start.
Something is...
about to start..?
Gon.
You got a moment?
Sorry, wait a second.
Soul Doll.
What's wrong, Killua?
I really can't trust her after all.
Is that so...
But you know...
But, what?
I feel like there's something
deep within Retz's heart.
So I want to observe
her just a bit more.
Don't blame me if she betrays us.
You will betray your friends.
I won't betray them!
Killua!
Please. Can't you let me help you?
Aren't you two doing your best
to get your friend's eyes back?
I want to be of help for you.
As your friend.
As a friend...
Please!
I'll turn back as soon
as I've guided you there.
There's no problem with that, right?
Killua.
It's not like we have other clues.
Let's let her guide us.
Fine.
Well then, Retz! Take us there.
Yes!
Huh?
Retz, what about your doll?
I left it for that shopkeeper
in case something happens again.
Come on, this way.
There it is.
I see.
It does seem correct.
The scenery here fits
Kurapika's description.
Yeah.
Thank you, Retz.
You don't need to come further.
But..!
I came all this way, let's go together!
No.
To be honest, you would get on our way.
What?!
I even guided you all the way here!
Retz.
Don't take it wrong,
that's not what we mean.
We don't want there to be a
chance for you to get hurt.
Got it?
Okay.
This is... pretty nice.
I've always pretended to be a boy,
so this is the first time
I've been treated this gently.
Gon!
What're you doing? Let's go.
I'll go now, Retz.
Take care of yourself, Gon!
And maybe you too, Killua!
The scenery Kurapika saw was
from the upper floor, wasn't it?
Yeah.
Let's find a staircase.
Wh...
Who's that?
You are..!
Big brother!
Why...
is he in a place like this..?
Calm down, Killua!
That's a doll!
I know.
But...
Kil.
Why won't you follow my warnings?
Why?
You disobeyed me and made friends.
Kil.
Even though I told you so many times
that you would only get
betrayed if you made friends.
Or perhaps,
did you make friends
so you could betray them?
No...
Killua!
Fine.
I'll stop expecting anything of you.
My eyes don't see you anymore.
Because...
my eyes...
show nothing but darkness.
So,
I was told to take your eyes.
Like I'd let you!
Kil.
You can't go against me.
So many times...
I've told you so many times.
Not to fight an opponent
you can't beat.
Killua, get a hold of yourself...
Nuisance.
You are.
Shit!
Kil.
I'll say it one more time.
You can't go against me.
Don't fight opponents you can't beat.
You don't need friends.
If you make any you'll
only get betrayed.
And one day,
you will...
kill that friend.
Shit!
Oh, he ran away.
But that's fine.
Running and leaving your
important friend behind
is the worst deed,
but that's the correct choice.
Shut up! Be quiet!
It's just like I said.
You're not qualified to make friends.
Fuck you!
Didn't I say you're a nuisance?
Gon!
Are you-
What a farce, Kil.
At any rate,
you'll just betray your friend.
I wouldn't..!
Then...
kill me.
If you won't,
I'll kill this guy.
What..?
Don't fall for it.
This is... just a doll!
Gon!
Come on, Kil.
Hurry up and kill me.
Quickly.
Kill.
Me.
Kil!
Come on.
Quickly.
Kill.
Me.
Now.
Killu...a...
I can't...
My body won't move...
You're fine that way.
That's the correct choice.
Don't fight opponents
you can't beat.
Killua!
Stop iiiit!
Too naive.
Gon..!
Different from the instructions but,
this is good too.
What wondrous eyes.
The world looks dazzling.
What...
am I doing..?
Gon!
Hang in there, Gon!
Retz?
That's right...
Gon-
At least...
I have to get Gon's eyes back.
Give his eyes back!
That won't do, Kil.
I was told to take these eyes with me.
Cut the crap-
Bye.
Gon, get a hold of yourself!
Gon!
I'm fine, Retz.
Retz...
Don't blame me if she betrays us.
Aren't I the one who betrayed him?
When Uvogin attacked us...
and when big brother was
about to take my eyes...
Gon was protecting me..!
I am...
I'm just like big brother said.
Killua! Where are you going?!
I don't...
have the right to be Gon's friend..!
Gon's Hunter's license...
That reminds me...
it was in the Hunter exam
where I met him.
At first I just talked to him
because we were the same age but...
We had the same athletic skills,
even though I thought
he was a mere softy...
He was always so honest,
the exact opposite from me...
Before I knew,
he had become
an invaluable friend for me...
And yet I...
betrayed him...
I'm really the worst.
I don't care anymore.
Killua!
Are you alright, Killua?
Gon...
How... did you get here...
I followed your scent.
It was a little hard
because of the rain though.
Why did you, for someone like me...
What are you saying, Killua?
But I...
abandoned you and tried to escape...
You didn't abandon me.
Didn't we fight together?
But..!
Besides,
if it was you I wouldn't
mind getting betrayed.
I'll still believe in you!
Gon...
You..!
Got it.
Where's Retz?
I just rushed after you
so I don't really know but,
she's probably gone
back to Omokage by now.
From the moment I met her,
there was something I had a hunch of.
That Retz's eyes weren't her own.
So, the owner of her eyes...
It's probably Omokage.
Otherwise,
she wouldn't have been able to make
a doll of Illumi using your heart.
Gon...
you even knew that..?
No,
there are still things
I don't understand, too.
But now I know where Omokage is.
We can follow the Nen in
my eyes to track him down.
Don't tell me...
that's why you let your own eyes..?
Why'd you do something so reckless?!
I know right!
Are you really okay, Gon?
Leorio...
Kurapika..!
How did you find us?
We used the GPS function on Gon's phone.
Gon!
I can't believe you...
Why did you go this far?
It wasn't a big deal!
Since we're friends!
I really have amazing companions...
It's too early for thanking us.
Right, Gon?
Let's go, everyone!
I'll guide us there.
It's the real deal from here on.
Damn right.
Let's go kick his ass!
So beautiful.
The world seen through
these eyes truly is dazzling.
These are quite impressive eyes.
However,
unfortunately, Retz...
They won't fit you.
But, they are suitable for my collection.
Brother... Let's stop
doing this already...
Retz...
What's wrong?
I'm doing this all for your sake.
I never asked for that.
It's all thanks to you that I
could become the doll maker of gods.
I need human eyes to
bring my dolls to life.
You know that, don't you?
I was able to reach these results
because you became my first victim.
I was still inexperienced back then,
so you ended up losing your eyes.
I'm truly sorry about that, Retz.
Isn't that why I
brought you back to life,
and look for eyes that fit you?
I don't need them.
Please return Gon's eyes.
Aren't you stubborn now.
I can't force you.
Everything other than my orders
is of your own will after all.
We have visitors.
I'll have you return my eyes.
Eyeball Steal.
They're definitely here.
Stealing the eyes back from
Omokage is gonna be tough.
What're we gonna do?
Gon and Kurapika are blind.
Will we take them back by the two of us?
I'm fine.
I can use Nen to fight when needed.
Yeah.
Since he's a dangerous opponent,
we won't win without
combining all our strength.
I knew you'd say that.
Alright!
Shall we go?
Yes!
I can't sense anyone's presence.
Welcome...
to my doll mansion!
So he used Zetsu too.
Are you Omokage?
Answer me!
Were you a member of the Spiders
back when they attacked the Kuruta clan?
Pairo would know that.
Omokage! It's you
bastard I'm asking from!
It was splendid.
I remember it like yesterday.
The warmth of the Kuruta clan's spirit.
And...
the warmth of that fresh blood!
Asshole..!
Do you have other red
eyes besides mine?!
Unfortunately yours are the only ones.
And those are Pairo's right now, though.
Behold!
Pairo's delicate body with
Kurapika's passionate eyes.
And,
Illumi's madness with
Gon's honest eyes.
These conflicting elements
can only be combined
as dolls.
You barbarian..!
Is Retz there too?
She sprouted my love for dolls.
My precious little sister.
Sister..?
No, rather...
now she's the creation of
me, the doll maker of gods...
a living doll.
Retz...
If you pity Retz,
you should hand over
even more eyes for her.
Doing that wouldn't make her happy!
She has obtained eternal life.
If she only lives for your comfort,
she'll never be truly alive!
Pairo is the same!
Pops, hurry up and give
Kurapika and Gon's eyes back!
There seems to be a misunderstanding.
I didn't give you
hints how to reach here
so I'd give them back,
but to receive yours.
Killua.
Leorio.
Your eyes too shall be mine!
This is the stage.
You humans are the actors.
Now awaken,
my dolls!
Perform for me!
Here they come.
Yes.
We won't lose this time, Killua.
Yeah.
Good for you for
having made new friends.
But I thought I was
Kurapika's only friend.
You're not Pairo!
The real Pairo is dead!
Yes.
Yet I am alive.
Controlled by a strong
will I can't disobey.
I need to get your friends' eyes too.
I won't let you!
Of course.
But you know.
I'm ordered to kill anyone on the way.
Though I don't want to do it.
Leorio!
Can I...
live as Pairo?
You're nothing but the
Pairo in my memories!
But I remember everything.
About grandpa,
and about Kurapika's mother and father.
Even if you died,
you'd definitely get revived as a doll.
And then we could live together.
Just like in the old days.
Bastard..!
Kurapika, get a hold of yourself!
You have to accept your loved ones'
deaths or you can't move forward!
That's how we both got
over our friends' deaths!
Pairo might have been your best friend,
but you have us now!
Live in the present, Kurapika!
Stop getting in the way.
What-
Leorio!
We're together, right, Kurapika?
From now on and forever.
Forever...
Forgive me, Leorio.
I won't hesitate anymore.
He's coming.
Gon!
Are you alright, Gon?!
Kil.
You still don't understand?
You are a puppet of
darkness without passion.
That's not true!
Killua isn't some puppet!
Gon...
The only moment when
you feel real happiness
is when killing people.
Wrong!
You don't know shit about Killua!
Even if you made friends,
you'd end up wanting to kill them.
Since you're a murderer by heart.
Killua's not a murderer.
He's my most precious friend!
Gon...
You can fight!
When you're with me
we can do it together!
Yeah!
I also...
trust Gon completely!
Don't fight opponents you can't beat.
I taught you so.
Let's go! Killua!
Yeah!
Gon!
We did it!
Kurapika.
Was the outside world...
fun?
What's wrong?
There were lots of sad
and painful things there,
but I gained friends who share it all.
Is that so.
I'm glad.
Pairo!
Thank you, Leorio.
Don't mention it.
A tragedy has the sweet taste of honey.
Sadness is the sign of being alive.
It's all thanks to
the dolls I've created
that you are blessed
to get a taste of it.
Be grateful.
You can't escape anymore.
Come down here!
Do you want to know
why I joined the Spiders?
Because I wanted dolls of the Spiders.
The reason I left was...
that I had completed the dolls I wanted!
The Genei Ryodan!
My favourite sextet.
Plus...
Kuroro..!
There's no way you could beat them.
This is bad!
Indoor Fish.
Why are you having such
a hard time against dolls?
Hisoka!
Rather than beating
the dolls one by one,
blocking Omokage's Nen would be faster.
Playing a knight in a
shining armour, Hisoka?
I'll add you to my collection too.
Omokage!
I won't allow you to do that anymore!
I'm not asking for your permission.
You don't have the right
to dishonour the deceased!
I will clear Pairo's heart.
Retz is sad too!
Retz?
That's right! Retz is in pain!
Don't you understand that?!
Silence!
What would you brats understand?
I don't care about your reason!
All you'll do is become
part of my collection.
As if you'd understand
the beauty of these dolls!
Emperor Time.
Fine. I'll be your opponent.
Doll Catcher!
Now. Shall we begin?
Double Machine Gun!
Then, the one playing with me will be...
you!
If it's one against three,
even dolls might be some fun.
When I fuse with the dolls,
I can use their Nen abilities!
Now..!
Chain Jail!
I know about this.
It's the Nen ability that
defeated Uvogin, right?
Let's go!
Shit! He'll get us at this rate!
Our only chance to win
is Kurapika's Chain Jail!
But I can't get close to him!
Don't worry!
Me and Killua will
do something about it!
How?
Let's combine our Nen and
become a shield for Kurapika!
Gon...
Combine your Nen?
If it's with Killua, we can do it!
Yeah!
If it's with Gon, I can do it!
Don't forget about me!
Alright. Let's do it!
Thanks for the treat.
Well then...
only you left?
Bungee Gum!
In the end, without a soul
this is as good as you get.
How disappointing.
I'm finished here.
Fuck you, Hisoka..!
How dare you do that to my dolls!
Let's go, Killua!
Yeah!
Gooo!
Come!
Listen, humans! I'll crush
you like rotten apples!
Go drown in your own lukewarm blood!
Chain...
...Jail!
It worked!
Now he's in a Zetsu state!
I decided that this ability
only works on the Spiders.
But since you were involved in attacking
the Kuruta clan and have the Spider tattoo,
I consider you a Spider too.
You think you've got
me captured like this?
Quiet!
Judgment Chain!
I'll set you a condition.
If you obey it, I'll release you.
What are you planning
to do if I disobey?
This chain inserted in
you will crush your heart.
Why can't you understand
the brilliance of my dolls?
On top of gaining an eternal life,
your beautiful eyes
would continue to live.
Don't you find that wonderful?
Pairo didn't wish for anything such!
You only forced your
crooked will on him!
That's right!
You only let Retz keep suffering
for the sake of your own desire!
Retz?
"Suffering"?
She doesn't want anyone's eyes!
Shut up.
Shut up, shut up!
Give up already, Omokage.
I'm prohibiting you from using your
Nen ability ever again hereafter!
So... I can't create dolls anymore?
You choose whether you say yes or no.
If I can't make dolls,
I'm as good as dead.
But,
don't think you've won with this.
Even if I died, the
dolls will stay alive.
And they'll kill you.
My answer is
no!
Then go ahead and die!
Killua?!
Kurapika shouldn't kill any more people.
I'm fine doing the dirty work.
Cut that out!
I don't want you to kill anyone for me-
The only thing I can do
is this much.
Retz!
Retz...
why...
me..?
Becuse if I was alive, I would
definitely have done this.
What are you saying, Retz?
You have an eternal life...
No.
Brother.
You aren't...
a doll maker of gods at all.
a mistake...
To the filthy humans that
live like rotten garbage...
death.
Ripper Cyclotron!
Be it dolls or whatever...
this isn't very pleasant.
The ones beating your asses...
will be us.
We won't let the chain
bastard touch the dolls.
If possible, I'd want to
finish you off right now.
Cut the crap.
We can't kill the chain bastard since his
chain is still wrapped around Danchou's heart.
You guys knew about it too, didn't you?
It's agonising but we
can't do anything for now.
You selfish fuckers!
I won't just let you out
of the leash like this!
Kurapika!
He used too much of his Nen!
We'll definitely settle this
once you're done with Danchou.
We'll let you taste suffering worse
than Hell when that time comes.
Remember that.
You too, Hisoka.
What an honour.
Kurapika, are you alright?
I'm just a little tired.
Retz!
I'll return with my brother.
To the memories.
Retz...
Gon, Killua, thank you.
Thanks to you two, I can
finally really live.
Really live..?
Retz..!
What the hell?
It's better this way.
Memories are something
to shut inside your heart.
"Really live", huh...
What did she mean by "real"?
Wouldn't that be
living the way you want?
Like you want to become
a doctor, right, Leorio?
I'll find my companions' eyes.
That's where everything starts.
I'll meet my dad!
I will...
I... don't have anything.
You should be by my side.
I want to be with you.
I guess I have no choice.
For now, I'll be by Gon's side...
That's where it'll start...
my reality.
Gon, Killua, Leorio.
Let me thank you one more time.
I'm indebted to you.
Don't be so formal!
Of course we'd do this much.
From now on too, just call
us when you need help.
Since we're friends!
Thank you.
Well then!
Someday, again..!