Once upon a time,
in Hanyu of Shimousa,
there was an acupuncturist
whose name was Soetsu Minagawa.
He raised two daughters by himself
after losing his wife.
As a side business,
he lent his money
with a high rate of interest.
On a snowy night in late December,
Soetsu called
on a high ranking Samurai,
Shinzaemon Fukai,
to collect the loan.
He loaned 30 yen three years ago,
but it has ballooned
up to 65 yen with interest.
Please, Mr. Fukami.
I won't leave tonight
without my money back.
Too bad.
I have no money to pay you back.
If not the full amount,
how about half of your debt?
I want to buy nice New Year's Day
dresses for my daughters.
I've already told you.
I have no money.
But you have money
to buy some sake, I suppose.
Watch your mouth!
Who do you think you are?
You owe me.
You can't get away with it.
You tell me when you
could pay me back.
Back off. Otherwise,
I will report you to the authority.
Are you threatening me?
You are the one to be reported.
You're insulting me!
Shinzaemon won't stop.
Soetsu searches for something
to defend himself...
and he finds a sickle buried in snow.
Fighting back against a Samurai?
Poor Soetsu.
He doesn't deserve such injustice.
Soetsu begs for his life,
but the Samurai is ready for...
Mr. Fukami...
I'm going to come back and kill you.
Shinkichi!
What's wrong?
There is a deep pool nearby.
It's called Kasanega-fuchi.
A woman whose name is Kasane
was killed there by her husband.
They say that her spirits still live there.
And it swallows anyone
who steps into the pool.
To avoid any criminal charge,
Shinzaemon orders his men
to dump the body there.
May his soul rest in peace.
They sent the sickle
down with the body,
hoping it might calm his soul.
Soetsu's two daughters,
Oshiga and Osono,
searched and searched
for their father in vain.
Since then,
the Fakami family suffered
from various mysterious tragedies.
Shinzaemon became insane.
He killed his wife
and then killed himself.
Shinkichi,
you're the only one left.
This is the beginning
of Kaidan.
"KAIDAN"
"25 YEARS LATER"
"EDO, OLD TOKYO"
Uncle, I'm ready.
Have a good day.
Tobacco!
Would you like tobacco?
High quality! Very popular!
Hey, Shinkichi!
Hey.
Would you like tobacco!
If
Your
Heart
Has
Changed
One more time.
If
Your
- Heart
- No, no.
Your heart has...
Now you try.
Your heart has
Good. Do it again.
If
It's a chilly day, isn't it?
Yes, it is.
Would you like some tobacco?
High quality!
Popular brand!
Would you like some tobacco?
No, thank you.
Well, maybe I should get some.
She is Toyoshiga,
whose father, Soetsu,
was killed by Shinzaemon.
And Shinkichi is Shinzaemon's son.
They have no idea about
their eerie connection.
This is the beginning of
their destined relationship.
Shinkichi's tobacco
really tastes good.
I couldn't buy one
from any other shop.
My lady loves its smell.
You mean that old lady?
Thank you.
Can I have some?
I'm gonna buy the entire box.
Oh, come on.
Stop that, please.
I'm going out to the public bath.
In the rain?
I'm sure it makes
the bath less crowded.
Enjoy.
Hello.
I hope it will clear up soon.
Why don't you come in?
Mistress, you're going somewhere, right?
Your tobacco is going to get wet.
I don't want to give you any bother.
You're already bothering us
by standing right here.
Come on.
I didn't know you were so stubborn.
It has turned into snow.
Well, I should be going now.
Mistress, Happy New Year!
Happy New Year to you.
Happy New Year.
Keep working hard.
Yes, mistress.
How long have you been working?
Three years.
Wow, really?
I promise this will be my year.
I even pray to God for it.
I don't think so.
We haven't seen Shinkichi for a while.
That's true.
I must wonder why.
I hope he is not sick or anything.
Mistress.
It never clears up, huh?
It hurts my business.
I haven't seen you for a while.
Everybody worries about you.
How have you been?
The same as usual.
Well, you're fine, right?
It's strange.
I see you whenever it snows.
It won't stop, don't you think?
It will stop snowing by night.
And the snow will melt away
by tomorrow morning.
Come with me.
My place is right over there.
I appreciate your offer, but...
It is gonna be heavy snow.
Yes indeed.
Why don't you come over by the fire?
I will never see you again.
Thanks to your help,
my business is really going well.
But...
I can't see you again.
Why?
Someone will gossip
if I keep coming here.
About what?
I come here because I want to see you.
I fell in love with you at first sight.
I have kept telling myself
to forget about you.
But I can't...
What's wrong with you?
I'm too old for you.
I like older, mature men
of a strong build.
I can't stand
a young, immature man.
I knew it.
I'm prepared for your rejection.
You have someone in your mind.
No, I don't have anyone.
You're skinny.
Not my type.
Stay with me tonight.
I'm lonely.
It's a beautiful day.
Well, that means you can go home now.
I know men never stay with women.
Mistress.
My father disappeared
on a snowy night.
The following morning was beautiful,
Just like this.
My little sister and I
searched for him everywhere.
By noon, the snow melted away.
We got muddy.
Hello.
Hello, sister!
Are you home?
I'm coming in, okay?
I've made you a kimono.
Hi, sister.
I didn't know you were here.
Hi.
Let's go over there.
I don't understand why she chose
such a young guy like Shinkichi.
He has changed.
He behaves like a big shot now.
Honestly, I envy him.
I wish I could be with her.
She has disappointed me.
Where has her dignity gone?
You want one?
Stop it.
What the hell are you doing?
Well...
Let's start over. From the beginning.
Never talk back to me again!
I didn't.
Say only yes to me. Understood?
How dare you embarrass me!
I'm sorry.
You treated me like shit.
Then why don't you quit?
I don't need you to be my student.
I want to work with you.
But my mom doesn't
like me to come here.
She thought this was a decent place,
but recently...
My personal life
is none of your business.
Tell that to your mother.
Work with other mistresses.
But I want to be...
Go wherever your mom prefers.
You're annoying.
Ohisa?
I don't want to see you again.
Ma'am.
You can also quit if you want to.
She just got here.
Not right now.
I don't feel well today.
Her training has given me a chance
to enjoy something.
My life is miserable.
My mom is very hard on me.
Still having trouble with her?
Come again.
I had a dream
about our father again.
As usual, he complained about you.
"How dare she end up
with Shinkichi?"
"God will punish Shiga for it."
He is the one
who has abandoned us.
Sister.
I have to agree with him.
Break up with Shinkichi.
You know this relationship
won't last long, don't you?
Let's go back to our hometown.
You could forget about him.
We'll be fine.
I will never leave him.
I want to be with him
no matter what's gonna happen.
Get out of here!
You go back to our hometown alone!
I don't want to see you again!
Sister, please!
Listen to me!
What's wrong with you two?
Behave yourself.
Are you all right?
Yes.
Thank you.
I'll never come back here.
Take care of my sister.
Osono.
Good-bye.
Be nice to your sister.
She is the only family you've got.
You are also too hard
on your students for no reason.
Why don't you treat them nicely?
They admire you.
Why are you so nice to Ohisa?
She has a hard time
with her stepmom.
But she never grumbles.
Right. She is better than me, huh?
What's wrong with you?
Students left you because of me.
Thank you for having
been so nice to me.
I should go back to my uncle's.
I don't care about the students.
I can't live without you!
Don't you get it?
I don't want to ruin your life.
No! I won't let you go anywhere!
Please, no! I love you.
Please.
I'm doing this for you.
No!
Ma'am!
Are you okay?
Oh, my God.
Does it still hurt?
How about you, dear?
I'm all right. Don't worry.
I'm so sorry. I didn't mean to...
No, this is my fault.
I've hurt your pretty face.
What's wrong with me?
I'm blaming everyone.
Even though I regret
what I say every time.
I guess I'm crazy about you.
What should I do?
This is too painful.
I wish I had never seen you.
I won't go anywhere, okay?
I don't deserve your love.
I'm nobody.
But you still love me, huh?
I'm very lucky... to have
someone who loves me so much.
My dear...
you really mean it?
Yes, I mean it.
I will never forget your words.
I won't.
Ma'am?
Ma'am!
It's a vicious swelling.
If it gets worse, I have to
cut it open to get rid of pus.
My dear...
Please come here, my dear.
I had a bad dream.
My ears decomposed and fell off.
Don't worry. It's just a dream.
Shinkichi.
Please nibble my ears.
I need you to do it.
Something's driving me nuts.
Harder!
You need to have a rest.
Once the swelling is healed, you'll be fine.
I know I won't get better.
Don't say that.
My care means nothing to you?
I can see...
I can see what's
gonna happen to you and me.
I see everything.
I need some air.
Remember?
You've been looking forward
to seeing the fireworks...
Of course!
I want to go to see them.
Go home by yourself now.
Don't tell this to our mother.
Shinkichi!
Are you here to see the fireworks?
No.
To get some medicine for my mistress.
How is she doing?
Not so good.
She can't leave the bed.
Can I go see her now?
Not a good idea.
She gets emotional if she sees women.
I see.
Then I guess I'll see you soon.
Here you go. This is your room.
Enjoy.
I've made up various
excuses just to see you.
To see me?
I'm planning to leave my family.
Really?
I sent a letter to my uncle in Hanyu,
asking to let me live with him.
He sent me a letter right away
to tell me that I would be welcome.
Hanyu, huh?
It's far away.
Which means I can't see you again.
I'm sure I will see you again.
I'm from Hanyu.
I don't remember anything
since I left it when I was young.
Do you know why she
is so hard on me?
You're so pretty.
She is jealous of that.
She is aware of...
my...
real feelings.
I wish I could take you to Hanyu.
If you are gone, who would
take care of our mistress?
You care about her, don't you?
That's why you're taking care of her.
She needs me.
Nobody counts on me like her.
I can also say that nobody
torments me like her.
I need your strength.
I wish I had your determination.
No.
I'm weak.
When my stepmom beats me,
I just try to suck it up.
Otherwise I can't stand my life.
I can't live there anymore.
I'll go to Hanyu with you.
My mistress and I don't
have a future together.
My dear, where are you?
What the hell
are you doing, Shinkichi?
Our mistress is sick in bed,
and you're wandering around?
Are you listening to me?
What are you going to do with these?
Sell them. I need some money.
What?
I'm leaving Edo.
What about our mistress?
That's why I'm selling them.
You son of a bitch!
You are like her husband.
You were nobody, remember?
She is the one to have supported you.
She has been waiting for you.
Why are you here?
I suspect that you
don't like me anymore
and have left me.
Please forgive him.
He is still young and immature.
He just needs your guidance.
Shinkichi, you can go anywhere.
I don't care.
But...
come back to see me off when I die.
Oh, come on. You just need a rest.
She is not doing well.
Take her home very carefully.
Yes, sir.
Who is it?
Wait here for a second, okay?
I'm coming.
Who is it?
Is Shinkichi here?
Oh, you are here.
I've been looking for you everywhere.
What's the matter?
She just passed away.
Are you kidding?
We're seeing her off right now.
Get out of here.
Shinkichi.
Where have you been?
Our mistress...
Shinkichi!
We found this by her bed.
If you marry someone,
I'll come back to kill her.
Remember that.
If you marry someone,
I'll come back to kill her.
Remember that.
I thought you had
already left for Hanyu.
I feel very sorry for her.
I shouldn't have
asked you out that night.
I'm the one to be blamed.
Ohisa!
Do you still want to go to Hanyu?
You want to go with me?
You and me together.
I cried a lot.
I thought it was over between us.
It's not over.
Take me to Hanyu.
Please.
Take me with you.
Come here.
Are you okay?
Yes.
We should have stayed in a lodge.
We will be there soon.
It's on the other side of the pool.
Looks like it won't stop raining
until tomorrow morning.
You want to go back to the town?
We are not in a hurry anyway.
I want to eat a warm meal
in front of a fireplace.
We're being followed.
By whom?
I can't hear anything.
See?
It's coming.
Ohisa! Wait!
Don't look.