Know what a 'split tongue' is ?
What's that?
A tongue that's split at the end?
Right, like a snake or lizard.
Some people have them too.
Wow
Don't you ever want to modify your body?
is it ok?
hey..
Didn't you say you'd pull out before...
sorry.. my timing was a little..
If you can't, use a rubber ok?
Hey!
Ama, long time no see.
This is Shiba, the owner.
Ah, my new girlfriend
Oh.
You caught a cute one
We came to get her tounge pierced.
Even girlies getting their
tongues pierced now?
I'm not a girlie
She wants a split toungue too.
Put your tongue out.
Ah, pretty thin so it won't hurt much.
But since it's a muscle
It's going to be pretty tough, right?
putting a hole in that sort of tissue
is still ok?
Well... if you compare it to ears,
it hurts more
But, if you put a hole anywhere
It will hurt
Hey, Shiba, don't scare her off.
It'll be fine, Lui. After all I've had it done.
What did you say?
When I pierced your tongue, you fainted!
Anyway, come this way.
Tattoos huh? I wonder if i should get one too?
Sit down.
Rinse out your mouth
- here you go
- thanks
A little further
Hold it
Where abouts?
Ok
Ready?
Have a look
Ok?
It went in straight and it's
where you wanted it.
You really did it! Awesome!
Did you say your name is Lui?
Pain is a powerful thing, huh?
Women are better at enduring it
Tongues, genitals,
just piercing skin often makes guys faint.
Shiba, what do you think about split tongues?
Huh?
Split tongue?
It's completely different from tattoos and piercings
It's an interesting form of
expression, but not for me.
I think changing a persons form..
..is a privilege granted only to God.
Well, if you were God, what sort
of person would you make?
I wouldn't change their form
I'd make simple men
something like chickens
so they wouldn't come up with
an idea like God.
Could you show me some tattoo
designs next time?
Sure.
If you want to get in touch..
.. about piercing, or anything..
anytime..
Oh, how much for the piercing?
Don't worry.
When I saw your face,
the sadist in me got aroused.
I'm a masochist so
I guess it's my aura.
I'd love to stick a needle in this throat
That's kind of "savage"
It certainly is
You know the word "savage"?
I know those kind of words very well
Hey, Shiba!
Don't go around touching other guys girls.
I'm looking at her skin, for the tattoo.
When he smiled,
his face seemed to distort
No way! What is that?
That looks really painful
What were you thinking?
I'm not sure..
Pierced tongues aren't fashionable!
I met a punk a while ago
He kind of influenced me
What kind of person is he?
He looks like a punk, but inside,
he's kind of soothing
What?
What do you think about tattoos?
Tattoos? Tattoos are fine
Butterflies, roses, they're cute.
not those kind,
Dragons, ukiyoe, guys with
that kind of tattoo?
What are you saying?
You've met that kind of guy?
You're associating with that kind of guy?
Lui, I think maybe he brainwashed you!
Brainwashed?
Maybe, but..
I want to know why..
seeing his split tongue makes me so excited.
It's a feeling like I'm running and can't stop.
Hey! Want to meet him?
Ah, he's here
Hey!
- Wait..
- Huh?
Are you serious?
Yep, the red hair guy!
He's scary!
-Hello
Sorry if i look scary
No, no, just a little scary!
This is Ama
- Ah, I'm Ama.
- Maki
- Nice to meet you, I'm Ama
- Nice to meet you.
I'm Maki...
Maki, right
I've heard you have a soothing personality..
Ama, when you're walking with you
- everyone gets out of the way!
- really?
Really! Whenever you're with him!
Nobody stops you or tries to
give you anything!
Ah, so I'm useful!
It's handy!
A handyman!
Here we go!
So cool..
That piercing,
keep making the hole bigger..
.. then put a string in and pull
until it cuts it completely.
- Eeh? You're going to do this too?
- Sure.
Then we'll have matching tongues!
Lui, why don't you get your eyebrow and
lip pierced too? Then we'll really match!
No way! All i want is a split tongue and tattoo
Sorry for saying this but..
Don't lead Lui too far down the punk road
Me and Lui..
We're the same. We're fashion victims and
we're gonna be that way for ever.
We're not the same,
and i'm not a fashion victim!
You are!
Be quiet!
Fashion victim..
Aah, Miki.. that was strong booze
No it wasn't
Why was it my treat?
Thanks for lunch, it was delicious.
Anyway, it was fun.
It was our first meeting after all
Your face is red!
To our first night out!
- Which?
- left
- Cute huh.
- Yeah
She likes you, man.
Red-head!
This is our turf, you can't just
come walking in
What's with the piercings?
Where are you going ladies?
Who's the loser? boyfriend?
No way..
Where are you going..
Go wash your hair..
You'll catch something from him
Let's go somewhere
Whats with you?
What are you doing?
Stop it!
That was scary
Stop!
I'm sorry
Forgive me
I'm really sorry..
Ama! Ama!
Please stop it!
Enough!
Maki, run away! quickly!
We'll meet up again.
Please, enough!
We have to run!
The Police are coming!
Please
This way!
What were you thinking?
Idiot!
He offended you,
so I took these
I don't want anything!
Just for now, this is proof of my love
This is Japan, people don't do
that sort of thing
I'm sorry
Huh?
Sometimes I can't control myself.
I know I should be more gentle.
I always thought I'd kill someone
I'm scared I might one day.
Ama, you're an adult now..
If you kill someone you'll go to prison
Understand?
Well, I'm still a minor so.
Idiot.
It's true
When I met you, didn't you say you were 24
Ah.. well..
When we met I just thought of that
I didn't want to sound like a kid
Anyway, how old are you?
I'm still under-age.
No way, really?
That's made me so happy!
We're the same
..say Ama, What's your real name?
Amano?.. Suama?
What's Suama??
I'm Ama, like Amadeus
My surname is Deus
Like Zeus, only cooler!
Oh?
Well if you don't want to tell me it's ok, but
No it's true! What about you?
Me?
You probably thought I was bout 14?
Yep
I'm Lui as in Louis Vuitton
Aah, you're an expensive girl.
- Come here!
- Stop it!
Dragons are ok?
Yeah,
I should probably go for a dragon
Ah, this one is Ama's tattoo right?
Ah yes.
It was a little different but it was that design
Hey
Does Ama know you`re here?
He doesn't know
Don't tell him I gave you my mobile number
Um, about Ama...
You want to know about him?
hmm, probably not.
- I don`t need to know anything
- ok
What, what`s up?
I close the shop when important customers come
Oh
I`m still a little unsure though.
It`s for life
I want only the coolest tatoo
You don't get a second chance, huh.
In my case
If I grew my hair you wouldn`t see it, but.
I bet you have others too.
You want to see?
decorated playing cards?
Yeah, I love that sort of design.
What`s this?
A "Kirin"
(Chinese mythical creature)
This one
is my absolute favourite.
It's a sacred animal
They walk without disturbing the grass,
and don't eat other animals.
Kind of a god of the animal kingdom
That's beautiful
I had this done in Japan, but
by a top class tattooist.
He held a design of a kirin..
.. when he burned himself to death.
If I tattoo a kirin on you,
and it becomes angry, it will feel like a curse.
This is what I want.
Please Shiba
Please, design one for me.
Guess I have no choice
Thank you Shiba
I'll start working on the design
Do you have any requests about the setting?
This
I'd like it combined with Ama's dragon, but
About the same size as Ama's,
I'd like that on my back, but...
..how much would you want?
Hmm
1 sexual act
..ok..
Take off your clothes
You're so thin
If you get fat, the tattoo will stretch and look wierd.
It's ok. I've weighed the same for a few years now.
Oh.
You even cuter when you're in pain.
I'm really turned on
Say, what kind of sex does Ama like?
Um..
Normal, i guess.
That's got to be frustrating.
Not really.. I can enjoy normal ok..
What?
I'm not normal, you think I can't come?
Can you?
No
So you're a mad sadist instead?
But I can with men.
I get turned on all kinds of ways
Are you wet?
Is it making you sick?
Painful? Huh?
- Do it
- Huh?
Hurry, do it, please!
Shut up
Keep crying
I'm ..
Will you contact me when the design is done?
Sure
Bring Ama too
I'll show you in secret
Ring me during the daytime ok?
Ama is at work then.
Sure thing.
I don't know if I'm a son of god..
Son of god?
You're more like a saw
God is definately a sadist,
for giving life to humans..
Mary was a masochist?
Definately
Oh, have you had anything to eat?
Ama will be home by now so..
Ah
See you soon
Are you ok?
I don't want to be in this world
I want to burn brightly until the
very end of this dark world,
Many private think-tanks inside and outside
the country say grounds for concern are low
but the rate of the economic recovery
has once again slowed
highlighting the likelihood of decline
from the current situation..
Also in the news,
Around 1am on 11th in Shibuya, Tokyo
A man was found collapsed in a pool of blood.
Passers by who discovered him,
transported the man to hospital,
where died around 2 hours later
from head injuries.
The deceased, who is believed to
be a member of the Tooru Murata gang,
was 25 year old Satoru Yokoyama
The cause of death was cerebral contusion
caused by skull fractures
A suspect seen fleeing the area is
described as 20 years old,
between 175 and 180 centimeters tall,
with red hair, slender build and black clothing.
Police are asking anyone with information
about the whereabouts of the suspect
to contact Police Headquaters in Shibuya
Good evening
Ama! Ama! Wake up!
Lui, what's up?
- come over here
- what?
- quickly
- what's this about?
never mind!
ok, sit here please
we're changing your hair colour
that red doesn't suit you
it's bothered me for a while
It looks kind of dirty,
You should have more sense
Lui you're too kind
I should have more style i guess,
thanks for helping
Sure
Thanks, Lui
For you I'd even cut it all off
I'd wear whatever clothes you'd like
How about having my skin lightened?
Give me a break
Ama..
From tomorrow you have to
wear long sleeves.
Why?
Quiet..
If you wear sensible clothes you
won't look so dumb
Ok
- You understand?
- got it
Can you promise?
I promise. If it's for you, anything's fine
Stop pulling that face
Would you like another drink?
Thank you
Lui
You suprised me
You really got your tongue pierced?
- A guy's influence?
- Ah, i guess.
I think it's his tongue I love..
Hello?
Hello Lui? Where are you? What are you doing?
Sorry, I got called in to help out with
some companion work.
What? You have a job?
What's "companion"?
Hey! It's a registration system
It's a normal kind of job..
Anyway, I'll call you back later.. bye!
Sorry
He try to keep you under control huh?
No, he's a just a bit immature.
He gets upset easily.
That's cute
It would be ok if it were just cute..
Ah, here you are. Skiving off work!
Sorry
Come on
Ama!
You're hair looks better this colour after all
- You think?
- Yep, very cool
Really?
Ah, you're as cute as ever
- You sure?
- Sure.
Hey look!
Split togue!
Hehe! Split togue!
Wait, wait..
I was relieved to see Ama laughing.
He seemed happy enough
His hair wasn't red anymore
I felt like there was no need to worry
Just going to buy cigarettes
Hello?
It's me. The design is done
A dragon and kirin as you requested.
It's not perfect but i've done all I can.
Ok
I want to show you as soon as possible
See you soon
Bye
Thank you
Who was that?
Ah, Maki. She said we should get
together again.
Yeah we should
Awesome!
Is it ok?
Will you tattoo it on me?
Sure
- You got it!
- Stop that
From tomorrow, don't drink alcohol
and make sure you sleep well
- I will
- Don't worry
I'm looking after her
Wow, when you walk down the street with
Shiba, everybody takes notice!
You stand out more than me
What are you saying?
You're both as scary looking as each other!
Phht
I bet we look like a pretty
wierd bunch all together
I want to go to a bar
- Good idea
- Let's go
I always thought I'd leave this area blank.
Here?... hmm, cool..
Sorry
I love this butterfly
Yeah?
This spot too
Toilet break
So, no complaints about the design?
Of course not
It will look so good on you
I have no doubt. It will be done
by your hand after all
Gods hand
When I tattoo you
If I get an urge to kill you
I don't know what I'll do
It's ok. What will be will be
I've never felt such a strong
intent to kill someone
There's puke all over the toilet
I feel sick now too
It was you wasn't it
It wasn't me!
I bet it was you
What are you saying? Honestly!
A toast
Aah, that's great
Shiba, this tastes great
Ama Deus, who killed for me,
the child of God who wants to
kill me,
I don't know which one is more
likely to kill me first.
Is it ok if I go tomorrow too?
Aren't you at work tomorrow?
Sometimes I don't trust Shiba
I'm worried, I don't want to lose you.
Don't worry about that. Shiba's a pro.
He wouldn't do anything like that
I know. But be careful, won't you..
Sometimes..
I don't understand him at all.
It's harder to find someone as easy
to understand as you
By this time tomorrow, there'll be
a dragon laying here
And a kirin
Your skin is so white, it's almost
a shame to spoil it
But it's gonna be so sexy.
Did you sleep ok?
Ama made sure I slept for 8 hours.
Ok
Today I'll do the outline
The design will be inked in completely
If there's anything you want to change, tell me now.
I do have one request
I don't want them to have any eyes
You mean the pupils?
Thats right, I don't want any black at the centre.
Why is that?
You know the story of the 'finishing touch'?
When you finish something,
you lose it at that moment
Ok, I understand
I won't finish the eyes.
It may make the faces look unbalanced though,
Is it ok if I put some shading around the edges?
Thanks Shiba
Have it your way.
Is it ok there?
Ok
Hey, look
I'm up to size 10
Don't go too quickly
If you force it to expand too quickly
it will become inflamed and sore. It's different to ears..
Ok
- Is it hurting?
- uh-huh
I'll begin
Are you ready?
Tell me if it hurts too much
You can really stand pain, huh.
Most people can't, especially the first time.
I wonder if I'm just not sensitive?
No way, you're fine.
You are gentle after all
The first puff is the best
No way, the second is the sweetest
So, did you want to kill me?
Yeah, so I concentrated on the work
If you ever want to die,
would you let me do it?
Is it ok if I perform necrophilia too?
Why not, I'd already be dead..
But if I couldn't see you in pain
I probably wouldn't be able to get an erection
Lui, I'm here!
Ah, I've just finished
You finish work early?
Said I had constipation so I got to leave early
Where do you work that you get to leave early because of constipation?
Well, the boss got mad but whatever
Whoa! Shiba thank you!
But Shiba
did you do anything wierd with Lui?
Don't worry
I have no desire for skinny girls.
Wait.
Neither the dragon nor the kirin have any pupils..
I told him to do that
I said don't put them in
Why
If he puts the eyes in, they might fly away
Aaah, i see..
But, my dragon has eyes and it hasn't flown away
- Shut it.
- Ow, ow
Don't take a bath for a while, ok?
It will probably form a scab in a week or so
but don't scratch it.
After that, the swelling will subside
Then when the scab has come off completely, call me
Ok
Ah Shiba, want to go somewhere for a meal?
Half way through a job? Are you kidding?
Come here a second
Come here
Why did you come here in that dress?
You could have worn jeans to get the tattoo?
I thought I should wear something loose
So the air would get to the tattoo afterwards
Do you think I'm pathetic?
..just a little..
Do you hate me?
Sorry.. I'm sorry
I thought we might break up
but I really love you
Let's go
That day, I drank until i collapsed
Ama looked after me, as cheerfully as ever
One month after that day, Ama was still by my side
Each time I stretched the hole in my tongue
The pain made me wonder if it's worth while
and I take it all out on Ama.
Whenever I changed the piercing,
I started wishing everyone would die.
I was losing my values and sense of reason.
When the tattoo is finished and my tongue has been split
What will I think then?
I will have nothing left,
Care about nothing, and live without blame
In the future, the tattoo and split tongue
will surely have no meaning at all
I wonder if should I quit tattooing
Get a girl, live a normal life. Like Ama
Do you have to give up tattooing to do that?
I mean start a new life
I've tattooed the best kirin I can.
I have no feelings of regret
The dragon and kirin dancing on my back
will never be separated from me
We decided on each other
This relationship can't be betrayed
After all, they can't go anywhere if they don't have eyes
After the tattoo was completed
I really had no energy left
wanting everyday to pass quickly.
- Lui you shouldn't be drinking
- Shut up
Ama worried over my binging
And even though I wanted to respond to him..
every time, the loathing I felt for myself..
eventually pushed me back to drinking again
Anyhow, the absence of light
my life, my future and inside my head was total darkness
The only time i could sense any true feeling
was when I felt pain.
Lui, do you ever think you want to die?
Always
If you harmed that body of yours
I could never forgive you.
So if you do, would you kill me too?
Everybody else dominates you
But I have no influence at all. I can't stand it
If I did decide to die
Which should I ask to do it?
Which would do it most skillfully?
Yeah?
Ah, It's me
Is now a good time?
Is something wrong?
It's about Ama
What?
Was he involved in something around September time?
I don't know
Why?
The police came here a while ago
Said they wanted to see a list of tattoo customers
Customers with tattoos of dragons.
I don't think it's Ama, but..
It can't be Ama.
He's always with me.
That's right. Sorry
They said he had red hair too.
Didn't he have red hair?
I'm slightly worried
Yeah he did.
Anyway, I got a little worried and thought I should call you. Thats all
Are you coming today?
Ah, no thanks
Today's off, I'll come again soon though
You're not coming?
I have something to discuss with you
Ok, I'll come when I feel like it.
Hello
Why did you lie?
Tired?
I'm not joking, you seem odd
What?
When did we meet last?
2 Weeks ago wasn't it?
Are you losing weight?
I don't know. Ama doesn't have any scales
You're looking ill and worn out.
Your skin is looking bad and you smell of alcohol
Isn't Ama feeding you?
He never shuts up telling me to eat
But I'd rather just drink
So that's what you're doing? Starving yourself
before suicide?
I'm not committing suicide
Did you come to buy something?
What do you want?
I came for a beer
The beer's in the refrigerator
Is that all?
Shiba, have you ever killed anyone?
Yes
How did it feel?
It felt good.
Oh.
Take off your clothes
Didn't I come to buy something?
Your crying has turned me on.
Would you marry me?
Is that what you wanted to talk about?
Yeah
Ama is too much for you to bear
You are too much for Ama to bear
You two are not balanced at all
Therefore you think I should marry you?
Not particularly.. that's unrelated
It was just an after-thought
Anyway, I made you a ring.
You made it?
It's a hobby
Completely different from your hobbies, I know
It's cool
even if I shouldn't say so
Thank you
Just going shopping
The person you are calling is not in range
of our signal
or the phone is turned off, and cannot be reached.
The person you are calling...
- Excuse me
- Yes?
Can I report a missing person other than a relative here?
Yes you can
Well?
well?
The persons name?
I don't know Ama's full name
I can't report a person as missing
if I don't even know his name
What's Ama's name?
Huh? What's the hurry?
He hasn't come home.
I wan't to report him missing.
You don't know his name?
I don't
But you're living together.
So what?
Don't cry
Didn't you ever see a name
plate or letter or something?
Ama didn't have anything like a name plate.
The mailbox was always full of leaflets
'cos he never opened it
Did he go to work as usual yesterday?
But he didn't come home last night?
Right, he left for work as usual  but
didn't come home.
Why are you so upset after just one day?
It will be fine
He hasn't been home for 1 day, don't panic so much
He's not a kid
In all the time we've lived together
He hasn't spent 1 night away from home
He was once 30 minutes late leaving work
But he called me so I wouldn't worry.
That's how he is.
I know..
Ama, might have killed someone
The police said he was a Yakuza member
I told him not to
I told Ama to ignore him
Ama beat him up but..
I never thought he would die
Even when I saw it on the news
I didn't really think it was the same person
I was sure it was a different person
It couldn't have been about Ama.
If we report him missing to the police,
they may arrest him
If he knows about all of this and has gone on the run.
If he thinks we don't know about this,
he might have decided to disappear
without telling us.
I'm worried about him
It's too hard, not knowing where
he is or what he's doing
I don't think Ama would run away on his own
If he was going to, he would have taken me with him
I'm sure he would want me with him
Ok
Let's go
Why do you have a photo of him?
Ah,
When I did his tattoo, we took lots of photos..
Amada Kazunori, is it?
Yes
He's not called Ama Deus after all?
Are you ok?
Ama?
What's happened?
Why did you leave me behind?
Why did you go before me?
Didn't you say I meant everything to you?
Why have you left me alone?
Why?
What are you doing?
Hey, stick your tongue out!
Isn't that a zero? Weren't you at 4 yesterday?
Stop it
Take it out
You'll stretch it too far
When I get to 00 I can split my tongue
I know, I know..
Ama..
If Ama saw a 0 gauge pierce in my tongue,
what would he say?
He'd probably laugh..
and say "Awesome" !
"Just a little further"
I know..
that's what he would say
He'd be so happy
The person you are calling is not in range
of our signal
or the phone is turned off, and cannot be reached.
Hey
Do you know where Ama works?
What? You don't know?
I don't know.
We didn't know anything about each other
He works at a second hand clothes shop
You really didn't tell each other anything huh.
Did you discuss anything?
Hey, It's me.  It's about Ama
Ah..
He's not been in? What about yesterday?
If you find out anything, let me know ok?
He went to work as normal yesterday
but didn't today.
His boss is pretty angry.
I know the people there
They gave him a job without any questions
Does Ama have any family?
I don't know
I think he has one parent
He talked about his father once
Oh
What?
Nothing but beer
It's ringing
yes
I see
Yes, I understand.
A body has been found in Yokosu.
They don't know if it's Ama,
but there is a dragon tattoo
They want us to go to the morgue
to identify the body
Alright
Ama is dead
He had been strangled to death
All over his body were cigarette burns
every finger and toe nail had been pulled out
something like an incense stick
had been inserted into his penis.
How should it be said?
he was killed after being beaten and tortured.
Like an object or a possession,
he was played with and then killed
Lui, I'm going now
the last conversation we had
I had my back to Ama
I was thinking about meeting Shiba
See you later
When will you catch the killer?
We are doing all we can to investigate this matter
What? Am I being too pushy?
Please excuse me
Why did you come to the funeral when
you can't catch the killer?
and you're saying I'm pushy?
You don't have that authority
So, what?
So saying you can't catch his killer is ridiculous?
You're not trying because Ama killed too!
Why don't you all die!
Then everything will be settled
Calm down
You're not making sense
fuck off and die
We'll look after the store together
for a while
You have to take it easy
like the doctor said
When I left Ama's room
I went to live with Shiba
He tried to comfort me many
times, but couldn't
my lack of emotion meant he
couldn't even strangle me
Hey, Shiba
Ah, could you stop calling me Shiba?
My name is Shiba Kizuki
Sounds like a womans name, huh
I don't know why but everybody
calls me Shiba
What do you want me to call you?
Kizuki is fine
Kizuki
What?
You can't get any more in here
Ah yeah, it's full
Lui, is it ok if you
tell me your name?
You want to hear it?
Yeah, I'm listening
I'm Lui as in Louis Vuitton...
Your real name
Nakagawa Lui
What is Lui short for?
Lui, do you have any family?
Any parents?
I may look like an orphan but
I have parents
I think they live in Saitama
I'm surprised
You should go see them
I never had a conversation
like this with Ama
I should have tried to talk
about normal things more often
about family,
about names, about age
Ama was 18 years old and I
only found out at his funeral
He was the first person younger
than me I ever hung around with
and I only found that out now he's gone
I wish I had realised that earlier
and talked with him about it
The burns were all done with Marlboro
cigarettes, menthol flavoured
Of course, we're making progress with
saliva samples too
Also, the incense stick inserted
into the genitals
was a kind called 'Ecstacy', musk
variety imported from America
Surely incense is sold everywhere.
Yes, but.. in this area that kind
is not widely available
Also, we would like to ask you something..
Was Mr Amada bi-sexual?
Are you saying he was raped?
We found that out during the autopsy
No he wasn't bi-sexual. I can assure you
He definately wasn't that way
I see
No use
Oh.
You should rest
Where did you go? I was worried
Ah, I went to buy incense.
I hate musk
I bought coconut
Whats up
Nothing
So Kizuki, you should grow your hair
I like long hair
Ok.. I wonder if I should
grow it once in a while
The symbol of Ama's love for me,
became part of me
Kizuki, I have one more request
What is it?
Are you sure about this?
Ok
At last I can say this tattoo has a deep meaning to me,
for what my life has become.
I finally gave my dragon and kirin their eyes
I wonder if they will fly away?
I don't know
It's all ok.
If Shiba killed Ama
If Shiba raped Ama.. I accept it all.
Is this all I wanted?
This unsightly, gaping hole is all I needed?
What are you doing?
I am making a river inside of me
Huh?
I just had a wierd dream
What sort?
I was hanging out with a good
friend from a long time ago
but I was really late for an appointment
So my friend began to sing about his anger
5 or 6 people gathered around
and joined in the song...
If I had reached 00 gauge,
would the river have flowed more violently?