Possessions
(Tsukumo  - Tsukumogami)
I've sadly lost my way inside this rainstorm.
Please, I will like you to let me rest here until the rain stops.
What does this mean? What’s going on?
Are you comfortable here?
Make yourself feel like home.
My umbrella has been broken.
It's broken and pretty useless.
We'll have to toss it to the trash.
Straight to the trash.
Some fine umbrellas are these!
I'll borrow one!
¿Huh...?
I'm going back.
I'm going back! I'm going back!
Am I pretty?
Pretty.
Pretty... was being said by all.
But...
Fashion change in any moment.
What is out of fashion is stored in the drawer.
Hey...
Am I Pretty?
Nice flowered ball
Shame these have been dumped...
... They are good!
I'll borrow them!
Beautiful.
I'm just a traveler passing by.
Lost my way under the rain.
So I made myself at home in a corner of this shrine, but it seems occupied.
If you excuse me.
So... would you let me out?
That's a very nasty smell.
If my journey led me here...
... I'm expected to throw away the trash.
But... Before that
I must not forget...
Before I ascend, thank you for your welcome and help...
...good work.