The infinite expanse ofthe universe...
A place filled with silence and light...
Our Solar System is about
30,OOO light years away
from the Galactic Center.
Earth.
The planet that, like a mother,
gave birth to us and raised us.
At the center ofthe Milky Way,
there is a space-time void with a mass
two million times that of our sun:
a black hole.
A black hole...
A pitch-black hole whose grasp not even
the slightest ray of light can escape.
The density in the deepest parts ofthat
hole makes it so gravity is infinite.
At the beginning of the 21st century,
Professor Hawking
suggested the possibility
that the radiation emitted by
these bodies during vaporization
contains information about the
matter that was sucked in.
Even in the 23rd century,
black holes remain a phenomenon
unfathomable to mankind.
Thus, humanity is still not aware that black holes are
the true rulers ofthe space-time continuum.
No one has yet realized that
they are sentient life forms.
Like a young lion approaching
humans in the savanna,
feigning curiosity at first,
and then reacting in a
completely di_erent way...
Earth was suddenly faced
with a black hole.
Space Battleship Yamato.
17 years have passed since it sunk into the seas of
the migrating planet Aquarius.
lt is the year 2220 AD.
On Earth, mankind is confronted with an unprecedented
crisis:
a dark stellar body with a gravity so enormous not a
single ray of light can escape,
a black hole.
Every second, the black hole, hailing from a distant
corner ofthe galaxy, gets closer to Earth.
Gravitational signatures
detected at 12 o'clock!
Distance: approximately 25 space km!
What are those?
l have never seen ships like that before.
How many ships are there?
We have detected about
900 and counting.
900?!
At 2 o'clock!
Another unidentified fleet at 9:48!
We're being surrounded.
Captain, this is an ambush!
Hailing all ships!
Mark all unidentified vessels as hostile!
Kamijou, fire!
Fire! Fire! And fire again!
Those bastards...
Eat this!
All fighters, engage the enemy!
Protect the emigrant ships!
We're losing pressure quickly!
Disengage from the battlefield.
Warp!
Captain Kodai!
forfreighter Yuki.
Yes.
Here you go.
Captain!
lt took three months to arrive...
Thanks.
ls it from your wife again?
l really envy you.
Hello dear, how is the sea?
''The universe is a sea, and
the freighter is my ship. ''
lsn't that what you always said?
Miyuki and l are eagerly
awaiting your safe return.
Shipwreck detected!
Where's that shipwreck?
According to the map, it's 150
space km away at 4 o'clock.
We'll rescue the survivors.
Engine at full power!
Going full power with
this shabby engine...
this has got to be a joke!
Shut up and do it!
How long have you been on this ship?!
R-Right.
Full powerforward!
This is awful.
Look for survivors.
A survivor?
Looks like the barrier isn't broken.
Help him.
Damn!
You will pay for this!
Wait!
We're allies!
Allies?
H-Hey!
Emigrant ships from Earth?
Right.
l was part of an escort fleet
transporting 300 million people to Amarl.
300 million people?!
Were you attacked by them?
Y-Yes!
Damn!
Move!
All right, she can still fly.
Sakurai, locate the enemy's position.
Roger.
Damn them...
Wait!
Don't shoot yet!
Here they come.
Grab on to something!
What's your name?
Earth Defense Force 1st Lieutenant
and Tactical Oflicer Kamijou Ryo.
Kamijou, prepare the main battery!
Preparing main battery.
D-Distance: 3000!
C-Captain! We're going to collide!
Keep your cool, Sakurai!
We're going to crash!
Full throttle!
Now! Fire!
Firing main battey!
We did it!
Well done, Kamijou.
You've got some skill.
That's Captain Kodai for you!
Well done.
Captain Kodai...
The legenday captain of the Yamato...
We'll head back to Earth immediately.
Mayday! Mayday!
Who the hell are they?
Why are they attacking us?!
Here they come!
H-Help us!
When did this happen?
lt has been sent through the
booster relays a few times.
The footage is three days old.
Why were they attacked?
This is a massacre!
Who's the enemy?
We don't know.
Chief.
Shouldn't we postpone the departure
of the Third Emigration Fleet until
we know more about the situation?
We can't send transpoR ships there
knowing they will be destroyed!
Continue as planned.
With all due respect...
Has Kodai returned yet?
Kodai-san?
He's the only one who can save
the Earth from this danger.
We don't have much time.
Chief, we've been contacted by the Solar System
Communication Bureau.
Displaying transmission on screen B.
Okay.
This is the Solar System
Communication Bureau.
Deep space cargo vesseI Yuki wIl be be warping
out within the system.
Kodai...
You've come back...
Excuse me, Captain.
We're ready to warp out.
Okay, l'll be right there.
lt's been three years, huh.
l bet your daughter has
grown up into a fine lady.
Yeah.
We're finishing our lastjump.
We've finally returned to Earth!
Aquarius.
This observation footage has been colored, processed
and fast-forwarded
to make it easy to understand.
l hadn't expected this...
This is a black hole that doesn't move according to
any pattern we've observed.
We're calling it the
''Cascading Black Hole. ''
Yes, sir.
Are we certain it will devourthe Earth?
Yes.
We have run the
calculations over and over.
We are certain that it's passing
through the Solar System.
lt's unavoidable.
We estimate eight million seconds
before it reaches Earth.
ln other words, Earth has just three
months left until its destruction.
Yes.
We first observed this black
hole three years ago.
We gathered astronomers
from all around the world,
and organized daily conferences
to discuss countermeasures.
Altering the black hole's
trajectoy, destroying it...
terraforming one of the frontier planets
and temporarily taking shelterthere...
They even looked into
shifting the Earth's orbit.
Eventually, they came to the conclusion
that none of these possibilities were
feasible with our current technology.
Mankind's only hope is to seek
refuge in the vastness ofspace.
l've put Shima-kun in charge
ofthe emigration plans,
and finalized the preparations forthe evacuation of mankind
while helping them understand this decision.
l've heard that the crew ofthe salvaged ship was
escorting people to Amarl.
lndeed.
Amarl is located in the Sairam System.
Our destination is its moon.
Will we be able to
create a second Earth?
This is the route ofthe
Second Emigration Fleet.
Displaying map on screen C.
Any intel on the fleet that attacked us?
No, we have no intel on them yet.
Will the Earth vanish...
without leaving behind a trace?
This planet that the
Yamato has protected...
lndeed.
That's why l've been waiting for you.
For me?
l want you to take command ofthe Third Emigration
Fleet escort forces.
You're the only one
who can save mankind.
You're giving me too
much credit, Sanada-san.
l deserted the Earth and roamed
aimlessly for three years.
l'm not the man l used to be.
However, Yuki knew that you'd take
responsibility in this crisis
and assumed command o1the
First Emigration Fleet.
Miyuki...
Does she know about the
First Emigration Fleet?
''Dear, how is space?
The universe is your sea, isn't it?''
So you've returned...
Welcome back, Miyuki.
Your motherEUR''
lt's your fault, Father.
Th-That's not true.
You're way too attached to the Yamato.
The Yamato has already
sunk, don't you get it?
lt's resting in the depths ofthat sea.
Yes.
Mom just pretended to understand.
ln truth, she was so lonely.
ln my memories, her smile was
always veiled by loneliness.
l wantto see mom.
Miyuki, l haven't given up on her!
Kodai here.
We have an emergency!
The Second Emigration Fleet has been attacked by
an unknown armada.
We've lost contact with them!
Understood.
l'll be right there.
Just go.
l'm sorry.
So the Second Fleet was
annihilated as well...
Both the First and Second fleet
were attacked in the same vicinity,
a region about 17,OOO light
years away from Earth.
lt's as ifthey were ambushed.
There's one more thing bothering me.
The enemy fleet was diflerent
from the one l've encountered.
Theirform is too di_erent.
l fear it's a fleet from another planet.
Does that mean that several parties
are attacking Terran fleets?
lt looks like someone is trying
to prevent the emigration.
Please allow me to command
the Third Emigration Fleet.
Thanks, Kodai.
ForYuki, for mankind...
Your ship is ready foryou.
lt's the Space Battleship Yamato.
The Yamato?!
Space Battleship Yamato
is awaiting your return.
Aquarius.
17 years ago...
the migrating planet Aquarius
threatened to flood the Earth.
Kodai, Yuki.
You two will have a wonde_ul child.
Since it will be your child, l'm
sure itwill be really adorable.
l'll think of it as my grandchild.
Mother Earth...
Take care ofthese kids.
Yamato...
You have lought and
perished for this planet.
Let's go to where the soldiers rest.
Fire!
Yamato.
Yes.
This is the new Space
Battleship Yamato, Kodai.
Yuki, l don't believe that you died.
No matter where you are, be
it the depths of Hell...
l'll come and save you.
Waitfor me!
However, l have to save humanity first.
Hey!
Don't touch the Yamato, old man!
Who are you?
You're a spy, aren't you?
Fight me!
Wait! lEUR''
No excuses!
That idiot!
Not bad!
YouEUR''
What are you doing, Kobayashi?!
Captain Kodai!
Captain?
Captain, l was an engineer on
the Yamato. Tokugawa Tasuke.
lt's been a long time, Tokugawa.
Currently, l'm in command ofthe Earth Defense
Force Moonbase Yamato Reconstruction Project.
You're in charge of
rebuilding the Yamato?
Yes.
Hey wait!
Hey! Hold on!
We're the ones that rebuilt
the Yamato's engine room.
l see.
That sounds reassuring.
Would you tell me your names?
Tenma Sou from engineering.
Likewise, Shou.
And you?
Earth Defense Force
pilot, Kobayashi Jun.
Though he's lacking in
military discipline...
D-Don't laugh!
So this is the new wave-motion engine...
The old Yamato had one
nuclear reactorwave core.
On the other hand, the new Yamato has six big nuclear
reactor wave cores.
Six?
Then the wave-motion cannon can...
Yes, it can fire six rounds.
That's amazing.
That's quite a power-up.
Ob...
... viously!
Check this super charger!
The six consecutive transition wave-motion cannon
rounds can even blow the moon into smithereens!
But ifwe were to use all six rounds,
the engine would be depleted.
l see.
So we mustn'tfire all the rounds.
Which means it has to be
maintained pe_ectly.
Of...
... course!
So, Sakurai, how is the
Yamato's computer room?
Captain!
This is unreal! As
expected from the Yamato.
l've been pumped up with excitement!
l trust you to make full use
ofthe ECl's potential.
Yes, sir!
You're the only crew member that has experienced
a voyage to Amarl.
l have high hopes for
you as a piler as well.
Yes, sir!
l've only gone there as practice, but
l'll live up to your expectation.
Maho-san, this is the Captain.
Captain?
l am the ECl Chief
Navigator, Orihara Maho.
l think we've met at the
Astro Science Department.
Yes.
So you were that Orihara.
You're being called the Child of
the ECl, the genius navigator.
Oh my, genius?
You're exaggerating.
Your task is very important.
l'm counting on your
assistance with Sakurai-kun.
Yes, Captain!
We're about to depart.
Everyone, run your systems checks.
Yes, sir.
Departure, huh...
All this nervousness
has made me hungry.
Every time you open your mouth it's to say you're
hungry. Isn't it, Nakanishi-kun?
Will you be able to fire?
What?
l'm wondering ifwe should really leave the wave-motion
cannon to a loser.
Say that again...
Stop it, Kobayashi!
This is the Yamato we
brought back to Jife.
l don't want itto sink.
You...
Stop it!
Stop!
Aren't you Kobayashi, the chief pilot?
And you are Kamijou, the
tactical o_icer, right?
Who are you?
l'm Oomura Kousaku, the
executive oflicer.
l don't care ifyou're the XO or the CEO.
lt's me and the Tenma brothers who brought the Yamato
back to life!
l don't want to see it getting wrecked!
lnsubordinate brat!
The rebirth ofthe Yamato was only possible because
all of mankind wished for it!
C-Captain.
Gentlemen.
l'm the Captain of the
Yamato, Kodai Susumu.
Your lives are in my hands now.
We will protect humanity and
the Earth with the Yamato!
How do you feel?
Great!
The Seventh, Eighth and Ninth Escort Fleets are
Iaunching from Moonbase.
They're going to rendezvous with
the Third Emigration Fleet.
They're currently awaiting
orders in lunar orbit.
All ships, prepare for departure.
A_irmative.
lnitiating wave engine.
Moving to the ECl to
finalize preparations.
All systems functional.
Engine room, all systems ready.
Engine room is ready.
All communication lines are open.
All transfers functional.
All radars functional.
Firing systems are functional.
lnternal systems, all green.
No anomalies detected.
Navigation systems functional.
Launching preparations are done.
Undocking.
Activate the auxiliary engine.
Linking auxiliary engine to power nexus.
Switching on the power nexus.
Enable the first and second
flywheel in ten seconds.
First flywheel connected!
Second flywheel connected!
Yeah!
Releasing the gantry lock.
Yamato, take ofl!
Farewell, Mother Earth. It's
time for this ship to depart.
Space Battleship Yamato,
fly to the other side of
the universe, to Iscandar.
Shoulder your destiny and take ofl now.
l'm sure you will come back here
and answer the people that
wave to you with a smile.
Leave the galaxy and go all the way
to Iscandar, Space Battleship Yamato.
We're counting on you, Yamato.
Take care of it, Kodai.
Kobayashi, that was a great maneuver.
Of course!
The Solar System, where the Earth is located, is
positioned in the Orion Spur.
lt's about 30,OOO light
years away from the center.
We're currently observing this part.
lt's approaching from this angle.
l think it's going to suck in the
Solar System as it passes through.
The destination ofthe emigrant fleet is
the planet Amarl in the Sairam System.
lt's 27,OOO light years away
from the Galactic Center.
The emigration lleet will reach its
destination after warping several times.
However, the First and Second Emigration Fleets were
attacked by an unknown armada
about halfway into their voyage in
this region 17,OOO light years away,
and were annihilated.
ln otherwords, the Yamato's mission is not only to
escort the Third Emigration Fleet safely there,
but, also, to bring the
ships back to Earth.
Before the Earth is swallowed
by the Cascading Black Hole...
After all the emigrant
ships have been prepped,
we will make the first warp jump.
Dismissed.
Dr. Sasaki.
l've been pondering about
this for a while now.
Why do you have goggles?
Oh? You didn't know?
l don't quite look the part,
but l'm actually a pilot.
You're a pilot?
Oh and...
''Doctor'' sounds too formal.
l'm just not used to it.
You can call me Miharu.
First and second engines, ignite.
Understood.
lgniting first and second engines.
Yamato, enter warp.
The Third Emigration
Fleet and the Yamato,
consumed by the fear that the unknown enemy fleet
could strike at any time,
continued theirjourney to Amarl.
But at that time...
Attention leaders o1 the
Interstellar Alliance...
The president o1the Alliance, SUS representative
Governor-General Metzler, has arrived.
A big threat, a galactic evil...
Earth has made its move.
Behold.
So Earth finally made their move.
They have really started their invasion.
We cannot turn a blind eye while
Earth jeopardizes our peace.
On behalfofthe Alliance, l hereby command the
annihilation of the Terran fleet.
Unless the Earth is destroyed,
our Alliance cannot prosper.
Admiral, we have received a message from the
Interstellar Alliance through the Ethos brass.
Report.
A gigantic fleet has departed the Earth.
Attack and destroy upon sight.
Currently, we are 17,OOO
light years away from Earth.
Eveything has gone smoothly so far.
Orihara, deploy the probes.
Roger.
Launching the probes.
What the hell is this?
Maho-san, what is that?
lt's a honeycomb-type search network.
They could be observing our movements.
l assume the First and Second Emigration Fleets
were caught by this network.
That's very likely, since
they were ambushed.
Maho, show me how far
the network extends.
Stafl, gather in the
central situation room.
How big is the network?
lt's impossible to get past it.
lf it were just the Yamato, we
could push our way through,
but it's impossible to take that
many emigrant vessels along.
Captain, why don't we make
a turning movement there?
We could make a long warp jump straight from
the emigrant fleet rendezvous point.
Even if it's feasible
with the Yamato's engine,
their ship engines can't
possibly handle such a jump.
l think it could work.
There is a black hole called
BH-199 nearthe emigrant fleet.
We will go through that.
l'm putting it on the screen.
lt's gigantic... with a mass
300 times that ofthe Sun.
The gravity is enormous, too.
We'll accelerate while being pulled in...
By using that gravity pull,
we can make a flyby.
Don't be ridiculous!
Can you imagine what will
happen ifthe flyby goes wrong?
lfwe fail,
after passing the event horizon, we will be swallowed
by the black hole.
Right.
But it's still feasible!
Hey, academy brat.
There's no signboards
showing the event horizon.
Are you aware how many lives are
dependent on our decisions?
Even ifyou try to go back
in your own footsteps,
you will be long swallowed by
the black hole, academy brat.
What do you think, Oomura-san?
lt's definitely tricky.
l have no prior experience in approaching black holes
with emigrant ships...
However...
There's no otherway, right?
Yes.
We'll pe_orm a flyby.
We cannot overcome this hurdle
ifwe're consumed by fear.
Orihara, collect data on BH-199.
Sakurai, apprise the fleet of our plans.
Yes, sir.
So they really came.
All vessels, prepare to engage.
Attention all ships,
we're pe_orming the last warp
jump to the Sairam System.
Take your positions and
warp out in order!
Just like that... carefully...
Maintain speed at 99 space knots.
Speed: 120 space knots.
Roger.
l can't stand this anymore!
Please! Oh, please!
The first group has warped out.
Thank the heavens.
All right!
lt's a great success!
The second group is about to warp.
What a fearless warp.
We can'tjust sit here slack-jawed.
Their commander seems to
be an interesting person.
We cannot allow them to slip away.
All vessels, attack!
Captain, the enemy fleet has appeared.
Direction: 4:23.
Distance: 2, 8 space km.
lt's them!
Don't panic!
We still have some time.
Let the emigration fleet
continue warping out.
All escoR lorces disperse
and cover their backs.
Kobayashi, alter the course to 4:23.
Roger.
Altering the course to 4:23.
Kamijou, this battle is in your hands.
Understood.
All ships, prepare for battle.
Man your turrets.
All fighters, prepare to sortie.
Kobayashi, turn the Yamato to the
ridge ofthe emigration fleet.
Understood.
Just watch!
l'll crush you all!
Another enemy fleet
has appeared at 3:30.
Anotherfleet has appeared at 1:20.
Attention escort fleet,
Split in two!
One halfwill take the port side fleet, the other half the
starboard side.
The Yamato will engage
the enemy in the middle!
All fighters, launch!
l'll go too!
The more the better!
But you're the one steering the Yamato...
l'll do it.
He's better suited to fly a fighter.
The greater our force is the better our chance to protect
the emigration fleet.
Kobayashi, take command of
the Cosmo Pulser Squad.
Thanks!
Understood!
Hey, Maho!
lt's me, Kobayashi.
l'll protect you from the outside.
Hey Miharu, wanna go on
a space date with me?
Don't be silly.
Kobayashi, l heard that weird confession.
That was no confession.
Doctor! What are you doing?
You can't go out.
Hush!
l got on the Yamato because
l like this stu_.
But what ifwe have casualties?
You can do the first aid.
Kobayashi, l'll shoot you
down ifyou screw up!
All right!
l'd be okay with it if l
were shot down by you.
Cosmo Pulser Squadron, follow me!
Full speed ahead!
Prepare the main battery!
All vessels, open fire!
Kobayashi, several fighters are being launched from the
vessels in the center!
Take care ofthem!
Roger!
All units, altitude: 9000.
Follow me!
Miharu, behind you!
Nice one, Miharu.
l'll hug you when we get back.
Jerk.
Shift all muzzles to the left!
Prepare the stack missiles!
Distance: 30 space km.
Firing angle: 45oard.
Fire!
Aim for that big ship!
Roger.
An enemy group is approaching the emigrant vessels
from the port at 4:30.
Distance: 18 space km.
Kamijou, deploy the heavy bomber.
Yes, sir!
Heavy bomber, attack the hostile at 4:30 port of
the emigrant vessels.
Roger!
Now!
Fire!
Yes, sir.
Prepare first and second batteries.
Fire!
Launch bow torpedoes!
What are they doing?
lt's that ship...
That ship is encouraging the whole
fleet and increasing their power.
That ship?
Aim for that ship.
Forget about the others.
Blow that ship to smithereens!
Yes, sir!
Damn that Gorui...
Having trouble against a fleet like that.
He's not worth my attention.
Escort ships Hatsuyuki
and Shirayuki are down.
Explosions in the Asagiri.
The enemy is moving
toward the black hole.
How far along are the emigrant vessels?
880/o ofthem have warped.
Attention all escoR ships,
pull back as you fight,
and prepare to warp after
the emigration fleet.
The Yamato will take
care ofthe enemy fleet!
All fighters, help the
escort force to withdraw!
Damn!
l'll kill them for sure!
Prepare the wave-motion cannon!
Don't get carried away, Kamijou!
lt's pointless to use the wave-motion
cannon against a scattered fleet!
Not only is it ine_ective,
but it will cost the Yamato
the energy it needs to warp.
l'm sorry.
This fleet is completely di_erent from the one we
defeated the other day.
lt's because ofthat ship.
Such a sublime decision... not to
Iose even a single emigrant vessel.
Their spirit is what makes their command ofthe
whole fleet so extraordinay.
You seem to admire the enemy.
ls this really the way an invader fights?
l feel a strong will to live,
rather than to invade.
What we are doing is no
di_erent than a massacre.
That ship on the other hand...
Rapid turn!
Captain! What are you doing?
Kamijou, shoot randomly at that ship!
Yes, sir!
Cease the attack!
Why?
Don't you think that it would be
regrettable to bury that enemy?
lndeed.
lt's frantically trying to protect the emigrant vessels by
risking its own life.
We used to have that soldierly spirit.
But look at us now...
Now we are bound to that parvenu SUS
and helping to massacre people.
Don't you think we should stop
degrading ourselves any further?
lt's something only you'd say, Admiral.
Cease the attack, Captain.
Understood, sir.
Attention Ethos fleet, cease fire!
Full speed ahead!
Where are we going?
We must regain our honor.
Enemy fire has stopped.
What?
All fighters, hury up!
Captain, there's an incoming
transmission from that ship.
What?
Put it on the panel.
l'm the Commander in Chief o1 Planet
Ethos's fleet, Admiral Gorui.
l highly admire your
eflort on the battlefield.
Would you tell me the name
of the captain and his ship?
EaRh Defense Force Space
Battleship Yamato.
l'm the Captain, Kodai Susumu.
Space Battleship
Yamato... Captain Kodai.
l'll be frank now.
The Ethos military has
many excellent allies,
and it also respects formidable enemies.
This is an old tradition.
lf l cannot protect this honor,
l'd chose an honorable
death like the Yamato.
l'd like to ask you, Admiral Gorei.
Why are you attacking us?
lt's decision of the Greater
Urup InterstellarAlliance.
The leadership ofthe union
has been grabbed by the SUS.
The SUS...
But this massacre is nothing but an irrational
way of demonstrating their power.
Therefore, l deeply respect your e_orts ofsaving
the emigration fleet from them.
l appreciate that, Admiral Gorui.
Good luck.
What's the meaning ofthis, Gorui?
l'm only following the
Ethos military honor code.
Does the honor code ofthe Ethos military state to defy the
decision ofthe Greater Urup InterstellarAlliance?
lsn't that the will of the SUS,
rather than that ofthe Alliance?
l assume you know the
consequences ofdefying us.
Oh, what are you going to do?
lfyou ever defy my orders again,
l'll not only destroy you,
but your whole planet!
Keep that in mind.
Destroy Ethos?
No matter what happens, our
citizens will understand.
Attention all emigrant vessels.
We're about to arrive at Amarl.
Finalize your preparations.
Kobayashi, you can switch back now.
Yes, sir.
lt's the Yamato!
The Yamato has come!
lndeed.
Wow!
Thank heavens this emigration
fleet made it safely here.
Looks like the emigrants
are doing fine here.
Yes.
There's something l'd like to ask.
ls the First Emigration Fleet's
Ieader, Kodai Yuki, here?
l'm afraid she's missing.
Actually, my current duties were supposed to
be handled by Commander Kodai.
We were busy trying to warp out and
escape underfierce enemy fire.
The ship she boarded warped
without a person on board.
Oh, where is it?
lt's this ship.
So you couldn't find her body...
Yes.
l see.
l will keep searching for her.
Thank you.
From now on, that moon will
become our Earth, huh?
l wonder i1the people of Amarl
will call it Earth as well?
Sorry.
Well, people would oppose me if
l were to call that moon Earth.
When l think that the
Earth cannot be saved...
We have to accept it.
Without that resolve,
it would mean that mankind
has merely run away from it.
Chief Sanada!
We have received a message
from Captain Kodai.
We have landed on Amarl.
April 5th, 14:10 Earth time.
The situation is as follows:
6, 300 emigrant vessels,
162 escort ships.
Furthermore, we've met up with the survivors of
the First and Second fleets.
This adds up to 630 million people.
After the maintenance works,
the Yamato will return with
the six emigrant vessels.
Over.
He did it!
Kodai-san lives up to his name.
Yeah.
Thanks Kodai.
l'm awaiting your quick return.
Hey, wait!
Your leg hasn't healed yet.
You have to be patient for a bit longer.
Miyuki-chan!
Hello, Dr. Sado.
Kodai and his crew have
safely landed on Amarl.
That's Kodai for you!
Miyuki-chan, at times like these
just be honest and happy...
Dr. Sado...
My father has the Yamato.
Miyuki-chan, do you know...
... do you know how many lives
he and your mom have saved?
Mother...
He couldn't save Mother!
lt's time to give it his milk.
Young kids are hard to understand.
lndeed.
Your Majesty.
l've heard that Amarl is working
together with the Interstellar Alliance.
Long ago the center ofthe Milky
Way sufFered from great wars.
Our country was sucked into
those wars, and was ruined.
That situation continued
over generations.
The first step toward peace
was under the mighty SUS.
The flames of war stopped
upon SUS's call of peace.
And that gave birth to the
InterstellarAlliance.
So that's why the SUS is the
Ieader ofthe Alliance.
Yes.
But in truth it's merely a tyrannical dictatorship
under the guise of ''peace. ''
We ought to hate the SUS.
But...
But?
We're supplying the SUS with resources.
Resources?
Yes, there's a material that
only exists on this planet.
And in return we are receiving
the SUS's protection.
Could you really call
this peace for Amarl?
Stop!
l'm General Pascal.
Go in there.
Captain Kodai, l'd like to ask you
to leave our country at once.
lf we accept Terrans,
we will be punished by the
InterstellarAlliance's forces.
ln the worst case, they
would destroy this planet.
Please, leave this planet.
Are you saying that you'll bow
down to a cowardly tyrant?
lt's to protect this country.
We don't have any time.
lfyou aren't going to
listen to our plea, then...
We were too late!
l want you to stay out ofthis.
Please don't drive us further
into this predicament.
Forward!
lt's them!
There's no mistake!
Them?
They attacked the First Fleet.
Sir, prepare to launch!
We'll get ready for the fight!
Wait!
How can you order us into combat
readinessjust like that?
Only the Captain can decide that.
They're withdrawing.
l assume thatwasjust theirfirst wave.
Captain!
Give us the orderto sortie!
What happened?
This is notjust our problem.
The SUS and Amarl are both members ofthe same
InterstellarAlliance after all.
Our decision could greatly a_ect Amarl.
We cannot act carelessly.
No way. .
All hands, prepare for
engagement and stand by.
Several enemy crafts on high
altitude above the city.
Crap!
This has to be the second wave.
Call Me_ler.
Yes sir.
Commander Me_ler, why
are you attacking Amarl?
Aren't we allies?
They are being sanctioned for defying the Greater
Urup InterstellarAlliance's decision.
l believe the InterstellarAlliance didn't tell us to murder
Amarl civilians as well.
Who decided that?!
lt's the SUS.
The SUS's decision is the decision
ofthe InterstellarAlliance.
Now, Gorui, commence
your attack already.
l refuse.
Admiral...
Your unpleasant attitude from
yesterday has caught our attention.
l've just realized how you've
degraded to the level of a pig.
l'll keep those words in mind.
Looks like you've finally let it out.
Humans cannot choose
how they are born,
but they can choose how they die.
l want to die honorably!
lncoming transmission
from Admiral Gorui.
Okay, l'll get back to the bridge.
Captain Kodai.
Admiral.
What we're doing is definitely not in order to protect
the people of Earth or Amarl.
lt's the decision ofthe people of Ethos.
We have been oppressed in
exchange for ''peace. ''
That's how the Interstellar
Alliance truly operates.
We're hereby going to put an end to this!
The day will come when they realize
how foolish their actions were.
Ourtarget is theflagship Maya,
Metzler!
Understood.
Full powerforward!
That's...
Crush Gorui!
Damn that Gorui!
Pascal.
What do you think of Ethos's decision?
Your Majesty!
The citizens have gathered in
front ofthe royal palace!
Their numbers are gradually increasing!
Make Amarl independent!
Let's fight along with the Yamato!
Queen Ilya!
Declare our independence!
Let's fight along with the Yamato!
What do you say about
their cries, Pascal?
Damn!
l want to kick their asses...
Why isn't the captain
giving the orderto fire?
Yuki, Amarl is walking the
path of peril for our Earth.
However, the Yamato can't do anything...
lfwe retaliate, Amarl can be saved.
But then humanity will lose its
place to settle, and perish.
Your courage has always
protected the Earth.
lt saved humanity.
You never succumb to injustice, and
always hold up righteousness...
Even if it means risking your own life.
l'm sure you're not the only
one who thinks that way.
The whole crew of Space Battleship Yamato must
share the same feelings.
Oomura-san, send the emigration
fleet ahead to Earth.
Nakanishi, relay my message
to Queen Ilya ofAmarl.
Yes, sir.
Humankind will never succumb
to tyranny and oppression.
Hereby, we declare war on
the InterstellarAlliance,
and in order to uphold justice, we are
ready to fight until the last man.
This might inconvenience
the Kingdom of Amarl.
However...
Captain Kodai.
We havejust arrived to
the same decision as you.
We have decided to fight the
InterstellarAlliance...
No, the SUS.
We declare our true independence,
and we will fight the
SUS until the last man.
Let's uphold justice together.
Attention all crew members,
the Yamato will abandon its mission
to escort the emigration fleet,
and engage the enemy fleet.
Our enemy is the dictatorship, the SUS, that governs
the West Star Systems, the Interstellar Alliance.
The Kingdom of Amarl has
declared its independence.
And in order for mankind to survive,
we have no other choice
butto defeatthe SUS.
This fight will decide
our and Amarl's future!
There are things we can only
protect by shedding blood.
Everyone, believe in what's
right and engage the enemy!
Thank you Captain Kodai,
Space Battleship Yamato.
Yamato, lift ofF!
Yamato, lift ofF.
l can't believe the InterstellarAlliance has experienced
such a bitter defeat!
This cannot happen!
Our enemy is the filthy Terrans!
This is the greatest humiliation
l've ever experienced!
ln the name of the Interstellar Alliance,
we will send the Yamato to Hell!
Captain, we've received a call
from the ship that's following us.
General Pascal!
Captain Kodai, please allow us
to take part in the battle.
You're back.
The Terran and Amarl
fleets are approaching.
Reinforcements from Fride and
Beldel have already arrived.
There's no reason to panic!
We will focus our attacks
on the stronghold.
All hands, prepare for battle.
Cosmo Pulser Squad, heavy
bombers, prepare fortake-o_.
Kobayashi, take charge o1
the Cosmo Pulser Squad.
Sakurai, take Kobayashi's station.
WhaEUR''
Understood.
l, Kobayashi, will sortie
with the Cosmo Pulser Squad!
Don't drop your guard, leader.
You too, Miharu.
Hury!
They're following us.
All right.
Miharu!
We're even now!
Just hide behind me
when things get tense.
l'll make you eat those words.
Sakurai!
Sakurai-san!
l'll take his place.
Gouda, you will direct the battlefield.
Understood.
l'm fine.
Allow me to continue.
Kamijou, take the command.
Got it.
Crap! It's not responding!
Why has the output dropped
at a moment like this?!
Come on, don't be so fickle!
Shou, let's run another systems check.
We're helpless ifwe get the order
to fire the wave-motion cannon!
Yeah.
lt has stabilized.
C-Chief!
Sou! Shou!
What did l teach you two?
Can't you even use a wrench properly?!
We'll break through the middle!
Aim for the stronghold!
Yes, sir!
Kobayashi, the Yamato will
break through the center.
Cover us.
Roger!
Maho, analyze that stronghold.
What's that gigantic energy flow?
l'm going to analyze it in the ECl.
Me_ler, when are you going to show me
the demise ofthose monkeys?
Vey soon.
Prepare the hyper neutron beam.
Commander, i1we fire now, we
will not only hit our own ships,
but the ships ofthe Alliance as well.
l don't care.
Shoot.
All ships, full speed
ahead! Protect the Yamato!
General Pascal...
Take care of the rest... Yamato...
Even though they are both part
of the Interstellar Alliance...
They wiped out their allies as well...
Relentless SUS bastards!
That's...
The otherAlliance fleets are withdrawing.
Looks like the death of General
Pascal has opened our path.
We cannot let General
Pascal's death be in vain.
We mustn't let this chance go, Captain.
Yes.
But evading that stronghold's
beam is almost impossible.
Damn Yamato... It's still intact.
They don't pose the slightest threatto us.
Should we fire all canons and
deliverthem to oblivion?
You're right.
Prepare all canons!
Prepare to fire all hyper neutron beams!
E-Emergency blow!
Emergency blow!
Dammit!
All fighters, pull back!
Hury!
Damn it! Don't screw with us!
Fire the batteries!
Fire bow torpedoes!
Missiles and main battery
fire are being reflected.
lt must have a strong magnetic field.
Kamijou, call Cosmo
Pulser Squadron back.
They mustn't get in that
gigantic canon's beam.
Yes, sir.
Captain, l've got the results
ofthe energy flow analysis.
l'm putting the results on-screen.
The energy flow wrapped
around the stronghold
forms an enormous magnetic lield that serves as
a defensive barrier.
The energy flow comes from the place where the
beam was launched.
We assume that the canon's
barrel also serves as a shield.
ln other words, as long as we
don't destroy that shield,
none ofthe Yamato's attacks will ever reach
the central command tower.
Captain, allow me to borrow the Shinano.
The Shinano?
The Shinano is equipped with
24 wave energy torpedoes.
l'm planning on using them
to destroy the shield.
But the missiles haven't been tested yet.
That's why the young ones
aren't cut out for this.
l'll test whether they work or not.
No, that's too dangerous!
l think they will be eflective
if l launch them at point blank.
There's no other way to
destroy that shield.
Oomura-san...
l'll be going, Captain Kodai.
Damn!
Eat this!
Oomura-san!
An unmarried man has nothing to lose!
Captain Kodai, can you hear me?
l can hearyou clearly, Oomura-san.
The three years l've spent with you...
That was the best voyage l
could have asked for...
Thank you for everything.
l'm counting on you, young ones.
You have to protect mankind!
l'm leaving it in your hands!
No matter what kind of
monster you're facing...
it always has a weakness or two!
Don't look down on Earth!
Don't underestimate Space
Battleship Yamato!
l'll make you feel this one!
Metzler!
The shield has...
Oomura-san...
We will destroy those five towers
before the enemy recovers!
Prepare the transition
wave-motion cannon!
Captain, are we going to fire all six rounds o1
the wave motion cannon?
No, leave one.
We will fire five beams and
crush those five towers.
Understood!
Energy level at 1200/o.
Understood.
Activating flywheel!
Kamijou, align the five beam
cannons with those five towers.
Do not miss!
Y-Yes, sir!
Kamijou-san, l'm sending you the
exact position of the beam gun.
Thanks, Maho.
Prepare the transition
wave-motion cannon.
Open the target scope!
Visual crosshair, brightness 20.
Everyone brace for shock.
Equip your anti-flash goggles.
lncreasing wave-motion
energy from 1000/o to 1200/o.
Kamijou, we're counting on you!
You can do it!
Yes, sir!
5...
_...
3...
2...
1...
Fire!
All beams have hit their targets!
Yay!
Enemy fire has stopped.
You did it!
You did it, Tactical OfFicer Kamijou!
Yahoo!
Yay!
We did it!
Thank the heavens.
Kobayashi, change stations with Sakurai.
lt's too dangerous for him
to continue with that wound.
Captain, check our 12!
What's that?
Fire all batteries!
Full speed ahead!
Roger!
Hard to port!
Full speed ahead!
That ''space submarine'' is amazing...
lt can manipulate dimensions and
wander through them freely.
Second auxiliary canon damaged!
Torpedo tubes damaged!
Anti-air turrets on starboard
are seriously damaged!
Full speed ahead!
Towards the sun!
The sun?
l don't have time to explain.
Just move!
O-Okay.
Understood.
Moving toward the sun!
lncrease the wave
engine's output to 1200/o!
Understood!
W-What?
Kamijou.
Aim the transition wave
cannon at the sun.
We discovered that it is linked
to the enemy's power supply.
That's an artificial astral
body camouflaged as a star!
The SUS's power source!
Understood!
Target: the sun.
Prepare to fire the wave-motion cannon.
Kamijou, shoot at the appropriate timing.
Yes, sir!
Open the target scope.
Equip your anti-flash goggles
and brace yourselves.
Firing the wave motion cannon!
No good?
Something is appearing on the screen.
Wait!
Human.
We are diflerent from you;
we are many but we are one.
We were merely sent to
maintain this universe,
and must seize this dimension.
Sent?
We'll give this world to you.
You may rule it.
We won't rule it.
We want to live together.
That's what this world means to us.
Human, l cannot understand your kind.
ls this nightmare over?
l don't know.
l still can't believe what l saw.
There's one thing we know for sure now.
What the SUS presented us
as the ''truth'' is a lie.
My dear citizens of Amarl.
We have made noble sacrifices.
And thanks to the eHorts
of Space Battleship Yamato,
we have finally won our independence.
This independence we have achieved
must be protected with honor forever.
lt's the Yamato!
The Yamato is returning to Earth!
Yamato...
We will arrive at the first long
warp point in five minutes.
All right!
We'll go straight to Earth!
Warp!
The emigration fleet has returned.
Good.
Once the fleet has landed,
begin maintenance.
We will depart in twelve hours.
Now we have to wait for the Yamato.
Warp finished.
We've caught up with the
Cascading Black Hole!
Transferring the processed visuals.
Height: circa 304,OOO km.
Width: circa 338,OOO km.
lt's several times biggerthan Jupiter.
l-ls that thing going to swallow the Earth?
lt's like the Devil's mouth.
Maho, what's its location?
At 14:05 the center will be
on a galactic latitude of 8
What's its velocity?
29,OOO kmrs.
lt'll hit the outer reaches of
the Solar System in three days.
The Earth will be
destroyed in three days!
Hurry up! We'll pe_orm the next warp!
Chief! Pluto has been swallowed!
lt swallowed Pluto, with a 2274
km diameter, just like that!
Processing the visuals.
Playing it in slow-motion.
What a monster!
How long does the Earth have?
Three more days.
Hurry up and get on the craft!
Hurry! We don't have any time!
Dr. Sado!
The rescue craft has arrived.
l'm staying here.
Me too.
Humans eventually die.
l've got so many memories here.
l'm fine with that.
Doctor...
But...
Miyuki-chan, if you disappeared as well,
yourfatherwould be all alone.
Kodai has been lighting because his beloved
ones are waiting for him.
All the lights and journeys
ofthe Yamato were like that.
l believe it was because there was
always someone waiting for him.
But...
What a pain!
Analyzer!
Roger!
Analyzer! Let go of me!
Please continue to live, Miyuki-san.
Analyzer!
Bye!
Space Battleship Yamato
has returned to Earth!
Thank you, Kodai.
l'm really sorry.
Sanada-san, we don't have any time.
Board the last remaining
people onto the Yamato.
Okay, l understand.
Chief, the last emigrant
vessel has departed.
Okay.
l hope they make it safely to Amarl.
What about you?
l will stay here.
Chief!
As a scientist, l want to witness the
Earth until its vey last moment.
Sanada-san said that?
l see.
Shima, are you done
housing all the people?
No.
The emergency craft that Sanada-san
arranged for the Field Park
still hasn't returned.
Field Park?
The one that Dr. Sado
and Miyuki-san boarded?
Yes...
What are you doing, Tactical O_icer?
They lost contact with the emergency craft
occupied by the captain's daughter.
What?
ln that case, l will go!
l won't allow individual decisions!
Captain!
Kobayashi, get back to your station!
You too, Kamijou!
Captain, aren't you going
to help your daughter?!
You still call yourself a father?!
Are you the captain of the Yamato?!
Didn't you hear me, Kobayashi?
Return to your post!
That is...
Captain Kodai!
So he planned to go by
himselffrom the start.
Damn!
l can't believe l said that!
He did that to stop us from going, too.
Where are you, Miyuki?
42 minutes left.
Miyuki! Miyuki!
F-Father...
Can you get out?
Father!
Miyuki, are you okay?
Yeah...
Take this, Miyuki.
This is...
Mom's...
Yes, your mother isn't in Heaven yet.
She's somewhere out there in space.
l will find her the next time for sure!
Come with me.
Okay.
Father...
Don't throw your life away.
l guess it's about time.
Kodai, when first l saw you,
l believe you were still 18,
we boarded the Yamato together,
and later you and Mori Yuki
gave birth to Miyuki-chan.
Take care of Miyuki-chan.
However...
l thought the animals would anticipate the danger,
and start running away or crying.
Mii-kun, you are like their exact opposite.
Come here.
Even if you're a little kitty,
are you still prepared lorthe
inevitability of destiny?
Thank you!
Farewell!
Thank you for everything, Earth!
Thank you!
Thanks for the wonde_ul memories!
l'll never forget you!
Farewell!
Thank you!
l'll never forget you!
Farewell!
Farewell, Earth!
Thank you so much!
Farewell!
Humankind is about to lose the
thing most precious to us.
We have come to realize this fartoo late.
Humans have always had the
worst attitude toward her.
We stole, destroyed,
wrecked, and rebuilt.
We thought we ruled over everything.
From the point of view ofthe immeasurable universe,
this is just another inconsequential event.
We can't even save the Earth.
We're so powerless.
Ultimately, we failed.
Moving to a new planet is
but a chance to start over.
What's this?
That's...
You're...
You were still alive?!
l've been waiting forthis.
The time has come for Earth to
become a part of our dimension.
What appears to be a black hole to you,
is a door leading to our dimension.
The immense energy torrent that
is created by the flux capacitor
is merely creating a little
interdimensional crack.
What lies on the other side ofthat crack
is a dimension that is beyond
anything you can fathom.
However, there aren't many planetary systems
or stars that can serve as resources there.
We had no other choice butto get provisions
from other dimensions in order to survive.
On top ofthat, in order to
survive, we have chosen your world.
All things in space are essential
resources for our dimension.
Humans, stars, organisms,
inorganic substances...
Evey single atom serves
to feed our dimension.
EaRh, you shall be
devoured by our dimension!
Every living being
will be reborn as our new energy supply.
Farewell, Kodai.
l see!
lt was man-made.
Then there's something that
operates the flux capacitor.
Maho, use the full capacity
of the computer room,
and find where that
interdimensional crack is!
Yes, sir.
Don't give up until the bitter end!
All hands, prepare for battle!
Understood!
The flux capacitor...
The crack in our dimension...
Where... Where is it?
That's it!
l've found the spot with the
highest energy emission.
Putting it on-screen.
lt's 300 km away from the gaseous entrance,
on the su_ace near the center.
So that's the black hole's true form?
All right!
Prepare the transition
wave-motion cannon!
Understood!
Engine room, prepare the
transition wave-motion cannon!
Captain, keep the influence of the gravity sphere
created by the crack in mind,
orthe wave-motion cannon's energy
will be stripped when we fire it.
We will fire once.
How about shooting all
six rounds at once?
Maho, calculate the feasibility.
Understood!
All six rounds at once?!
Otherwise we cannot
destroy that monster!
Captain, it's theoretically possible.
Just...
Just what?
Even ifwe manage to fire,
we don't know if the
Yamato can handle it.
The Yamato isn't the one
we need to protect!
lt's the Earth!
lf, by doing this, we
can protect the Earth,
no one will complain, Captain!
Chief!
What's wrong?
The whole firing system
is modifying itself!
The program was protected until now.
Because of the calculations
in the computer room,
the program has launched itself.
Putting it on-screen!
lt's Sanada-san!
So there were things about the
Yamato we didn't know yet.
As expected from Sanada-san.
But, he didn't implement it oflicially
as it's too risky and shouldn't
be used unless it's an emergency.
Let's do it, Captain.
First and second wave-motion
engine energy levels at 1200/o!
Preparing all rounds forfire.
Yamato, full speed ahead!
Captain, we have three
minutes and 20 seconds left!
Sou, Shou, get ready!
Y-Yes, sir!
We're ready anytime!
Kamijou!
Move, Kamijou!
l'll do it!
Captain!
Eveyone, cover your eyes!
l'm putting the fate of Earth and
the Solar System on the line.
Fire!
The infinite expanse ofthe universe...
A place filled with silence and light...
lfthere are stars that die,
then there are also stars that are born.
Yes...
The universe is alive.