A Co-production of
Shochiku & Haiyaza Films
SHOCHIKU FILMS, LTD
In the middle of the 18th century,
Japan was under the reign of Iyeharu,
The 10th Tokugawa Shogun,
It was known as the Tanuma era,
after a Shogunate minister,
Who created a world of politics
controlled by bribery and corruption,
The general corruption
and resulting lawlessness
Spawned fearful secret organizations,
Which thrived in the
shadowy underworld,
The people called such groups
"Hunters in Darkness",
HUNTER IN THE DARK
Executive Producers: Sato Masayuki,
Kishimonto Ginichi, sugisaki Shigemi
Based on the novel by:
IKENAMI Shotaro
Screenplay by: Kitazawa
Naota Endo Takeshi
Cinematography by: Sakai Tadashi
Music by: Sato Maseru
CAST
Nakadal Tatsuya
As Gomyo no Kiyoemon
Kishi Keiki as Omon
Ishida Ayumi as Oriwa
Fujita Makoto as Kasuke
Natsuyagi Isao as Sharaku no Matsu
Narrated by:
Hosokawa Toshiyuki
Tamba Tetsuro as Okitsugu Tanuma
Tono Eijiro as Shogen Hannyain
Harada Yoshio as Yataro Tanigawa
Chiba Shinichi as Samon Shimoguni
Directed by: Gosha Hideo
1784- Edo
Are you listening?
Get the first palanquin that comes.
Don't touch the second one.
Kill the man in the first palanquin.
You understand, right?
Who are you?
Why are you watching the lantern?
What's wrong?
RIVERSIDE TEAHOUSE KEMESEN
GOMYO'S DEN
Good morning.
- Good morning,
The red Camellias are lovely aren't they?
- Yes they are,
Please take these.
- Thank you,
Good morning.
- Good morning,
Take this to the inner room.
- OK,
Is that so?
Such a unique sword style.
I'm told you are an excellent swordsman.
Not at all. I'm just a novice.
Sorry Boss, but it's late.
I'm afraid I can't give you much.
You should have let me know.
Not at all. I was hungry.
The food was fine.
Right Tanigawa-san?
Yes, it was fine.
Her name is Omon.
She runs this teahouse.
Sometimes she carries our messages.
My name is Tanigawa Yataro.
I'm glad to meet you.
Tanigawa-san is going to work for me.
He's a friend of mine and
he is exceptionally reliable.
I have total confidence in him.
Please take care of him.
Arrange it so he can rest until evening.
Certainly, i'll do my best,
Tanigawa-san.
You understand, Tanigawa-san?
I trust you'll perform your
services well for me.
Still the same old picture.
How does the boss seem?
Seems he likes him.
Is that so?
Now that Tokuzo of
Shirogane was gotten rid of,
From now on it'll be either
our boss or Jihei of Shiba.
It'll be settled this evening.
I wish I could see how it's hand led.
Don't treat it lightly.
Tanigawa-san.
It's about time we got going.
Omon.
Are you sure it's all right?
We can't turn back.
That's right.
The die is cast.
But, just in case...
There's no way we can fail.
Jihei, of Shiba,
Never puts himself in jeopardy.
He'll tactfully lure out
our boss Gomyo.
and he'll be stabbed.
He'll never return alive.
But, that Ronin...
Can we really trust him?
That one?
He won't fail us, there's no doubt.
That Ronin ...
I saved his life.
Sorry to keep you waiting, Gomyo.
Welcome, Boss of Shiba.
I’ve      brought only
One aide, as agreed.
and also, I'm unarmed.
I trust you in that respect.
We're here to discuss who will be
the new boss of the underworld in Edo.
She is enough as my aide.
But what about you, Gomyo?
You're with a samurai.
You're Very careful.
Don't be difficult.
If we can settle it by a
Discussion, it'll be best.
You sound peaceful, but...
Last night at Omodaka bridge...
I hear Boss Tokuzo
was assassinated there.
What about it?
One of the three
biggest bosses was killed.
It makes it convenient for us.
Are you sure your weren't
behind the scenes on that?
Boss, I hope you haven't grown
stupid because of your mistress.
Whoever may have been behind it
It's one of our basic rules
not to make an issue of it.
You better educate her.
You're absolutely right.
Well then, let's come straight
to the main point.
Gomyo...
You're too good natured.
How did you ever get to be
an underworld boss?
Listen.
Yaichi, your underling who
arranged this meeting,
Fell in love with omon
and betrayed you to us.
What do you think about that?
Well, Boss Gomyo?
Shut up!
Hurry and kill me!
Well said!
According to your wish, we'll kill you.
Kill him.
You...
Damn it!
REVOLVING LANTERN SHOP
GOMYO'S DEN
Welcome back.
What are you doing?
This is absolutely unforgivable.
Are you making a fool of me
Just because the boss isn't here?
Sakimatsu. What's all this about?
explain all this.
What are you all up to?
- Will you be quiet for a while?
Yaichi.
- What is it?
You said the boss isn't here.
Where is he and what's he doing?
Will you tell us?
Will I tell you?
What's wrong?
Very well.
I will tell you the story.
The boss, he isn't alive anymore.
What's worse...
Jihei's men will be here soon
to  shut you all up permanently.
So that's how it'll be.
Then are you the one
who betrayed our boss to Jihei?
We'll talk about it later.
If your want to live, join me.
You better hurry, or...
- What if I say I want to live, too?
Boss!
According to the
rules of the underworld
We must stab the betrayer
with a dagger until he is dead.
What about her?
I never thought you'd betray me.
I don't care.
Kill me if you like.
It's my fault.
If you kill me.
I'll have no regrets.
You left me for that woman
who tried to commit suicide.
I felt like I was thrown
into the depths of hell.
Boss...
Let's observe the rule.
That picture again?
Sometimes you can be so childish.
Always the same picture.
But we are going there one day,
aren't we?
We'll go there together, won't we?
Yes, someday.
If you want to go that badly.
It's strange.
As you so often asked me to go,
I began to feel as though
I'd been there too.
Boss...
Kill me at once!
Please kill me!
Boss!
You chose to live in the underworld.
No one forced you.
So don't complain now.
I fell for a woman I shouldn't love.
I'm to blame. It's my fate.
I’ve      no grudge against the boss.
I’ve nothing personal against him.
So as the rule says, kill me!
I wish I could ask
him to forgive you.
But you tried to kill him,
and that's unforgivable.
Omon...
Boss...
What's wrong?
You look so stern.
I was lonely.
Yesterday... Today...
So very lonely.
Don't say that.
Don't say you're lonely.
I love you. Boss.
I'm floating.
My body is floating.
Is this where I'm to die?
Omon.
It's our rule to kill woman
without bloodshed.
Because of that, you'll drown.
- Wait a minute!
We'Ve been friends a
long time haven't we?
Let me at least prepare myself.
Omon.
What are you doing?
Stop it!
I'm the infamous Madame of Kamesen
and I'm going to die.
I want to be neat when I die.
Don't underestimate me.
I'm different from Yaichi.
You misunderstand .
You're very suspicious, aren't you?
Look. Now I have no
weapons whatsoever.
Now, search me.
Don't do it.
Omon, you mustn't.
You want me, don't you?
You can hold me if you like.
I'm going to die soon anyway.
What are you doing?!
PUBLIC BATH
GOMYO'S DEN
Will you hurry?
Please hurry, will you?
We're closing for the day.
Welcome Inspector Chosuke.
I'm going to soak in
The bath for some time.
I'm sorry.
We are closing early today.
Please forgive me.
He likes the water hot, understand ?
Inspector...
I'm with the police,
yet you dare to say no to me?
No, sir. Sorry, sir.
"offerings of money work so well. "
I see.
"The children of officials soon
learn how to tickle people's palms. "
Good, excellent wording!
Nowadays, officials won't do a thing
unless they're bribed.
Is that what this means?
Good wording.
It couldn't be better.
I really mean it.
You're making fool of me!
That I won't forgive!
Out of my way!
Why you...!
- Wait, inspector.
- What?
- He's upstairs.
What? Upstairs?
Boss Gomyo's upstairs?
A comic song goes...
"Tanuma is absolutely beyond me"
"But a Shogun, at least,
I wish I could be,"
Minister Tanuma's political power
exceeded even that of the Shogun,
The mansion of Tanuma,
The Prime Minister,
was always filled with visitors,
who brought him bribes,
It appears you deeply regret
having missed being assigned
to  oversee the Ezo district.
That is correct, Sire.
The Kitamae Clan has been abolished.
The procedures are over.
Therefore, I believe you
no longer need me.
I know that.
Don't try to be sarcastic.
I already assigned that position
to  Kazue Ishikawa because
I heard there was a plot
to revive the Kitamae clan.
I know, Sire.
I hardly think those
country samurai can do much.
But if they ever get
a wind of what we're doing
not only you, buy I as well,
Will be in trouble.
I don't think you have
much to worry about.
Still, it's wise to be cautious.
It's because I'm always
careful in whatever I do,
That I’ve enjoyed political might
for more than ten full years.
Until the rioting Kitamae Clan
Ronin are liquidated,
I order you to continue overseeing
the city of Edo from the shadows.
When all threats are removed,
I shall then appoint
you to govern Ezo.
Seems he is concerned about us.
Because the boss ordered
him to take care of me.
Don't you mind me staying here?
The boss wouldn't object.
You really don't remember your past?
Nothing at all?
not a thing.
It's better that you don't remember.
Why?
I'm scared about
you recalling your past.
Even if I could remember,
I'd never change.
Then...
Then you...
What?
If you stay with the boss too long
Something terrible will surely
happen one day.
So, we still have
Seven more remaining.
They are trying to
act against Lord Tanuma.
They're good swordsmen.
They're very smart, too.
Please don't say any more.
We never ask our clients
Why we must kill.
That's one of the rules
of the underworld.
No matter what
other bosses might do.
I took the liberty of
having you checked out.
Shimoguni-sama,
You were the chamberlain
of the Kitamae Clan of Ezo,
Which was abolished
a few years ago.
You pulled the strings
behind it's abolishment.
Since then,
you've worked for Tanuma.
You're asking me to get rid
of those Kitamae Ronin
Who are plotting to revive the clan.
Right?
Then, let me ask this:
What do you think of Kakizaki,
the one who's their leader?
I know he's all talk and no action.
All he has is his name and
his lineage. He's incompetent.
and I'm a traitor.
I arranged it so my
own clan would be abolished.
But Gomyo...
I was able to stand back and
watch my own clan being destroyed.
Because I felt it was already
caught up in the current of the times.
No one could stop it.
when I saw no future for the clan,
I decided to aband on it.
Instead, I had a beautiful dream
About the vast land of Ezo.
Ezo?
That's right, Ezo.
I want to develop the land of Ezo
with   my very own hand s.
That vast land ...
Countless wild horses...
Enormous amounts of fish...
Many lakes with wild birds...
It's not just a dream.
not just a dream.
When my present job is over
I'll become governor of Ezo.
But...
Why must you always
stay in the shadows?
Why is it you don't come
out into the daylight?
You, a commoner, and I, a samurai
can make big plans for Ezo together.
It can be anot her way of life.
I mentioned this so abruptly.
We have a long way to go.
We have time to think.
It's been such a long time.
You're always working hard.
You're sexy.
That's terrific!
This is bad.
They're almost burning.
They're cooked too much,
but bear with me.
What's wrong?
Don't worry about the police anymore.
How's this?
Don't be so sulky.
I'm the reason that you're safe.
Besides...
Your body already belongs to me.
I have good reason, huh?
I'll never get a woman like you again.
I'll never let you go.
Absolutely not .
Do as you wish.
It's like...
It's like I'm already dead.
Stop it!
Forget about the
organization and the boss.
I'll make you forget.
Do it this evening.
This is from the boss.
It's your advance.
Who am I to kill?
All the ones we're after.
It'll be a close game.
I mean, it'll be
a life-or-death match.
I can easily hand le two or three.
But not six or seven.
Then...
Sukegoro-san, will you help
with   the preparations?
Of course.
and will you do me anot her favour?
If I fail to return,
Will you give the money to Osaki?
Yes. I'll do as you request.
Thank you.
We aren't well informed about Edo.
If we stay like this,
we'll all be killed before long.
That's the point.
We overlooked a prime new hideout.
Lord Kitamae's family temple...
Hannyain Temple.
It's in Asakusa.
It's practically in ruins.
But it'll make a good hideout.
Rather than finding a hideout,
Why don't we plan a counterattack?
- Don't underestimate them.
They're very strong.
Then, what kind of plan do you have?
Plan? Plan to do what?
To  revive the Kitamae Clan.
- There's no possibility of that.
No possibility?
Sire! Why isn't there?
Listen. We don't even know
where the young successor is.
- Then what have
we been working for?
In order to approach Lord Tanuma,
so that he'll allow us to revive the Clan.
Is that understood?
Plots always fail in
some small way or anot her.
In our case
They left the little lord alive.
Why are you grinning?
You'll get to sleep with the
woman you love this evening.
I envy you.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
You're pretty clever, huh?
Welcome.
Give me saké.
Here you are.
Isn't she waiting for you?
It's cold out.
I want one more hot saké.
Heizaburo!
Sasao Heizaburo!
Damn you!
Heizaburo! I'm Sugioka, your friend!
Omon.
Well? Want some, too?
Help yourself.
I think...
I still have a chance.
Something good
will happen to me soon.
I can't stay in dire poverty forever.
Look...
If we get some money,
Let's move to osaka.
Let's get a fresh start there.
How's that?
Try to understand how I feel.
Don't betray me.
If you betray me...
Boss...
That man...
I hope your not in love with him.
No way.
Recently...
You've become very sexy,
haven't you?
Yes. He may have pleased you.
But don't fall for him.
You know what, huh?
Jihei sent you here
to  spy on Gomyo and his men.
It's starting to work now.
Yet...
Oren, please trust me.
I'll lure him out
as soon as there's news.
That's good.
Then Jihei, who was killed by him,
will be able to rest in peace.
I'll get revenge on him,
Even after i've turned to ashes.
As long as you remember the
rules of the underworld,
It'll be all right.
Won't it, osaki?
You're all right?
Thank goodness.
Undo my sash.
Yes.
You'll get dirty.
Put it on the counter.
I'll get rid of it later.
Yes.
For Osaki from Tanigawa-san.
Osaki.
Kill him! Kill him now!
Yataro-san!
Get him! Kill him!
Osaki!
You bitch!
Damn it!
Tanigawa-san,
get a hold of yourself.
Now, Tanigawa-san!
Hang in there!
REVOLVING LANTERN SHOP
GOMYO'S DEN
He needs a doctor.
What do you suggest?
The boss is out. What'll we do?
Tanigawa-san...
You all right? Get a doctor.
No! I don't need a doctor.
It'll cause the boss trouble.
Tanigawa-san!
- Tanigawa-san!
- I'll take care of him.
Sorry for the inconvenience.
Are you all right?
You have other matters
that need taking care of.
Yeah, we have to cover it up.
Sadahachi.
- Yes,
Then, will you please see to this?
Be careful.
Sorry...
Who are you?
I haven't introduced myself.
My name is Tanigawa Yataro.
Tanigawa-san?
Thanks a lot.
You saved him.
Not at all.
How's your wound?
I wasn't careful enough.
I'm sorry.
I'm the one to apologize.
Try to get well first.
Hey, Oriwa...
Yes!
Some cotton cloth...
I'll do it.
No. Never mind.
Sir, it's been a long time.
I used to work for you.
I have something to tell you.
Your name is Kasuke. Is that right?
Yes. It's been a while.
So, what is it you want to tell me?
Do you know a samurai
named Sasao Heizaburo?
Sasao Heizaburo?
He tried to kill you
But killed his father by mistake.
There was a massacre
at Esashiya Inn last night.
He did it. and also...
More and more Kitamae Ronin
are being assassinated.
Do you know why?
Well...
I have two keys
to  help solve the mystery.
Keys?
One: A woman who bears
a grudge against Gomyo.
I know about it, because I
happen to live with her.
Are you boasting about her?
Anyway, the other is...
The fact that I was
the only other person there
When Heizaburo killed his father.
Heizaburo!
It's you!
Asakusa...
Hannyain Temple...
What his father said at that time
Is worth a hundred pieces of gold.
We'll talk about it some other time.
How about it?
Will you come to my house?
- No thanks.
It can be very dangerous.
Let's contact one anot her like this:
Kamesen, a teahouse by the river...
We'll attach letters
to  a willow tree there.
Teahouse by the river?
Yes. It's deserted.
Nobody goes near the place.
Called Kamesen?
Yes. Goodbye.
Satisfied now?
The tattooed one.
I’ve      been waiting for a man like you.
This is all.
It's everything I have.
You're worth a hundred gold coins.
Think so?
I know where he is.
Kill Gomyo when he slithers out.
Don't fail.
Rest assured.
Oriwa.
Thanks for your help.
I read the books you lent me.
And...?
What?
They included a travel diary.
This one.
Yes.
What about it?
Tanigawa-sama.
Tanigawa-sama...
Are you sure you don't remember
anything at all about your past?
Nothing.
But it's strange.
I can read.
This picture. Doesn't it help?
Doesn't it remind you of anything?
This sound.
This tinkle.
Doesn't it help?
Oriwa-san.
Ezo.
Kitamae Clan.
Don't these words help?
Who are you?
You know something, don't you?
Oriwa-san.
Heizaburo-sama!
You do know something, don't you?
Oriwa-san.
Heizaburo-sama.
You're Sasao Heizaburo.
I don't know.
I don't know!
I'm sorry.
Tell me.
Who are you?
Hannyain Temple in Asakusa.
Hannyain Temple in Asakusa!
Go there.
If you go there
You will know the whole story.
The man called Tanigawa Yataro...
I've got to get rid of him at any cost.
Why don't you call him Sasao Heizaburo.
He was a Kitamae samurai.
Just before his clan was abolished
He and his wife were attacked.
They're both missing now.
They were attacked by your men.
You don't have to explain any more.
That's one of the rules
of the underground.
But, in any case...
Gomyo.
It's useless to
try to hide anything now.
It happened two years ago.
The Kitamae was abolished.
The only way to save the clan was
Through little Lord Kanemaru.
Kanemaru's guardian,
Sasao zenzaemon,
Tried to stop the
abolishment by using him.
He came to ask me to
appeal to Lord Tanuma.
Our Lord went insane
and killed himself.
We may well be punished.
But abolishing our clan is too much.
We must prevent it at all cost.
Little Lord Kanemaru should
succeed as head of the clan.
Will you appeal
to  Lord Tanuma for us?
Fortunately, you're a good
friend of Lord Tanuma.
Please help us.
I dissuaded him.
He finally gave up and went home.
On his way,
The crest on his lantern caused him
to  be mistaken for me.
He was assassinated.
and the assassin
was Heizaburo, his own son.
He is now Tanigawa Yataro.
He killed his own father?
Strange fate!
with   zenzaemon dead
There was no way left
to  save the Kitamae Clan.
Whatever he said to Heizaburo
with   his dying breath...
We must know what it was...
and deal with it.
Or my dream may be ruined.
Gomyo, my dream about Ezo.
Why not join in?
Why not make up your mind?
What do you think, Gomyo?
Lotus blossoms sometimes
grow even in the mud.
But it has no meaning to me now.
Gomyo.
I can't answer right now.
What?
Our work involves gratitude.
It embodies both
gratitude and a sense of duty.
It consists of something
that money alone cannot satisfy.
Are you saying you need time?
Is that it?
Anot her thing...
What is it, Boss?
She tried to kill herself.
Why did she do that?
Don't worry about it.
Get a doctor.
Will you wait awhile?
I cannot wait too long.
I'll give you until midnight.
Very well.
Midnight tonight.
Exactly.
The place: Here.
Gomyo.
Bring Sasao Heizaburo
here by midnight.
Understand ?
If... You break your promise...
I suppose you know what'll happen.
Don't worry about it.
No one in the organization
Ever has regrets if
anything happens to him.
Will you excuse me, then?
Remember your promise.
Remember.
Midnight.
Midnight, Gomyo.
He hasn't recovered
enough to go out by himself.
Any ideas about where he is?
He said "Family Temple".
Tanigawa-san was trying
to  visit it, right?
So that's it.
Hannyain Temple in Asakusa.
Boss...
That's it.
He must have gone there.
You still look like you did
when you were a child.
Your eyes, your mouth.
They remind me of how
you were 20 years ago.
You are the son of
Sasao zenzaemon, Heizaburo.
I'm certain you are
Sasao Heizaburo, a Kitamae samurai.
Sadahachi. Will you take
Oriwa to Kamesen?
Oriwa.
No.
I'd hate to part with you. No!
Listen oriwa.
There are things I must do.
I'll go as soon as I finish.
You go first and wait.
No. I don't want to.
- Don't complain!
- No! No! No!
Oriwa!
No!
Boss... That's too much!
- Shut up!
Don't interfere!
Oriwa.
I'll take care of you.
Just be quiet and
do as I say until then.
Got it?
Alright.
Now hurry!
Go.
What are you waiting for?!
Boss!
Boss...
Listen, all of you.
Listen to what I'm about to tell you.
Boss...
Why so formal?
As of now
I'm quitting the organization.
- What? What do you mean?
What's this all about?
I have no time to explain.
I'm tired of this kind of life.
I've had enough.
Listen. I'll tell you
one thing before I leave.
Tonight at midnight.
When the bell tolls midnight.
The police will attack this place.
Get your things together and run.
Get out and go where you like!
If you stay here,
You won't live to see tomorrow!
- That can't be!
The money you earned
and saved is in the back room.
Distribute it as your wish.
Boss! Wait a minute!
- Boss...
- Shut up!
I'm not your boss anymore.
No gratitude, no duty.
Forget about it
and think for yourselves!
Understand ?
Your father...
Before he left for Edo,
He entrusted me with
This letter case.
He said to give it to you in case
he didn't make it out alive.
It contains the charter
Signed by Tokugawa Iyeyasu,
founder of the Shogunate.
Giving Ezo to the Kitamae Clan.
The government cannot ignore it.
I firmly believe it.
Also, it can tell you where
The little lord is. Your father hid him.
So, your father entrusted
me to give this to you.
Priest.
What are you saying?
What is it all to me?
Your father died trying to
save his clan and his retainers.
Observe your father's will.
That's what you must do.
Why must I be the one to do it?
Man cannot aband on
his past as long as he lives.
Listen carefully, Heizaburo.
Running away will ruin you.
Stake your life on
reviving the Kitamae Clan.
I don't know.
Look, Heizaburo.
The fate of the
Kitamae Clan is at stake.
I don't know.
Heizaburo!
That sort of thing
has no meaning to me now.
Who are you?
We overheard the best news around.
Sasao Heizaburo!
We'll kill you
and take the letter case!
You're acting only
in your own interest.
Get out!
Heizaburo!
Take this letter case!
Heizaburo! Heizaburo!
The letter case! The letter case!
Heizaburo!
Hagino!
Tanigawa-san!
Tanigawa-san.
get a hold of yourself.
Tanigawa. It's me.
You're all right now.
You can relax.
Tanigawa-san!
Boss...
What happened?
The past... I remember...
Really?
You can remember your past?
I can remember.
Is that so.
That's good. I'm glad.
No! No!
I want to stay as I am.
I'd rather stay as I am.
Tanigawa-san!
Tanigawa-san! Tanigawa-san!
Get a hold of yourself,
Tanigawa-san!
Boss!
Boss, we're here to help you.
Why are you here?
We're determined to die with you.
Fools!
Boss...
Take Tanigawa-san to
Kamesen's warehouse.
OK. Got it.
Tanigawa-san. Don't die! Stay alive!
Boss.
We got Tanigawa-san
safely aboard a boat.
Is that so?
Boss, let's hurry to Kamesen.
Oriwa is waiting there.
No.
But...
Never mind. It's all right.
Leave the two alone.
That's what's best.
Boss.
Where are you going?
I have something to do at midnight.
At midnight?
I'll meet Shimoguni at the
Somezen Dyeing Shop at twelve.
Somezen?
Everybody has
already gathered there.
Everybody? What for?
Until you've gotten safely away.
We're supposed
to  hold off the police.
Everybody's gathered?
Stupid! Don't do that!
Who are you?
I'm in the same business as you.
I'm Matsu, the tattooed one.
This is a good place for you to die.
I'm here to kill you.
Idiot!
Don't take us lightly.
Gomyo.
Die, you damn officers!
Damn you!
Get out of here!
Gomyo.
If you think you've won
You've got anot her thing coming.
The Ronin you're protecting...
What?
Oren is already after him.
She must have killed him by now.
They must be here!
Look everywhere for them!
Kamesen,
Isn't there any good news yet?
Omon! Omon!
We Iucked out.
He's coming on his own
like a moth to the fire.
Omon, you wait here.
We've arrived, Tanigawa-san.
Don't worry about the boss.
He'll surely come later.
Omon! Omon!
Omon!
Damn it!
Omon, you saw that boat, too?
The one with the Ronin aboard.
It disappeared right
in front of my eyes.
Omon, you must know.
Is there a good place to hide a boat?
A secret inlet or something.
There must be a
cave leading to the river.
You know, don't you?
Maybe...
That Ronin can earn me money.
Gomyo will be coming here.
Then Shimoguni-san
and the police will rush in.
Shimoguni will win in the end.
It's a good chance to make money.
Omon, will you tell me?
The basement of that
warehouse leads to the river.
That one?
That's perfect.
Omon, hurry and give me the key.
Forgive me.
Please forgive me.
After all i've done!
I don't want to die!
As soon as I find the boss,
I'll bring him here.
Sukegoro-san.
Good Iuck.
I've finally paid...
My debt.
Heizaburo-sama! Heizaburo-sama!
Darling.
I'm sorry... I'm sorry, Oriwa-dono.
No. My name is...
Hagino. I'm your wife...
- Don't say any more!
You mustn't.
Please listen to me.
Go with the boss.
Stay alive with the boss.
Are you Shimoguni-sama?
I implore you.
Please forgive the boss.
The boss?
Instead, i'll tell you where to find
the Ronin you're looking for.
Run!
Hurry! Run!
Hurry!
You're Sasao Heizaburo's wife,
Hagino, right?
The two of you,
Return to Ezo together.
Go.
Gomyo.
Is that...
The charter that decides
The fate of the Kitamae Clan?
Your dream...
and my way of
Life in the darkness...
They're both staked on it.
Very well, Gomyo.
I'll obtain my dream...
.. with my own hands.
THE END