Karin!
I found Yuuji.
Hey,
why does he only draw pictures of garbage?
He knows how it feels to be abandoned.
Abandoned?
Yuuji was put into my orphanage by his mom when his dad died.
She made a promise before leaving.
That she'll come for him when she has enough money.
He's still waiting for her, believing that promise.
Then, eventually...
There's no way she'll come back.
What?
Yuuji was abandoned, just like me.
Karin! My head aches!
I always tell you, don't concentrate too hard.
Let's go home.
Okay.
Bye, Satoshi.
Bye-bye.
Yuuji...
You really came.
He works in the same art supplies shop as me.
He fell from his motorcycle on the way home.
This is...
Yuuji found your shop's article by chance.
Momoka!
Look, look, look at this!
Here.
"Trash" is the name of our dog.
He was looking forward to surprising you with his own art exhibition.
Then, why didn't he send that postcard?
His exhibition was cancelled.
Cancelled?
It was Yuuji's mother who brought the idea of an art exhibition.
His mother?
He met his mother?
His mother said she was going out with a famous art dealer for some art gallery.
He liked Yuuji's drawings,
so they were going to open an art exhibition and sell his drawings.
Yes, I deposited the money this morning.
Thank you.
Oh, and...
please take a good care of my mother.
He became ecstatic,
and even borrowed money to make it happen.
But...
[ This number is no longer being used. ]
[ Please call again with the right number. ]
The whole deal was a lie.
They defrauded his money.
They betrayed you!
It's a fraud!
Let's report to the police!
It doesn't matter for me.
As long as that money helps my mom and her boyfriend...
It's fine by me.
This is the sketchbook he always carried around.
He always drew that picture when he hit a dead end.
"I have at least two true friends who believed I can become an artist,"
he said.
Yuuji...
Hey, let's go.
Back then...
...the three of us were here all the time.
But...
sometimes, I think...
Maybe everything happened in this town was a dream.
It's not a dream.
Because Yuuji waited for us in this very town.
You're moving?
My mom is being transferred to a hospital far away.
You'll be going to another school?
Yes.
But I'm sure we'll meet again.
The three of us will always be together.
It's a promise.
- Promise.
Satoshi.
We're friends, no matter how far apart we are.
Karin! Satoshi is leaving!
Yuuji, I'm counting on you to look after Karin.
Good bye.
Satoshi!
Karin!
Karin, let's go.
I'll stay by Yuuji's side.
I'll stay here.
To be honest, I...
I don't think I'll ever come back.
I'm glad I got to see you.
Take care.
Good bye.
Karin...
Karin!
Aren't you worried?
Yuuji has Karin with him.
I'm talking about Karin.
I wonder why she visited you all of a sudden?
Because...
She came to my bakery a few days ago.
"Look after Satoshi for me,"
she asked me.
She loves you.
What am I saying?
Misaki...
I can forgive you for being oblivious to women.
But you can't be oblivious to your own feelings.
I'm sure Satoshi loves you.
Really?
It would make me really happy...
...if you married into this family someday.
Let's beat our illnesses together, Karin.
Yes.
Mom...
Is that the medicine Karin was taking?
Dad.
These are just sleeping pills.
No,
it's a medicine that prevents sleep.
Karin doesn't have much time left.
She was sick.
Sick?
An illness where she can't wake up once fallen into deep sleep.
She had only been allowed momentary sleep ever since she was little.
Even the most powerful medicine is no longer working for her.
What happens if she falls into deep sleep?
She'll slip into coma,
and eventually...
...die.
She said she's scared of dying,
that she can't stay here any longer.
She asked me not to tell you,
and cried.
But I thought you should know.
Dad...
Karin came to see you one last time.
Satoshi.
Trash!
Trash died...
It didn't die.
Look, it's just sleeping.
It died.
It didn't die!
Trash died.
It didn't die.
It didn't die!
Karin!
Karin, wake up.
Wake up!
Satoshi.
Why are you here?
You won't die, right?
You're just sleeping, right?
I'm sorry.
I couldn't tell you.
I couldn't tell you either...
...that I loved you.
I loved you since I was little.
Satoshi...
Good bye.
I'll be waiting.
I'll wait forever, until you wake up.
Satoshi...
I'll be waiting forever.
Karin?
Karin!
Twinkle, twinkle, little star.
How I wonder what you are.
Yuuji...
I've heard of it when I was little.
An illness where you can't wake up once you fall asleep.
Once captured by the dream,
they die in bed without ever waking up.
I met Karin in my dream.
She told me to hurry and go back.
I said let's go back together,
but she shook her head and said it was impossible.
I think it was just a dream.
But...
I want to believe she saved me.
She might be upset if I showed this to you, but...
[ Dear Yuuji. ]
[ I'm praying you would wake up and read this. ]
[ Actually, ]
[ I met Satoshi. ]
[ Reunion after 13 years. ]
[ Yuuji, do you remember? ]
I'm Tooyama Satoshi, I moved here a week ago!
[ About the first time we met Satoshi. ]
Also, he's "Trash".
Nice to meet you, Trash.
[ I think I fell in love with Satoshi ever since that day. ]
Then, model for the artist,
and mascot girl for the aqua plants shop.
It's a promise.
Promise.
[ Satoshi gave me the hope to live. ]
Geez, what the hell?
Great,
one more! Ready?
[ Even for someone like me, ]
[ just maybe, ]
[ a happy future was waiting for me when I grew up. ]
[ I wanted to be by Satoshi's side forever. ]
Bye.
[ Satoshi was... ]
Satoshi!
[ ...my first love. ]
[ That's why, on the day Satoshi left, ]
[ to make up for not being able to tell him I love him, ]
[ I kissed for the first time in my life. ]
[ I've lived my entire life, ]
[ with that fond memory as an encouragement. ]
[ Even if we're far, far apart... ]
[ I'm sure we'll continue to shine forever. ]
[ Believing we'll meet again.
Somewhere, someday. ]
[ But... I couldn't escape from my illness. ]
[ That's when... ]
[ I thought maybe God gave me one last chance. ]
Satoshi!
[ Only a limited time left for me, ]
[ I had to see you, no matter what. ]
[ I wanted to tell you what I couldn't for the longest time. ]
Aqua plants shop, "Trash".
[ Satoshi, ]
[ it surprised me how you didn't change at all. ]
Have some coffee if you like.
Ow, hot!
[ Clumsy, and... ]
Why don't you notice?!
[ Oblivious... ]
Honestly, I can barely stay in the business, but...
it's a promise I made as a child.
[ But you were still a pure and... ]
That's Microsorium Narrow Leaf.
[ A kind person. ]
[ You were still the same Satoshi I loved. ]
Thank you.
[ That's why... ]
[ ...I couldn't tell you again. ]
[ Because I wasn't in your future. ]
I found it!
[ The truth is... I wanted to be by Satoshi's side forever. ]
[ I wanted to at least tell him, "I love you." ]
[ But... ]
[ This is my fate. ]
[ But you know, ]
[ I'm glad, ]
[ I met you two again one last time. ]
[ I pray that Satoshi and Yuuji will be... ]
[ ...happy, forever and ever. ]
[ That's why, ]
[ if... ]
[ you wake up and see Satoshi, ]
[ When you see him... ]
[ When you see him, ]
[ Say hello for me. ]
Satoshi...
Is it fate,
this mystifying reunion of us three?
You three were bonded by a strong force.
There's a powerful force in this world,
that can't be explained by physics.
It doesn't weaken no matter how much time and space separated you.
That's why you were able to reunite like this even after more than 10 years.
[ Hey, Karin. ]
[ We were connected by an invisible force. ]
[ Ever since that place, 13 years ago. ]
( Trash )
I've decided the name of my shop.
When I become the owner of an aqua plants shop,
I'll name it "Trash".
You're the mascot girl for Trash.
Hey, Karin. Do you remember?
The seeds of water lily.
It may take more than 50 years to sprout up.
But it will definitely sprout one day.
It will wake up.
[ I don't care if you stay asleep. ]
[ I'll keep talking to you. ]
How long will you be staying in Paris?
I want to train myself until I'm satisfied.
I see.
Chocolate danish.
My last and greatest masterpiece.
Thank you.
Satoshi.
Waiting is not easy, is it?
But...
I think it's wonderful that you're accepting your own feelings now.
Misaki...
I'll write you.
Good luck.
You too.
Hey, Karin.
Yuuji and Momoka has a baby now.
I'm sure it's a cute baby.
( And so, Nello and Patrasche woke up,
and lived happily ever after. )
Thank you so much for everything.
[ Natsume finally became a certified accountant. ]
[ I'm stumped! ]
[ Now I have to place orders and do the packaging all by myself. ]
[ Delivery too. ]
Hey,
Karin.
His eyes look exactly like Yuuji's!
Her name is Haruka.
Oh, I see.
I wish Karin can see her.
[ Hey, Karin. ]
[ I can wait for you, right? ]
[ You'll wake up again someday, right? ]
[ I can believe in you, right? ]
[ Hey, ]
[ Karin? ]
Thank you very much.
Can you switch these two?
Thank you.
Hey, Satoshi.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
My dad wanted to come too, but...
He's still not feeling well?
Yes.
At last.
It took 5 years though.
A lot of things happened on the way,
but I think they were all meaningful.
I drew it for Karin.
By the time I realized how I felt about her,
she was already in love with you.
I think maybe...
Karin was hoping you would wait for her.
I was dreaming.
A dream of when you were born.
It was a difficult delivery.
Your mom and I,
we were in tears from happiness.
It's was the first time in my life...
...I felt so warm inside.
I'm sorry.
What is it?
I should've...
...started a family,
so you wouldn't worry about me.
You should live the way you want to.
That's how I intended to raise you.
You two,
...are connected through a powerful force.
Your mother and I...
...are connected to you with the same force.
Dad?
Twinkle, twinkle, little star.
How I wonder what you are.
I want to become Satoshi's little bride.
Aqua plants shop, "Trash".
Is this your shop?
Are you the owner?
Yes, I am.
I met your father...
...in my dream.
Satoshi is waiting,
so go back for him, he said.
He told me how to get back.
When I was about to leave, your father said...
...he was happy,
and that he loved you.
"Karin, I'm sure you will see Satoshi again."
"When you see him...
...Say hello for me," he said.
Welcome back, Karin.
I'm back.
Translated by: 8thSin
For past fansubs and updates,
http://fansub.d-addicts.com/User:8thSin
Theme song: Shibasaki Kou - Prism
[Nagasawa Masami as Karin]
*
Swaying inside the water tank
[Yamada Takayuki as Satoshi]
*
Gazing into the aqua plants, vivid colors
[Tsukamoto Takashi as Yuuji]
*
Chasing your eyes, flashing in front of me
[Kitagawa Keiko as Momoka]
*
Caring for my body,
[Kikawada Masaya as Natsume]
*
Limited time left for me,
[Kuninaka Ryouko as Misaki]
*
Will you understand my feeling
[Wakui Emi as Satoshi's mother]
*
Of wanting a little more time?
[Kohinata Fumiyo as Satoshi's father]
*
I thought when our fingers cross and separate,
[Music: Matsutani Suguru]
*
That's the very end of us.
[Assistant director: Shiozaki Jun]
*
Your hands, which stopped me, arms that embraced me,
[Based on novel by: Ichikawa Takuji]
*
Still burns into my heart, I can't forget about you
As I wake up, still sleepless
I hear the crying of a baby for his mother
I used to desire the same way in the past.
Do I hate the person who gave birth to me into this world?
Who created this world?
Don't hate anyone,
Just laugh it off,
Even when something really sad happens
You can pile it up as a sweet memory
You'll know what I mean soon, I'm sure
[Also check out "Heavenly Forest"
and "Be with You",
based on novels by the same author]
It's all right, I'm right here, staring at you
You sleeping, me crying
"Don't give up, we still have a future together"
As long as I embrace your words, like a prayer
Shining three primary colors, prism of rainbow
Love that grows within you
When the water lily sprouts from the seed,
I want to welcome you with open arms,
embrace you with everything I've got
Directed by: Hirakawa Yuuichirou
"Sono Toki wa Kare ni Yoroshiku"
When You See Him, Say Hello for Me