Twinkle, twinkle, little star.
How I wonder...
Translated by: 8thSin
For past fansubs and updates,
http://fansub.d-addicts.com/User:8thSin
I've heard of it when I was little.
An illness where you can't wake up once you fall asleep.
Once captured by the dream,
they die in bed without ever waking up.
I met Karin in my dream.
She told me to hurry and go back.
I said let's go back together,
but Karin shook her head and said it was impossible.
I think it was just a dream.
But...
I want to believe she saved me.
[ Hey, Karin. ]
[ We were connected by an invisible force. ]
[ Ever since that place, 13 years ago. ]
Hey, let's go.
"Sono Toki wa Kare ni Yoroshiku"
[[ When you see him, Say Hello for Me ]]
Natsume.
Yes?
I don't think I'll be back 'till night,
so please turn the lights off when you leave.
Boss.
A love letter for you again...
...from the bank!
Business is not getting any better even after being featured in a magazine.
Please rip that sign off.
Oh, okay.
See you later.
Bye.
Uh, excuse me.
Welcome.
A moss started growing...
( Hiring part-timers: )
- Any age, sex.
- Anyone, as long as you love aquatic life forms.
Thank you very much.
Cute.
What?
Where did you get her?
Oh...
a customer gave her to us.
But it must be lonely, maybe I'll get another one.
It needs a lover! Right?
Uh...
This is an additive for accelerating aqua plant growth.
These plants withered because you put in too much fish food,
and the ecosystem became unbalanced.
Ecosystem?
Yes.
Leftover fish food and her bodily wastes must have polluted the water.
Because of that, the fragile balance inside the water tank fell apart,
and these aqua plants withered.
You must really love this job.
( We are permanently closed for various reasons.
Tooyama Hospital. Director, Dr. Tooyama Gorou )
When did you get here?
Oh, yeah...
Need any help?
I couldn't give it up until now.
It can't be helped. You have a bad heart.
Is your shop going to be all right?
You don't need to worry about me, dad.
( Time Capsule )
This is...
Yeah, I found it while cleaning up.
You didn't have to clean up my room...
Oh, Yuuji and Karin.
They made mom happy.
She said they were the first friends you brought back home.
[ Thank you very much, Mr. Kosaka. ]
[ It's a cold night. ]
[ It might be snowing in some areas. ]
[ Please continue to drive safely. ]
[ Next up on SEA-FM, ]
[ "Promises Don't Come Easy." ]
Aqua plants shop, "Trash".
Is this your shop?
Are you the owner?
Yes, I am.
May I help you?
You don't know?
Huh?
You don't know what I'm looking for?
Aqua plants?
Oh, a water tank?
"Hiring part-timers, any age, sex."
"Anyone, as long as you love aquatic life forms."
"Please contact the owner for details."
Oh, this... excuse me.
Wow, it's beautiful!
It's like I'm at the bottom of a lake.
Have some coffee if you like.
Ow, hot!
Thanks.
Not bad.
Although, slightly smaller than it seemed in the magazine.
You learned about my shop in the magazine?
Yes.
Thanks for coming, but this...
...I forgot to take it off.
We're no longer hiring.
You can hire one more.
No, that will be difficult.
It'll be difficult for me too.
I have nowhere to go.
But that's...
Then...
...you don't have to pay me, so let me stay here.
No, I use that room.
Hmm...
Then, I'll sleep here.
No, wait...
I'm Morikawa Suzune.
Oh, Ms. Morikawa.
Nice to meet you.
I'm Tooyama Satoshi.
Looking forward to working with you, boss.
- What?
Good night.
Uh, um...
( Destination: Our secret base )
Who are you?
Who the hell are you?!
What the hell were you doing here?!
He's my friend!
Huh?
Come on, introduce yourself.
Otherwise, she'll kick your butt.
I'm Tooyama Satoshi, I moved here a week ago!
She's Karin, Takigawa Karin.
Karin?
Yuuji's friend is my friend.
I'm Igarashi Yuuji, nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you!
Also, he's "Trash".
Nice to meet you, Trash.
A model?
I'm retired, so I'm an ex-model.
Wow...
This is a nice town.
I like your shop too.
When did you open that shop?
2 years ago.
I see.
Do you actually earn money selling aqua plants?
Honestly, I can barely stay in the business, but...
It's a promise I made as a child.
Really...
And... this too.
Yes.
Oh, she is...
Morikawa Suzune, right?
What? You know her?
Boss, you didn't?
She's a top model, famous overseas too!
She's that famous?
Excuse me...
Yes?
Are you Morikawa Suzune?
Yes.
I'm a big fan,
can you shake my hands?
80% of people in the world know her!
Hi.
Are you sick?
Uh... I have insomnia.
These are just some sleeping pills.
Oh.
Hey,
what's this aqua plant called?
This is Myriophyllum Matogurossense.
What about this?
That's Microsorium Narrow Leaf.
This one is Echinodorus Angustifolius,
and this is Willow Moss.
I designed this with the image of a forest.
It's kind of mysterious, isn't it?
Hey,
what are these?
They're seeds of water lily.
Some of them stay asleep for up to 50 years.
Stay asleep?
But sometimes, it suddenly sprouts up after 50 years.
I hope it wakes up while I'm alive.
This place is really relaxing.
If you'd like, you can sleep upstairs.
I can sleep here.
No.
Hurry and get out of my room.
This is my shop...
Uh, no...
Good night.
... Morikawa.
Morikawa.
Morikawa!
Are you all right?
You were crying out in your sleep.
This will wake you up.
Want sugar and milk?
No, thanks.
It's all fine now, the water is clean.
I'm relieved.
How I wonder what you are.
[ Humming ]
Here.
As a thanks for always coming to help.
Thanks.
Chocolate danish! Looks good!
Tooyama loves it.
Thank you.
Listen,
why don't the three of us have a dinner tonight?
Huh?
All right?
You can eat it.
"Tooyama loves it."
( Can also mean "I love Tooyama" depending on context )
I only need one.
You' really are oblivious!
Remember this, there's a meaning behind everything a woman does.
You don't pay attention
to her gaze or signs she's sending you.
Huh? What are you talking about?
Why?
Why don't you notice?!
Watch out, watch out!
Good evening.
Where's Suzune?
Cancelled last minute...
She sleeps in the shop at night?
Yes, she doesn't have anywhere else to stay.
Doesn't that excite you?
Am I really that oblivious...
Congratulations!
This is from us.
Thanks!
It's a water tank!
Do you like it?
Yes. Thanks,
mom and dad.
I'm back!
Welcome back.
Karin...
has never seen the faces of her parents.
I see...
I think that's why it made her feel lonely.
I'm back.
Welcome back, Karin.
Welcome back!
I'm back!
Trash?
Karin, blow it out.
Karin.
Come on, Karin.
Thank you so much.
Congratulations!
It's beautiful!
Satoshi found it from a broken binocular.
Yuuji said you like shiny stuff like this.
It's a prism.
It's a mirror that bends light.
Prism.
Thank you.
Come here for a minute, Karin.
It looks good on you!
You're a girl after all!
Happy birthday.
Hey, no peeking!
Twinkle, twinkle, little star.
How I wonder what you are.
[ Humming ]
Come here!
Let's take a photo!
This way, this way.
You go, Yuuji.
You go, Satoshi!
Come!
Great!
Twinkle, twinkle, little star.
How I wonder what you are.
[ Humming ]
How was it?
I didn't notice.
See? Told you.
She loves you.
Looks like there really is a meaning behind everything a woman does.
You just realized that?
I just realized...
...what you were looking for,
and why you came to my shop.
That's the prism Yuuji and I gave you.
Karin.
Oblivious!
It's been a long time.
Hey, Satoshi.
Which one is better?
That one.
This one?
What are you drawing?
- A clock.
- A clock?
- This?
- Yeah.
Right.
No, to the left!
What do you think, Yuuji?
Here.
- No, a bit to the right!
- A bit to the left!
Why?
They're all shining!
It's beautiful.
Give me one too.
Give me this one.
Where are we goin'?
What accent is that?!
What's the problem?
Let's go!
Wait!
Why didn't you tell me?
I have a pride too, you know.
You didn't remember me at all!
Because...
...you've really changed.
You haven't changed at all.
I'll take that as a compliment.
You can stay here forever, right?
How's Yuuji doing?
You didn't see him either?
Out of contact ever since leaving that town.
I see.
I wonder where he is now.
I wonder if he's still drawing.
I hope the three of us can get together again.
It's finished!
Do you think I can become an artist when I grow up?
You can. I guarantee it.
I think so too!
I think my mom will come back if I become a famous artist!
Right.
What's your dream?
Let's see...
Become the owner of an aqua plants shop.
What about you, Karin?
I don't have any dreams.
What do you want to be when you grow up?
Then...
...model for the artist,
and mascot girl for the aqua plants shop.
She's not here...
Ow!
Well, that's a surprise.
I'm surprised too.
No,
I'm surprised that you didn't recognize your childhood friend for so long!
He's been like this forever.
Shut up!
I can quit any time, now that Karin's in Trash.
What? You're quitting?
That's if I pass the accountant certification exam.
I'm thinking of succeeding my father's firm.
Really?
So, please stay here forever!
Oh, right. We have to find a place for her.
Huh?
You can't be sleeping in the shop's sofa forever.
He's right.
I wonder why she retired.
She said the diet was too tough.
Do you think that's the only reason?
I mean, she was just about to become a famous actress.
Satoshi!
Hurry.
What do you want to eat?
Curry!
Curry?
Curry, huh?
I found it!
Let's go.
Are you all right?
Yay!
Thanks.
Let's eat.
Hmm! It's delicious.
Ta-da!
I think this is a nice room.
What do you think?
Yes...
It's close to the shop too.
Listen, Satoshi...
Maybe this one is better?
That's not what I meant.
What is it?
Never mind.
[Medical Examination Room]
I wonder if Karin's all right.
Hey, Satoshi.
What?
What do you think of Karin?
What do you mean?
Don't you love her?
Huh?
But...
she has a bad mouth, and she's like a boy.
Don't you think?
I love her.
Are you all right?
Don't worry, just a minor anemia.
Karin?
It has been a long time.
I'm glad you came!
Come on in.
Well...
I don't mean to defend my own son, but
she became so beautiful, it's impossible to recognize her.
See?
It's nothing to brag about.
But you were beautiful back then too.
It wasn't something you could hide simply by dressing like a boy.
You must be happy to see her again.
He locked himself in his room after we moved.
- "I wanna see Karin!"
- Let's not talk about that!
What? What is it?
Come on, tell me!
It's nothing.
I'm sure his mom wanted to see you too.
It's been 13 years...
I wish I could turn back time.
I wish I can relive the time I spent in that town over and over again.
Karin.
It's the most powerful medicine.
This one stopped working for me too.
It wasn't cured?
I don't think I have much time left.
I keep falling deeper into sleep.
I'm afraid the next time I fall asleep...
...I'll never wake up again.
Karin...
I'm really glad you came!
Thank you.
Please don't tell Satoshi.
We haven't seen each other for 13 years.
So...
I intend to tell him I'm going somewhere far away.
Karin...
I'm...
...scared.
Scared of dying.
Please don't tell Satoshi.
Okay, I promise.
I'll write you a recommendation.
Have it looked at a bigger hospital.
Don't worry. I'm sure it'll get better.
I'm back.
Welcome back.
Where's Karin?
She said she's going out for a while.
Hello, this is Trash.
Yes.
Boss,
someone named Katsuragi wants to speak with you.
Okay.
Please help her.
10 Rotala Indica.
Got it.
Hello.
Are you Mr. Tooyama Satoshi?
Yes, it is.
My name is Katsuragi Momoka.
I'm Igarashi Yuuji's friend.
What?
Then, you're Tooyama's childhood friend?
I just wanted to see if he's doing all right.
As a childhood friend?
Satoshi has been like that since he was little.
Really oblivious and hard to get along,
he's the kind of person who can't adapt to the society.
You know, he's not interested in anything other than aqua plants.
He seems so happy...
What?
When he talks about aqua plants.
Oh.
Don't you think so?
It takes time for Satoshi to get used to other people,
but the truth is, he just thinks too much about others,
a kind person.
Please,
look after Satoshi for me.