SHOCHIKU FILMS
BLAZING SWORD
Moe Yo Ken
Produced by
OSUMI Tsuneo
Original Story by
SHIBA Ryotaro
Screenplay by KATO Tai
MORISAKI Azuma HASEBE Toshiro
Photography: SAKAI Tadashi
Music: WATANABE Takeo
cast
KURIXUKA Asahi
WAZAKI Shunya ISHIKURA Hidehiko
KOBAYASHI Tetsuko
Narrated by AKUTAGAWA Takayuki
TAKAMIYA Keiji UESUGI Takaya
TAKANO Shinji TOUE Jotaro AMATSU Bin
UCHIDA Ryohei
Directed by
ICHIMURA Hirokazu
MAY, 4th YEAR OF ANSEI (1857)
It was May of the 4th
year of Ansei, in Hinojuku.
A hot and humid night in early summer.
It happened on the festival night
at Rokusho Meijin in Fuchu...
Toshi, where are you going?
Are you heading for Myojin
to look for women?
It’s too early for that!
Why not come to my place? I’ll
keep the door open for you!
Idiot!
Don't you know Toshi
doesn’t go for farm girls?
His women have to have class!
Toshi, is that true?
Hurry up and run!
Don't forget where we promised to meet!
We swore that if we die, we'll die
together! I'll never leave you behind!
Stop that woman!
Doesn't look like much of a fight...
Are they serious?
Somebody help us! He's going to be killed!
Toshi, help them! Please!
Not me!
I like fighting, but I won't
interrupt a revenge match.
Damn you!
If you're going to kill
me, go ahead kill me!
kill me!
- We're not through with you yet!
You'd better come back and get to work!
No!
If I have to go back there, I'd rather die!
kill me! kill me!
Let go of me! Let go!
Release that woman!
Mind your own business,
or we'll cut you down!
Stop it! Toshi!
Don't! Toshi, stop!
Sister, what are you doing here?
What's the matter with you?
Why are you using your sword?
You didn't kill anyone, did you?
No, I didn't! I just tried to scare them.
My sweetheart...
My beloved!
Toshi, go back to the house.
There was a break-in at the Dojo!
A break-in?
Hiruma of Kogen Ittoryu in Hachioji...
He knew Isami wasn't
there, so he broke in...
Toshi, wait for me!
Don't forget the Sennin Toshi
men of Hachioji are behind him!
I know.
The man swinging the bamboo
stick is Rokusha Sohaku.
The one with a birth mark under
his eye's Shichiri Kennosuke.
Shichiri Kennosuke can
draw a sword in a flash...
like his right arm's longer than his left...
I don't like him.
Are you saying you refuse
to accept my challenge?
All right!
If you don't accept my challenge...
the Tennen Rishin style must
bow to the Kogen Itto style.
You must apologize and
treat our dojo with respect...
Hiruma...
Our students are just amateurs,
working as farmers...
We don't have the skill to
fight the Kogen Itto style...
Silence!
Swordsmanship is in our souls!
You must have confidence!
We can't let you use it as a game for
lowly farm-boys! Do you understand me?
Do they?
They may be low-class farmers,
but they own 3 tanbu each...
and belong to the Matsue Shogun family,
reinforcements to the Shogun's army.
Since Kurofune arrived, the
Samurai are afraid to fight...
and can't do their part, so we
can't trust them with the Shogun.
So, we must practice our swords.
What's wrong with that?
Toshi!
Hey, Toshi!
Who is this?
He runs the Dojo and he's
my step-brother...Toshizo.
If you're the leader of the Dojo,
why not accept my challenge?
Yes, I should, but it's a waste of my time.
What did you say?
Your Kogen Itto style and our
Tennen Rishin style are so different...
It's a waste of time fighting.
If we don't try, how will you know?
Okay, let's fight!
Toshi, don't!
You'll lose.
I'll demonstrate our fighting
technique with a bamboo sword.
Stick to them, otherwise they won't leave.
I don't have a choice...
Hiruma...
Let me explain the Tennen Rishin style.
I'm a teacher of Tennen Rishin...
And I'm here to teach farmers
who want to join our dojo.
That's all.
It's none of your concern.
Not only that, we stay within the
Hinojuku area and never go to Hachioji.
Shut up!
The Saitama area is Kogen
Itto's territory, including Hino.
Rokusha!
I am Rokusha Sohaku, a teacher.
I am Hijikata Toshizo.
My point!
The match!
Not yet!
What do you mean?
You're not just ignorant of
technique, you're defying the judge!
That's why I said we won't
accept your challenge.
What?
In our style, first we
retreat, and we retreat...
Finally we attack...
You're lucky we,re using bamboo swords.
If we were really fighting...
Your face would already be bleeding and
then, you'd be attacked from behind.
Look.
Your tobacco case!
It can't be...
In a real fight, your hand
would be cut in two!
I can hold a sword in my other hand.
If we were fighting to the death,
the match would be mine!
Will you shut up!
You've lost! You're still
refusing to admit defeat.
Regardless of your
opinion, I won the match.
I don't care what you say about it!
Am I right, Isami?
Isami, you'd better not say that I lost.
You lost, Toshi.
You're the loser of the
bamboo sword match.
Nobody will give you
extra points for brains...
If you're going to teach a fencing
style, can't you teach it correctly?
Wait!
Toshi, you're persistent!
What are you doing?
What can I prove with this!
They only saw me fight with bamboo!
They can't see my skills with steel!
I'll ask you, how would I have
done if this fight was real?
I've told you, we won't know
until you do fight for real.
All right!
From now on, I'm going
to fight only with steel.
Only true matches so that
anyone can tell the difference.
Maybe it's a good idea...
Who cares about the Kogen Itto style?
Who cares about being a samurai?
This is the day of the warrior.
If we want to conquer the
world, we'll do that too.
Isami, I promise you I'm going
to turn you into a Daimyo!
Toshi, your head's getting
too big again, isn't it?
I'm serious.
I understand.
We must reach the top of the
world with our swords alone.
That's our only chance of success.
Kondo, let's do it!
Then please, help me do it.
Okay, leave it to me.
Toshi's technique is unearthly...
He must be possessed by ghosts.
Yeah, right! By a crazy female ghost!
Toshi, come over here for a minute!
What is it, sister?
What's this, Toshi?
Where did you find that?
In your room. Why are they in your room?
I don't know.
Found them on the street...
You fool!
This mark on the bag is the proof
mark of Lord Sawatari of Sado.
Sawatari?
It must be Sae's, she's
the sister of Sawatari...
I think you saw Sae at last
night's fair, didn't you?
I guess...
Toshi, you'd better get married soon.
I can find a wife for you.
Stop! I have so many things to do.
A man with a wife and
children can't do anything.
She's Sawatari's sister...
Toshi, Sae is not for you!
Think of who you are!
Think about who I am?
Who's there?
The man you met last night.
I came to give this back to you.
You don't have to thank me,
but I want to ask one thing.
You're a woman born to a great family...
Why did you act like a farm girl last night?
The 'Night Fair, is for farmers
who worked all year...
to relax and enjoy themselves
like human beings for a night.
It's not for an upper
class woman like you.
I just wanted to forget my status...
for one night.
So, you've had too much red snapper
and wanted to try a sardine last night.
And that sardine was me.
Please leave!
No, I won't.
I'm sure you realize I'm not here...
just to return the bag after
what passed between us...
I'm trying to forget last night.
That was a gift for my God from me.
Please forget last night!
I won't forget! That's why I'm here.
There's a legend that if a man and
woman sleep together during the Fair...
God will punish them and they'll
belong to each other forever.
According to the legend, I belong to you.
It's true!
If you don't want me,
kindly kill me with this!
You say you want to forget
who you are for one night...
But if you hate your position,
why don't you leave?
If I could do that, I'd do it
now. You don't understand.
No, I don't!
But I'm going to make
you do it right now.
Oh, it's you!
It's me. What about it?
Since I'm a Sawatari
family guard, I'll kill you!
Since when does a Kogen Itto
man get demoted to a guard?
The other day you said
you'd have won a real fight.
Have you ever killed a man?
No, I haven't.
But today I'll kill my first man.
If two men with the same
skill at bamboo swords fight...
the man who's killed before will win.
A man's skill is different
before and after he has killed.
Do you understand?
Perhaps...
I'll find out very soon.
I killed him!
At last I've killed a man...
Finally... I've killed!
Damn it!
He fought many duels.
But who did this to Rokusha?
Was it revenge or a challenge?
Why didn't I kill him with my first swing?
Why couldn't I take one step
forward and slay him immediately?
Toshizo!
You killed Rokusho, didn't you?
How do you know my name?
Please do this for me!
Run away with me!
Run away? Why? Who
are we running from?
From our status!
You said you would make me leave.
If I stay, I'll never see you again.
You know of the bonds between the
Sawatari and Kujo families, don't you?
You mean the Kujo family
from Kuge in Kyoto?
To secure my brother's future, I
must marry into the Kujo family...
If you don't want to, why not refuse?
If people find out that
you killed Rokusha...
Are you saying I'm not
good enough for you?
If you love me, run away
with me right now!
It's true!
I love you from the bottom of my heart...
but a woman's love and
a man's are different.
A man doesn't love staying
together like a woman wishes.
A man must fight for his
life and defeat his enemies.
Win over himself and kill
whoever tries to stop him.
But you are my life!
What am I to you?
A prize in your fight? Am I your enemy?
Or...
Or what?
As you say, perhaps you are my enemy...
KOISHIKAWA, YANAGIMACHI
Oh, Soji!
I'm back!
Well, come in.
Hijikata, I went to Hino yesterday
and practiced at our Dojo.
Your brother and sister seemed very well.
Is that so?
They send their regards
and ask you to be careful.
Careful about what?
I don't know.
Sensei, Rokusha Sohaku was killed!
Did you say Rokusha
got killed? By whom?
The people at Hiruma Dojo are
looking hard for a suspect...
but they can't find one.
Hijikata, aren't you going to practice?
Strange for you to take a nap
in the middle of a day, isn't it?
Something wrong with you?
Shut up! A kid doesn't understand!
What could have happened to him?
I don't know.
I don't know what happened,
but he's a changed man.
Lately no one wants to
be his practice partner.
I'm having a hard time getting
them to practice with him.
Sensei, there's a man
called Shichiri Kennosuke...
a member of Hiruma Dojo, here
to request a practice match.
What? Shichiri's here?
Isami, let me ask you...
Is there a technique to block...
an enemy's first sword swing
in the Tennen Rishin style?
At first, step back...
Second, step back and
back, step back...that's it!
If there's no room to step
back, what should I do?
Take a breath and slice their sword
guard with the end of your blade.
If it's too late for that, what should I do?
You're going to be killed.
Anyway, Shichiri wants me
for a partner, so I'd better go!
No, you're not!
I'm the owner of this Dojo.
Mind your own business!
But he wants me to...
This is the middle of Edo.
It's not a little country town.
Thank you for accepting my request.
Our dojo rules for a practice
match are three to a game.
Hey, Todorisuke, you're the first!
I'm sure you remember Rokusha
Sohaku who came for a challenge fight.
He's dead.
I see...
Because he had a few sword wounds...
the law thinks there were a few attackers.
A few attackers?
Fools.
Fight's over!
Next! Nagakura Shinpachi!
Next! Inoue Genzaburo!
One moment!
One group against another should
fight with a different style...
and I now understand this Dojo's style.
I see...
Will you quit now?
Never! I will never quit.
I'd never do such a rude thing.
But I hear your Dojo has a special
technique called the Sunegiri Art...
that attacks knees and thighs.
The art you're probably
thinking of is the Ryubo style...
our Tennen Rishin style
has no such technique.
But, there are people who can
use many styles and techniques.
The man who killed
Rokusha is one of them.
I can tell by looking at his wounds...
It's an evil and cowardly art!
I'm going to find out who
this man is and kill him!
Hijikata, don't let him provoke you!
Shut up!
I'm going to be next!
Wait!
Do you like my Nejiri Art?
It was you!
Surely, this style was
used to kill Rokusha.
No! This style didn't kill hm!
It doesn't matter, thigh or
elsewhere, my sword will slice all!
It was the spirit of the Tennen
Rishin style that gave me victory.
What's going on?
Are you villains teaming up to rob us?
This is a challenge with Samurai pride!
Pardon...
but it's not proper to fight in the
Shogun's family Dojo. If you do...
you'll be blamed for starting a quarrel.
Isn't that right?
Fine.
I'll come back and look at
Hijikata Toshizo's style again.
Your Sunegiri Style, a farmer's
art and it's only good at night.
Toshi!
- Hijikata!
Hijikata!
It's you! What do you want?
What do I want? How can you say that?
I got up in the middle of
the night to look for you.
But you were gone.
I thought you went to the Dojo by
yourself, so I woke Master Kondo.
He said, ''I can't let dear Toshizo be killed.
''Please Okita, go after him
and help...'' Just like that.
How can I let a kid help me!
Mind your own business!
Go home and go back to bed!
Hijikata, are you really going to do it?
Fool!
How can we say and do nothing...
after they show up at our
Dojo and insulted us like that?
Think about it!
You're right! I'll go with you!
You'd better not! It's
nothing to do with you.
If we let you die, the Tennen
Rishin style's name will fade away.
You can't!
You've never killed a man.
That's why I must go!
Toshi, you must leave as
soon as you finish eating...
or the men of the Hiruma
Dojo will find you.
I saw them not long ago.
Toshi!
They're coming soon.
Coming here?
Don't worry!
They'll just bring a letter to
request a challenge match.
Are you Okita Soji of the Kondo Dojo?
You know very well.
Please give my message
to Hijikata Toshizo!
Tell him we know who killed Rokusha
and we could go to the police...
but we of Hiruma Dojo take pity on
you and we won't, he needn't worry.
And?
Too bad I discovered his pian to
sneak in and attack me in the night...
No matter how good he is with
technique, he won't succeed tonight!
Where? What time?
The place is the bridge
over Buai river at midnight.
Just the two of you.
Don't fight!
It's not a fight.
Just a wild dog running
around here and bothering us.
I'm going to get rid of him.
I see, it's a wild dog.
Yes, a wild dog.
You've set a time and place, haven't you?
Yes, I've set a time and place.
Don't attack a wild dog head-on.
Attack it from the side.
Is that so?
By the way brother, I have a favor to ask.
What is it?
After I kill the dog, I'll
leave it under the bridge.
Please send some men to
get rid of the dead dog.
Right, no problem!
Good night.
- Later.
How was it?
It's a problem!
I'm not sure because of the darkness...
but I'd guess about twenty men
are hiding around the place.
Shichiri's a liar!
He told me only two men would show up.
How many on the bridge?
There's only two.
But there's 3 or 4 men
under the farmhouse roof...
and 3 or 4 more hiding
in the grass nearby.
Where are most of them hiding?
North of the bridge, behind
the hut and behind the oak.
They're all over the place.
I can imagine...
They're expecting us to come
south on the Kamakura highway.
That's the common route.
Hey, why are you staring at me?
No, I'm just admiring you.
And thinking that you're not
just a good man in a fight.
You idiot!
You shouldn't tease an adult!
Just keep your eyes on the map!
We'd better figure out what to do,
because there's only two of us...
How about this area?
I only saw one shadow moving.
Okay!
Thanks.
Soji, we're going to
attack by the river first.
You start from up-river.
I'll start from down-river and I'll
attack the men under the bridge.
This is a tough position.
We're stuck like a
snapping turtle in the mud.
That's our strategy!
I admire your style, but what style is this?
It's Hijikata style!
Can't be. It's snapping turtle style.
Now I'm going to sneak
in under the bridge.
You turn back and start from the south.
I have no choice!
Okita Soji, here I come!
Go after him!
Get him!
Let's get out of here!
Get them! Chase them!
Toshi!
Do you have any medicine?
Soji, did you get hurt?
How's the bite of the wild dog?
The Tennen Rishin style isn't that bad.
Now you've been in a fight and
learned true fighting technique.
Did you see them?
Over here!
What time is it?
It's 4.
You're leaving already?
Sorry for the trouble.
Toshi...
I'm going to Kyoto tomorrow.
Hey, they're over here!
Go after them!
Sae...
I don't know who you're watching...
but you can't walk around
here anytime you wish.
I'm replacing Rokusha
and I'm your guard.
Thank you but no thanks!
I see...
Is it inconvenient for you
to have me hanging about?
No matter where you
hide Hijikata Toshizo...
I'll find him and I'll kill him!
FIvE YEARS LATER
THIRD YEAR OF BUNKYU (1863)
Five years later, in the
Third Year of Bunkyu.
The Tokugawa Government
sent about 234 ronin...
including Kiyokawa Hachiro
of Shonai, to Kyoto...
to stop the men who wanted
to destroy the Shogunate...
In the name of Tennen Rishin-ryu,
Kondo and Hijikata joined this group...
Kondo, why do you have such
a humble post in this group?
I don't know.
They don't respect the Tennen Rishin.
A man who drinks all day is
the leader in this group...
and even his follower
has a manager's role.
It's nonsense!
Serizawa Kamon.
He's a survivor of the Mito Tengu group.
We don't care who he is!
They chose us for our skills, didn't they?
You sound like Toshi now...
Hey Toshi...
You said you'd make me a
Daimyo someday, remember?
Of course I do!
Why did you say that?
Why not?
A man who has skill and
power should be a Daimyo...
If not, something's
wrong with the system.
Can you smell it?
I can smell it all right!
Won't be long before you're a Daimyo!
KYOTO
Everybody...
I, Kiyokawa, will give a
very important speech.
Please listen carefully and pay attention!
We're gathered to guard the
Shogun's family, visiting Kyoto.
Well, this is just a cover story.
Our true goal is the principle
of reverence for the Emperor...
and the expulsion of foreigners.
And to build a safe and peaceful country.
Kiyokawa Hachiro will kill anyone who
becomes an obstacle to my purpose...
even if he's a high ranking
officer of the Government!
Anybody disagree with me?
Yes!
Kiyokawa, you're using
underhanded methods!
Silence!
Serizawa, you're drunk again.
I'll listen to what you have
to say when you're sober.
Shut up! Shut up! You betrayer!
Kiyokawa...
We're here because
the Shogun invited us!
Until the Shogun orders
it, we can't leave Kyoto.
Who are you?
You're just a ronin!
You're not a man from any
Clan or the Government...
so your body and your
spirit should be free.
The country faces a
great storm these days...
so I must try hard to get permission to
take action in reverence for the Emperor!
If you're a man, stand up for yourself!
Believe in Kiyokawa and follow me!
I'm going to drink more Sake!
A woman! A woman!
Bring me a woman from Shimabara!
Toshi, what should we do?
I think this is an opportunity.
What?
The time has come for seven
men of the Tennen Rishin Style.
I was waiting for this chance!
Kiyokawa Hachiro is going
to make himself famous!
But what's going to happen to the
ronin who were chosen by Kiyokawa?
So, we replace Kiyokawa and
we build a new army of ronin.
I see...
Can we do it?
Yes, we can!
But there's one more man we can use.
Who's that?
That drunk, Serizawa Kamon.
I thought Hijikata didn't like drunks.
I don't.
But he's connected with a member
of the Aizu Katamori clan...
of the Shogunate police in Kyoto and
he can help present our plans directly.
So we're going to use him.
That's an good idea!
Toshi, I agree with you.
Sannosuke, Harada, how about you?
It's up to Kondo.
Inoue Genzaburo agrees!
Nagakura Shinpachi will let you decide!
Todo Heisuke says go ahead!
Okita Soji agrees!
Good!
If everybody agrees, Isami...
We have to do something, to bring a
gift to the Kyoto Shogunate police.
Is it about Kiyokawa?
Working hard, Isami?
Has anyone seen Kiyokawa
leaving the Kujo clan's house?
I don't think so, how about you, Kondo?
No, I haven't seen anything.
How about we just break in to the place
Kiyokawa's staying in and attack him?
No, we must be patient.
Isami, please go and get some rest!
And Master Kondo too!
''Master Kondo''...?
If you put it that way, I'll do it.
It's getting cold and I'm
getting hungry too...
Eat something!
Kondo's still a country boy, if he trusts...
and relies on an unsociable man like you.
He's a good man.
He's our boss, our leader since childhood.
The house of Chief Advisor Kujo.
If I go to Kyoto, at least once I'd
like to sleep with a Kyoto woman.
Serizawa!
Wait! Let me handle this!
But...
- I'll do it!
I'm the new leader! I can't
let another do this job!
If they attack, you'll be left all alone!
If we waste time now, we
won't have time for Kiyokawa...
Damn it! Do what you want!
Here I go!
- Be careful!
I understand!
Toge!
Did he do it?
Damn it!
Who are you?
A man who appreciates your grudge!
Kiyokawa, we're here to summon you!
we'll take care of this!
Sir, now!
Kiyokawa, you're a coward!
It's no use chasing Kiyokawa! Let him go!
It's an assassination!
Toshi!
Come this way!
Sae!
Hurry!
Put out the light!
It's all right!
We're alone.
The only visitors here are
young girls, my students.
Is there something wrong?
You've changed...
Have I? Why did you say that?
You seem so honorable...
You look so good in your scarf...
You seem to belong here in Kyoto...
To survive in a dangerous world...
a woman needs somebody to lean on.
Is that why you joined the
anti-Shogunate rebels?
After 5 years, people can change.
Maybe you have a reason to look
forward in hope, but I don't.
Stop it! Give it all up!
Throw it away and go back to your home!
Please leave Kyoto!
Toshi, why say it now?
I begged you to run away
with me 5 years ago...
Don't say that!
If you don't go, I may
have to kill you some day.
I don't care!
I'd rather have you kill me than leave me.
I'm a woman...
I can't see tomorrow,
but now... now I want...
This may be the last
time we see each other.
Please take care of yourself.
Yes.
Kiyokawa Hachiro leaves today
for Kanto to raise an army.
An Imperial order will be
issued within three days.
Will you believe me?
Toshi, when we're together
I'm not your enemy...
I am only a woman.
Toshi...
Kiyokawa and his ronin stayed
in Kyoto for twenty days.
Ten men left behind, including Hijikata
Toshizo, tried to find employment.
They banded together and
called themselves Shinsengumi.
The people feared them...
and swore they were as wild
and dangerous as wolves.
Did you donate some money
yesterday? How much did you give?
For 3o years...
the world's been peaceful and rich.
You've had a good life, haven't you?
Please take this and leave.
We didn't come here for blackmail.
We just want to know if you
have gratitude in your heart!
KYOTO GOVERNMENT
POLICE HEAD QUARTERS
Sir...
Thanks to the Shinsengumi,
people don't fight every day...
and Kyoto can stay peaceful.
I will report to our Lord and thank you!
But, Serizawa is a problem...
The way he's managing things
affects all the Shinsengumi...
It's a shame. Because of him the
Shinsengumi may have to be dissolved.
Dissolved?
That's what the Lord said.
Someone was hit by a cannon shot...
in Yamateya Shobei's
home in Nishiyamaji...
and a woman was raped...
the mistress of Hishiya, a
prominent textile dealer.
I understand.
Kondo!
Yes, I can see his concerns.
Is he saying that "under these
circumstances, please accept it,,?
Toshi, you say you
understand, so I also said...
,'I understood...,,
but what was Tojima telling us?
He thinks we must kill Serizawa Kamon.
But Toshi...
Serizawa is the leader of the Shinsengumi.
He can't do whatever he
wants because he's the leader!
The leader can't dominate
the Shinsengumi.
I know. But you said...
We should use him because he had
connections in the Shogunate?
It doesn't matter, we must
kill whoever does wrong!
We're going to kill an evil man!
Whoever breaks our
rules, we must kill him!
And whoever disgraces the name of
the Shinsengumi, we must kill him!
If I did one of these things,
would you kill me, too?
Yes, I would!
Are you sure?
Yes, I am!
But on that day...
the life of Hijikata Toshizo will end...
and Okita will die...
and the Tennen Rishin style
and Shinsengumi will also die.
I understand, Toshi.
Kondo...
What is it?
You are the commander in chief!
You're not the owner of a
Dojo in some old dirty town...
and you're not a swordsman
feared by the people.
You're going to be a model for
samurai all over the world!
You're going to help lead
the people of the world!
Who needs the Daimyo? Who
needs leaders of the Shogun's clan?
Kondo...
You are the one who's a true
samurai! We are all true samurai!
SEPTEMBER, THIRD
YEAR OF BUNKYU (1863 )
Master Ninmi...
I hate to interrupt your
charming conversation.
Hijikata, you're a crude ruffian!
Ninmi, I came here to ask a favor of you.
I'd like you to commit Seppuku!
What?
I want you to commit Seppuku right here!
You're not in charge of the Shinsengumi!
I have no reason to take orders from you!
Yes, you have!
The crime was burglary,
and taking bribes.
You!
You want us to kill you?
I'm willing to let you commit
Seppuku like a noble samurai.
Master Ninmi!
This is the way to perform Seppuku!
Kondo!
Your friend Ninmi was ordered to commit
Seppuku because he broke our rules.
What?
Master Serizawa...
I'm very sorry but you must die as well.
Silence! My sword...
Master!
You bastard!
Isami, now you truly are
the leader of Shinsengumi!
And I am vice-leader, Hijikata Toshizo!
The rules of the Shin Sen Group:
1. Don't break the Group's rules.
2. Don't ever leave the Group.
3. Don't try to profit from the Group.
4. Don't get involved with the law.
5. Don't fight other
members of the Group.
Whoever breaks the rules, will
be ordered to perform Seppuku.
A man to target, a man to be targeted.
The victor today may be dead tomorrow.
Doubts about the assassinations grew in
the last days of the Tokugawa Shogunate.
And there was a terrifying
atmosphere in the streets of Kyoto.
Katsura was a target, too...
They come to attack us, and
we in turn take revenge.
Back and forth. And it's so frightening.
I've heard a very ominous story.
They said that the ronin are
going to burn Kyoto down.
ONE YEAR LATER
SUMMER, FIRST YEAR OF GANJI (1864)
No! No! It's not true! It can't be true!
Of course, as you say, I
was called "Bragging Taro,,
...but now I'm just a handyman!
Silence. We have proof.
Everybody, it's the Shinsengumi!
Shut up!
All about the weapons and ammunition...
this letter from those ronin calling
themselves 'honorable samurai'...
You'd better come with us
and tell us if this is a fake!
If you're not guiity, we'll let you go home.
Come on!
TANTORA RESTURANT AND INN
Furutaka Shunsuke was arrested.
Sir!
Sir what do we do?
We're going to try to break him out!
How?
We have to break in...
It's too reckless!
Reckless?
Furutaka's imprisoned
by the Shinsengumi.
But do we have any other choice?
You're right!
We were ready to die
when we came to Kyoto.
With that resolve, all things are possible!
But rushing to our death
is not the best way.
We'd simply be committing suicide!
Committing suicide? Watch your mouth!
What?
Wait a minute. We don't
have time to argue now.
Let's meet again tomorrow night...
to talk about setting the fire
and trying to rescue Furutaka!
We already know they
pian to set fires in Kyoto...
to breach the Imperial Palace.
They want to start a war and
destroy the Tokugawa Shogunate.
Their targets are Miyabi of
Higo, Yoshido of Goshu...
Kitazoe of Tosa and Momoyama.
So far we have at least
twenty-two names.
Don't pretend you don't know...
we already know that they're
meeting at Tantora in Kiwamachi!
If you know, why ask me!
What else do you know? Maybe
their meeting date and time?
That's enough!
Furutaka...
You've kept your mouth shut this
long, your friends will forgive you.
Tell us everything.
I know nothing!
What can we do with you?
We're not going to stop until he speaks!
This is our moment in time...
when the Shin Sen Group becomes
the world-famous Shinsengumi!
Are you sure the place is Tantora?
On that snowy night... what time?
Toshi...
If we keep that up, he's going to die.
vice-leader!
What is it?
It's a letter!
To whom?
To Hijikata Toshizo.
From Sae.
Sae?
It's five years since you
saw her in Kyoto, isn't it?
Hijikata, she married into the Kujo clan.
She's connected with the
family of the Shogun.
I know that.
Hijikata!
I don't want to scold you but do
you understand the situation now?
That's why I'm going now!
This could be a trap!
And maybe it's not...
Even so, it's all right with me.
It's too dangerous to go
alone! I'm coming with you!
You idiot!
I'm going to see a woman!
Besides, if a scary-looking guy like you
comes along, even a ghost won't show.
Well, so long.
Pardon me.
Toshi!
As I expected, you've come to see me.
Please come in!
I've missed you!
Who did you send to bring me a letter?
A letter?
What is this?
You don't know?
I know nothing about this letter.
Who wrote this?
As we expected, it's a trap...
A trap?
Toshi!
Run! Please hurry!
Toshi, do you doubt me?
I want to trust you.
That's why I came here to see for myself.
Did you come here alone?
Are you risking your life?
Toshi! I'm so glad!
Please trust me!
When I'm with you, I'm just a woman.
Hijikata, long time no see!
Glad we can see each other again.
Toshi, it's wrong!
Wait!
I'll do it!
If I kill the vice-leader of the
Shinsengumi, I'll become very famous!
Shichiri Kennosuke of Kogen
Itto Style will be famous.
vice-leader! vice-leader!
Let's go!
Please stay where you are.
I'm Detective Yamazaki Susumu.
I'd like to ask you a few questions, please
come with me to our headquarters!
Everyone, would you please excuse us?
When will the arson group get
together for their meeting?
What time will the meeting be?
We won't accept that you
don't know. Go ahead tell us!
Not only are innocent people going
to suffer in the flames of the city...
but whether we are right or wrong...
the one thing that's certain is...
that the innocent townsfolk and
farmers shouldn't be caught up in this.
I see...
I really have to find out.
Toshi...
Don't let them torture her.
She's a woman!
She's not a woman...
she's our enemy.
The woman wants to talk to Hijikata.
Sae, I'm here! It's me!
Do you understand?
Oh, Toshi!
I don't care if I die, if I
can make you happy.
Today is the day that
they're getting together.
Today? You're certain?
It will be after sundown when the
people are all at the Gion Festival.
It will be five o'clock this night.
Where will they meet?
It will be at the Ikeda-ya
over by the Sanjo Kobashi...
Ikeda-ya?
Did you say Ikeda-ya?
Please do whatever you want with me!
I'm not going to try to escape.
Hold on, Sae!
Is she going to be all right?
If we treat her right way...
Please do that!
Tonight at 5 PM at the Ikeda-ya.
Ikeda-ya?
We never thought about that place.
Toshi...
Can we believe her?
Have you heard anything
from the watchman?
No, we haven't heard anything yet.
We're running out of time!
Captain, we'll break into two teams.
Will you really go to Tantora?
Hijikata, don't you trust her?
No, it's not that!
But if we trust her and
all go to the Ikedaya...
and then find them at Tantora later,
the Shinsengumi's pride will suffer!
Captain, there's a man here to see you...
who was sent by Detective Matsudaira.
Excuse me!
Are you Detective Oki?
We planned to send about
2ooo men to join you...
but it was a last minute decision.
We still don't know how we're going
to handle the confusion in town.
It's too late to worry about that now.
Anyway, the Shinsengumi
will take care of it!
Well, anyway, we tried to
hurry and did our best.
Excuse me.
Leader, it's time to make a decision!
Toshi...
Let's do it!
Isami, this is going to be
our life's final gamble!
Yamanami, Okita,
Harada, Nagakura, Todo...
This group follows our
leader and goes to Ikeda-ya.
The rest of you will come
to Tantora with me!
Hijikata, you're not taking enough men!
Why don't you take the Okita group?
No, it's all right.
Both groups, if you arrive and
find there's nobody there...
you must go to the other place and
join the fight as soon as possible!
Don't let any of the enemy get outside!
And don't count on the
men of Aizu Kawana!
We, the Shinsengumi must fight alone!
Where's the innkeeper? We're the
patrolmen of the Shinsengumi!
You! Shichiri...
Hijikata!
I've been waiting for you!
Where is Kondo?
Where is Yabe Teizo?
Where's Yoshida, Kitazoe, Murayama...
Minister and assistant minister?
Where's everybody hiding?
Draw your sword and come over here!
Did you take Furutaka
hostage and try to find us?
As we planned, he sent
you to Tantora, eh?
Hijikata, you're trapped!
Trapped?
The meeting place is Ikeda-ya!
What?
Sae answered my question
and told me it's Ikeda-ya!
Did Sae say that? You're lying!
Lying? Fool!
Kondo Isami and the Shinsengumi
are fighting at Ikeda-ya right now!
Damn you!
Listen! Our men at the
Ikeda-ya are trapped!
Go over there and help them!
Shichiri! Running away!
You coward!
Shut up! Come to the Ikeda-ya!
I swear I'll kill you there!
Be careful!
When I finish here, the Ikeda-ya is next!
Friends, we're here to help you!
Hijikata, why are you here?
Why not?
Tonight's the night for the Shinsengumi!
And it's the chance of
a lifetime for me too!
I can't miss it!
Sir, please let me handle this!
You, go to the clan's main
house and bring more help!
We've won...
I've won...
The Tennen Rishin won.
The Shinsengumi has won!
What you said has come true, Toshi.
Your prediction has come true.
Something is bothering me,
there's somewhere I must go.
Sae!
What did you do?
It's me!
I've killed you.
You said you just wanted to be a woman.
Hijikata Toshizo turned
you into a traitor...
and caused your death.
Sae!
What a tragic end this was.
Sae...
Your life was full of pain...
but thanks to you...
the city of Kyoto has been
spared and her people are safe.
Hijikata!
- Leave him alone.
Isami, I must change myself!
Tomorrow's Hijikata Toshizo must be
different from this Hijikata Toshizo.
But one thing will never change.
Our friendship...
and the fellowship of Shinsengumi
can be torn apart only by death.
But this was a young man's dream,
to belong to Shinsengumi...
and live a full life with sword in hand.
This day ended in victory at Ikeda-ya.
But their swords could not
stem the tide of history...
nor stop the rush of a changing world.
Only three more years remained before
the Shogun's reign would come to an end.
Special Thanks to Merlin and BigJohn
Subtitled and Mastered by Cannibal King
Subtitle fixed by Amendil
www.KuroTokagi.com