TOEI COMPANY, LTD. PRESENTS
Shimonoseki
This is an emergency!
Keep to the left!
Make way!
Watch out! Keep to the Left!
Move to the left!
FIRST STAR
This is an emergency!
Move to the left!
JONATHAN THE SEAGULL
I repeat! This is an emergency!
TRUCK RASCALS
NO ONE CAN STOP ME
Planning: Kenji Takamura
Screenplay: NORIFUMI SUZUKI / SHINICHIRO SAWAI
Cinematography : HANSHNIRO NAKAZAWA
Art director: KUWANA TADAYUKI
Film Editing: OSAMU TANAKA
Assistant Director: SHOUKAKU BABA
Music: CHUJI KINOSHITA
Theme song sung by:
BUNTA SUGAWARA
Cast:
JUNKO NATSU
YUKATA NAKAJIMA
MASAYUKI YUHARA - SHOJI ISHIBASHI
SEITARO KURODA - MASUMI HARUKANA
YUUSUKE NATSU - TORU YURI - HOSEI KOMATSU
HIROMITSU SUZUKI - TOSHIAKI MINAMI
AKIRA OIZUMI - MASAHIKO TANIMURA
SHINYA SATO
MAKOTO SATO and the members of the
DOWNTOWN BOOGIE-WOOGIE BAND
KINYA AIKAWA
Directed by Norifumi Suzuki
Tokyo
Kawasaki
I've brought you
good shirts, haven't I?
I don't like this one.
It's good Kojiro.
You're wrong.
I'm Konosuke.
Kojiro!
- Michiko!
- Hanako!
- Sayuko!
-Ko...
Kosaburo!
This is Koshiro,
and baby here.
Too many kids!
Let's eat!
Daddy's pilfered goods
are cheaper than presents.
Silly! Pilfering is free.
Brother Konosuke
told me about that.
Don't tell
Were you loyal to me?
Don't be silty!
Of course I was.
One more bottle of beer.
Don't get drunk.
You must love me tonight.
- Michiko.
- What?
You're like your mama.
You better get married, Momo.
Do you want me to be your wife?
My wife is my truck.
I'll always be with her.
Welcome back.
Take  these watermelons.
You pilfered a lot!
It's part of a driver's skill
to pilfer goods.
I once pilfered 10 cases
of frozen prawns.
Poor consignors!
It's a part of freight.
They know that.
Then I'll take them.
Thanks.
I'll come back later.
I'll have her.
Darling, make love to me...
It's been a while...
Wake up.
Papa, I wanna piss.
MONA LISA OKYO
- Just arrived?
- Getting ready for bed?
I had girls at the bathhouse.
You better sleep with a man
once in a while.
You, lecherous ape!
A present for you.
A widow should get married again.
You should get married.
You look filthy.
You scum!
Lousy driving!
Look at the damage!
It's only a lamp!
He's at it again.
Stop it!
What do you think a highway is?
It's not a private driveway!
Matsushita!
You were a policeman,
Shame on you!
You're wasting your words,
Captain.
he drove a squad car while drunk.
And he got fired.
He's a disgrace to us.
Can't Imagine he was once
feared by truck drivers
as "the devil.”
I'm sorry for being picked up so often.
Officer.
He quit the police force.
You're mean to say so.
Yes, I definitelty
quit the police.
Quit the police?
Ass! The police isn't a gang!
To us truck drivers...
it's a gang of terrorists.
What?
You insult the police?
Thanks a lot.
If you were held,
you wouldn't fight again.
Not again!
Fix me up too, Okyo.
The first aid kit
is in my truck, Kinzo!
Okyo, don't you want a man?
Your breast must be
crying for one.
Don'! fight again!
All right!
Hurry up! I can't wait!
Easy.
Are you constipated?
Hurry!
Pardon me.
It wasn't me.
Where has that nasty guy gone?
First Star, give me paper.
Don't say such a thing.
You're rude.
Use your hand.
There was a funny guy
in the can.
How are you, Viper?
Are you in good shape, Rover?
Hi, Jonathan!
Hello, Virgin! Do't eat to much
or your joint'll shrink.
- First Star, Here I am!
- Come!
Where are you going?
I wanna piss.
You did.
You can't drink from it!
Sister!
What do you want, sir?
A cup of coffe.
Coffee? Don't make me laugh!
I'm not hungry.
You? You eat like a horse.
You'd better order.
Fried leeks, pork stew
and a big bowl of rice.
Wait. Are you new?
You're beautiful.
I'm Jonathan.
I'm Yoko. How do you do?
I'm Momojiro!
Nobody hears you.
Wait a minute!
You're just like my dead wife.
Why are you working here?
For money.
She must have some special reason.
A rich man's daughter
working in a hash-house.
If you have a problem,
tell me about me.
We're now friends.
Tell me about your trouble.
I'll be moved to tears.
Don't cry. Just tell me.
Don't ask!
Every man has a past
he wants to conceal.
For example, I started
to work as a truck driver,
but before...
You'd been a driver.
Everyone jas a reason.
You're right. Each person
has his own reasons.
We can't go to Hokkaido,
leaving her here.
Hokkaido?
"Hamanasu" must be pretty.
“Hamanasu”?
It must be a flower.
"Hamanasu” must be beautiful.
We couldn't find
"hamanasu" in Hakodate.
Maybe in Shiretoko.
- I'll go to Shiretoko,
- You can't go there.
Let's see stripers.
I'll be moved to tears.
Save me from these hoodlums!
You slob!
What are you doing?
Get down!
Can't you read this notice?
Can't you read these letters?
Fool!
Save me! I beg you!
He tried to run
with our boss' woman.
Let's heat these truck
jockies first!
He's recovered from lovesickness.
You seduced a stripper
and were thrown out, eh?
There's no place for me to go.
Hire me as tour assistant.
- We don't use assistants.
- I ain't asking you.
Please, President.
You mean me?
Say it again.
I'll repeat it many times,
President. President!
What a beautiful truck!
When compared with this,
Rolls' and Caddies are just jalopies.
On the contrary, this one looks
like a junkman's truck.
What did you say?
He said, "a junkman's truck."
You can understand art.
I like you.
President Momojiro Hoshi.
- Hey, let him join us.
- What do you say?
You two make a team.
I don't care,
“Hamanasu”?
I need "hamanasu",
even if they're withered.
You're in Aomori.
There's no "hamanasu" here.
Do you want to kill
a man who's lovelorn?
A man's life depends
on that flower.
What's a "hamanasu” flower?
There's very red flower here.
This'll be all right.
It's called a carnation in this town.
Look, hand this flower
to that beautiful lady in there.
You have a keen eye
for women's beauty.
She's prettier than
those I loved.
I see.
She's just like
an image of "hamanasu."
I'll act as Cupid.
You've had me and now
you feel better, right?
I do, but my wallet
feels worse.
Lay me.
I'll give you a discount.
I haven't had
a customer for 2 days.
Not me. Get another sucker.
- Get something to eat.
- Thanks.
Did you give
that flower to her?
She wants to thank you,
but she's too shy to see you.
Order something for us.
Waitress,
take my boss' order.
What do you want?
I don't need you, chick.
What's the big idea,
dirty driver?
Do you have champagne?
No champagne for truck drivers.
Yoko, dear.
Hello, Jonathan.
This is for you.
All of them?
Don't care. All of them
are yours, Yoko.
They're all pilfered. Damn it!
Thank you very much,
Jonathan.
I'll eat them
with my friends.
I don't want to eat
with these fags.
Filthy ape with loose bowels!
Pipe down!
Momo.
This man told me
about you.
I didn't know
you're in love with me.
How romantic!
I like carnations.
- Carnations?
- So pretty.
Let's start, Okyo.
Momo, when you get back
to Kawasaki, let's have a talk.
I made a mistake.
Are you Momojiro Hoshi?
I'm "Draon" of Shimonoseki.
I came from Kyushu to race you.
All right. I'll take you on.
- How much?
-It's up to you.
300,000 yen.
That's chicken feed.
But it's enough for you.
Stop! Stop, President!
I don't want to die!
I'm still young!
Damn you!
Drink if you have time.
Step aside, losers.
Dragon, you made it.
I knew you'd easily win.
Hey, First Star,
drink with us.
My boss didn't lose the race.
I stopped him.
You talk too much.
We can't make excuses.
I'm..
... the loser.
Bravo, First Star!
You're a good loser.
Senkichi, your pants are wet.
You pissed, eh?
Please drink, Momo.
You, too.
I won't lose next time.
I'm sorry, Boss. I made
you lose 300,000 yen.
I don't care.
It's chicken feed.
You're rich.
Money can't make you happy.
Right?
Could be.
But some people are sad
because they have no money.
What do you mean by that?
Now I see.
Boss, she's broke.
The best way to get her is money.
I know.
I've known for a long time.
I want one more.
Let's play,
"Kill the Dragon" with this.
You won't be welcomed
by girls.
Attach these to the inside of your truck.
Neon lights.
Neon lights?
Good idea, You convinced me
I'll be moved to tears.
You're crazy.
Don't make me laugh.
Come.
What do you want?
Say it! I'm busy!
You want to give me the brush-off?
I misjudged you.
Why are you angry?
Don't grumble like a woman.
Like a grumbling woman?
You can call me anything.
Well, goodbye.
Did you call me out
to say goodbys?
Goodbye! I'll leave
you forever.
We were pals.
We talked all night
in the snow.
We talked about how to sell you
as No. 1 truck driver in Japan.
That's why I took you to brothels
and treated you to drinks.
Money is nothing!
Don't talk nonsense!
You like that lousy tramp!
Damn it!
Do you think our friendship
is nothing?
"My darling, Yoko"?
"I be moved to tears"? Nonsense!
Are you insulting Yoko?
If so, I'll never forgive you.
All right! Let's fight
to end our friendship!
Come on, First Star!
Stand up!
Jellyfish!
You fool! You know
nothing of life!
Your left hook is best, Boss.
Really great.
I'm glad you shook off
that jealous old man.
Jonathan didn't act
like that before.
Police are all power freaks.
He's just warped.
Maybe he was a stool-pigeon.
He has a sly face.
Idiot!
Jonathan's a pro.
You're just a greenhorn!
Get down and cool your head.
I didn't mean to insult him.
I respect you, Boss.
He's so cold.
MOTEL MOMOZONO
What's wrong?
Where's Momo?
He dumped me.
Get in and stop crying.
Cheer up!
I'll talk to Momo about you.
- Are you sure?
- Of course.
Thank you.
I was wrong about this.
My boss asked me to give them
to a pretty girl in the eatery.
He actually meant Yoko.
But you're prettier to me.
Later I got hell from my boss.
Hey, bring wine!
Can't you hear me?
Jonathan, what happened
to "First Star"?
He doesn't get drunk
that easily.
I don't care.
Ask the moonfaced bum..
He came here alone.
What's the matter?
Bring wine!
Oh, you're pumping gas.
Now I understand.
I didn't know.
Any woman'd pick him.
He's skillful and a nice guy.
Yoko, you have a good eye for men.
Bravo for both of you!
Don't get the wrong idea.
Don't touch me!
You sold yourself,
I was wrong about you!
Take it all!
You're a fool, Momo!
You got the wrong idea!
Pipe down!
Because of me and Midori here,
Yoko went to the motel.
While I was having
Midori four times...
...some thief stole my clothes.
That's why Yoko came to the motel
to bring my lover's clothes.
Why didn't you say so first?
You're always careless.
The money!
What's so funny?
He's wrong again.
He's senile now!
Yoko!
Forgive me.
I offered this money.
Please accept this for me.
Stop it.
If I accept that money,
I won't be able to accomplish my aim.
First Star, if you're a real man
take back that money!
Shut up! Don't butt in!
Let's fight!
I'll call the police.
Don't! It's between drivers!
Brother, stop fighting!
Stand aside!
Brother!
Did you come
from Kyushu to fight?
We haven't settled this.
Those two are brother and sister?
That man you're in love with
is strong and good.
I like him.
Forget about him, Brother.
Make Mom happy...
Force him to marry you
if you have to.
You're a shrew.
He'll be good for you.
I had the wrong idea, Brother.
Actually, I don't like him.
You're a fool.
I'm thirsty.
Let's get dressed
and get some beer.
Hello, little girl,
who put you here?
Daddy.
Where's your daddy?
Went shopping.
What's that?
"Please take care
of this child.
"Her name is Yumi Terayama.
Please raise her."
Momo, she's been abandoned.
What'll we do?
Take her to the police?
The police'll send her
to an orphanage.
Lousy father!
A parent must raise his child,
even if he has to steal.
I'd take her in, but...
I'll take her.
You have seven kids already.
Seven or eight.
Makes no difference.
What's one more?
Your hands are dirty.
I'll take it for you.
I's tasty. Eat more.
How could her father abandon
such a cute girl?
- A foundling?
- Kojiro!
I'm Konosuke.
Konosuke and you all,
help her.
Yumi'll be a member
of the Matsushida family.
She's your sister.
We must live helping
each other.
Momo, you better get married.
Don't you have a girl in mind?
"I'll be moved to tears."
Stop joking.
You should marry a good-natured woman.
I'm lucky.
You're my superiors daughter,
but you respect me.
My father was a police chief.
He told me a woman
should be reserved.
I married a man socialy
far below me.
But we're leading a good life
because I'm reserved.
He was of the lowest rank.
What made you become
a truck driver, Okyo?
You think it's a man's job?
When I think about it,
it was probably just a woman's pride.
I got married at 16.
Two years later,
we bought a truck
and looked forward
to our future.
Then my husband
was crushed to death
by the truck.
How?
He got under the truck
to change a tire,
It fell off the jack.
I resented it.
But I didn't hate the truck.
We worked hard to buy it.
I decided to drive it for him.
But I'm planning to sell it now.
You quit?
I'm a woman.
After the next trip...
I'll go back to Kyushu
in my brother's truck.
- Hello!
- Yoko!
No work because of rain?
You team up again?
Momo said he couldn't
live without me.
You two seem like a couple.
Don't think I'm a fag.
Give me
some European-style dishes.
Boiled vegetables
and pork soup!
I'll have the same.
Another special.
And coffee.
She likes me...
Just as I thought.
Stop jumping the gun.
Brother.
Okyo.
I was shocked to learn
you're his sister.
You're like him.
You're both reckless.
Okyo'll disappear from me today.
I must propose now.
Okyo.
Should I call her, "Kyoko"?
Okyo, please marry me.
Okyo, I'm a useless guy.
I'll fail no matter what I do.
I was kicked out of school
and the army.
I failed as an actor.
But no one will love you
more than I do.
Not even Momojiro.
I swear I'll make you happy.
Please, Okyo!
Please many
I'll go anywhere you want.
Hello, Gailant!
I heard you.
You're a good actor.
"Please Okyo!
Please marry me."
You're not fit for her.
Her brother is "Dragon".
He'll beat you up.
He said he was once an actor,
but he was
a stripper's assistant,
Stop it! Shut up!
What's funny?
He asked his girl to marry him.
Is that funny?
Not to me!
It's nothing to be ashamed of.
Okyo, isn't that so?
I'm a failure.
Cheer up!
Senkichi, thank you.
I gladly accept your proposal.
know I'm not worthy,
hut please make me your wife.
I'm glad.
Take care of her.
I think you lost
a very nice girl.
Go to her.
Go to Okyo.
Good luck!
I hope you'll get
a nice girl.
Here comes Momo!
Fill it up!
- She's a peach.
- Is she?
It's a tip. Take it.
It's chicken feed.
Hey, boys, he gave us a tip.
Let's thank him.
Fall in!
Thank you, Sir!
Thanks,
That was a great help.
Shall I wait?
You don't have to.
I'll take a train.
I see.
She's a rich man's daughter.
“Nebuta Festival"!
I wish I could dance there.
I used to dance.
On the night of the festival,
we kissed each other,
didn't we?
You were so eager.
You were so eager
my lips swelled.
Daddy! Daddy!
Daddy?
Momo, she must've come
from Aomori.
Maybe she's been there.
Maybe we can find
her father here.
Momo, let's bring her to Aomori.
And let her dance.
Aren't you happy?
I suppose she danced
with her daddy last year.
I'll take you
to the Star Festival in Sendai.
It's a great festival, too.
Yumi!
You're Yumi!
Her father was killed
by an explosion in the tunnel.
He was blown to pieces.
We had to collect him
in a basket.
Look, Yumi. Do as I do.
Uncle, what's this?
I guess the reason
why Terayama left her
in a truck.
He might've hoped
another driver
would take care of her.
Driver?
A long-distance driver.
His licence was suspended for six months
for being overweight
and speeding.
He couldn't pay the installments.
He got sick,
and his wife ran away.
He told me there was
a mean traffic cop.
The cop was very strict.
He wanted to get promoted.
Who was he?
I forgot.
But his nickname was
"The Devil's weight-examiner
"of Hanamaki. "
The Devil's Weight-examiner?
The weight-examiner!
He was Kinzo Matsushita,
a fraffic cop.
I want to hang him!
Don't blame yourself,
Jonathan.
What's done is done.
A man can't understand
unless he acts as others do.
When I was a cop...
I regretted that people
didn't obey the laws.
But I now know if drivers obey
the laws, they can't live.
Your license!
Six tons overload.
Get out!
Damn! I'll be suspended.
How heavy is your load?
Eighteen tons.
I'll have to be a laborer.
I'm sorry, Officer.
Come!
I'm sorry. Let me off!
Hey, you guys! Never mind
the lousy cops! Go!
I'll be responsible.
Everybodym take off.
I'll handle this.
Mommy, Room No. 3?
Kimie!
Darling!
It's coming!
What's up?
An ambulance!
We need an ambulance.
Easy! This is an hospital.
The baby's big.
It's healthy.
This is the eight child.
Actually Number Nine
because there's Yumi.
We'll have a dozen soon.
No more, thank you.
No more love-making.
Momo, you should have kids.
I have no field
to sow my seeds in.
Your field, Momo.
It's about farming.
Mrs. Matsushita, this is Yoko
from the restaurant.
Favor me from now on.
Momo,
you have a very good field.
I was surprised, but I'm glad
you weren't hurt bad.
You have a cute baby.
We must be the go-betweens
for his marriage.
Leave it to us.
It's too soon.
Uncle, when do we go
10 the Star Festival?
The festival's being held today.
It's beautiful.
I feel relaxed
for the first time in years.
You like festivals?
Why ask such a question.
You know I do.
Maybe you don't know,
but I know all about you.
Don't try to hide it.
Hide what?
Never mind. I'll keep it
in my heart.
Looking at Yumi, a woman said,
"She looks like your husband."
Husband?
She meant you.
Me?
She asked me,
"How long have you been married?"
It was embarrassing.
People are apt to think
we're man and wife.
Let'em think so,
my husband.
Okay. Shall we, a family of three,
have a nice meal?
All right, hubby.
Akira!
What are you doing here?
I've been thinking of us
while I've been working here.
I found we weren't defeated
by money at all.
But by ourselves.
Let's start over.
Go back to a life where we have
to live with sixty percent
of my salary?
We have to. You killed a man
by running over him.
That's whu I've paid for three years.
I can't pay the 60 million yen
indemnity in my whole life.
The man was rich.
One day, I brought money
to the family.
The victim's son said,
"This much won't even pay
for a night's drinking in Ginza. "
That's what he told me.
What an insult!!
Do I have to live like that?
I can't stand it!
Listen, Yoko.
I decided to take a tuna boat
at Shimokita at noon tomorrow.
I'll never come back to Japan.
I wanted to see you
and beg your forgiveness.
Because of me, you changed
your course of life completely.
I feel guilty. I want you
to find a nice man
and start over.
I think you can be happy.
- Goodbye.
- Wait!
You're going to run from trouble
for the rest of your life?
I've made up my mind.
Goodbye.
Yoko.
Yoko,
I have something important
to tell you.
Please listen.
"Of course."
Please accept
this "hamanasu" flower.
"How beautiful!"
This flower tied us
to each other.
"Do you remember?"
Marry me.
Oh, Momo, you've come early.
The flowers are beautiful.
Where's Yoko?
Yoko.
I've come to ask you
something important.
Please listen.
Please acceot this "hamanasu."
What's up?
Hold me!
Do anything to me.
Yoko!
What's up?
What happened?
I don't care
what happens to me.
Calm down.
Tell me what's wrong.
I don't care what happens.
I had...
...a sweetheart.
He's going to leave Japan today.
I won't see him again.
Who is it?
He was my classmate
in middle school.
When I was studying
to be a nurse...
He was working
at an automobile repair shop.
We promised to marry.
Don't lie! You went Into
your mansion in Tokyo.
You're wrong!
I took money to them.
Money?
He killed the head of the family.
He fell asleep while driving.
The victim was a VIP.
Akira worked hard
and continued to pay.
One day he brought money,
and the victim's son
threw it away.
He said it wouldn't even pay
for a night's drinking.
Since then he lost
his will to pay.
He quit the repair shop.
Nobody can accuse him.
The employees of the repair shop
were forced to work overtime.
That's why he fell asleep
at the wheel.
He's like us truck drivers.
Go to him, I'll drive you.
- It's too late.
- No!
It'll take eight hours
to get to Shimokita.
'I make it in three yours.
Forget it. We already
said goodbye.
Don't be silly!
You have to start over again.
Come on!
Hey, you In that eleven-tonner,
pull over!
Pull over!
Shut your big mouth!
We're in a hurry!!
Out of the way, flatfeet!
You're blocking the road!
You okay?
Start all over again
with him!
Two and a half hours.
A new record.
Don't cry.
Men don't like weeping girls.
Thank you.
Akira!
Yoko!
Akira, don't go!
We have to start over again.
Let's work to make a go of it.
Yoko, why did you come here?
We mustn’t run.
Let's face It
and go on with our lives.
Face it?
THE END