- Hello?
- Hello.
Yamada, can you talk?
Yeah. What's the matter?
I don't feel well.
Really? A cold?
I think so.
I have a fever.
My head hurts, I can't even
go to a convenience store.
That's bad.
Yamada, I suppose...
You're still at work, can you buy
something for me on your way home?
I haven't eaten today.
Really? I'm at work now...
but I was just about to leave.
Well then, since you asked...
Yeah, less than an hour.
See you soon.
It's open.
Mamo, are you okay?
I'll make dinner.
Thank you.
Yamada, don't.
It's okay. This wasn't
sorted correctly.
Don't worry about me, just eat.
Listen...
What?
Can you leave now?
- Uh?
- Listen...
- Thanks for helping.
- It's fine, I can stay.
It's fine, really.
Wait, wait...
- Will you be fine?
- I'm going to sleep. Thanks, Yamada.
I just noticed... when did Mamo
stopped calling me by my first name?
[What is love?]
Uh?
What are you doing?!
Fine.
Just get on a taxi, I'm coming.
It'll be 2000 Yen to get here.
Not the Koshu Highway...
take the Inokashira exit.
Yeah.
Takaido, the apartment
complex on the left.
The left.
Okay... see you.
- Nakahara...
- Yes?
Go buy some beer.
Sure.
- Here.
- Oh, she sent you. Thank you.
Thank you.
- I bought beer.
- Thanks.
I'm going.
- Are you going home?
- Everyone alread left.
Ah, the door is
unlocked... don't knock.
Don't wake up her mom,
or you'll be in trouble.
See you.
Wait... why are you leaving?
Fool.
Guilty as charged.
- Nakahara left.
- I know.
So what?
I feel bad for him, it looks
like you kicked him out.
- Whatever, it's fine.
- But...
Are you hungry?
Yes!
I made Udon for Mamo,
but I didn't eat.
- There's some Chikuzenni my mom made.
- Yes please!
"I got a cold, come here and
make me dinner"?! Is he for real?
And he throws out a girl in the middle
of the night. He's got some nerve.
That's not what happened, Yoko.
He never asked me
to make him dinner.
He only asked me to
buy something for him.
He had a fever of
almost 40 °C.
I couldn't just leave.
Listen, if you always act subservient,
the relationship roles are settled.
He'll keep taking
advantage of you.
Here.
And stop wasting your
time on that Little Lord.
I'm diving in.
Woah, this is delicious!
Do you want some? The leftovers?
No need to share,
you'll miss out.
Hey.
- Yes?
- Finish eating and let's go to bed.
Okay.
[to: Tanaka Mamoru]
[good night]
[take care of yourself]
What's the point?
I'm not Mamo's girlfriend.
- See you!
- Bye bye.
Friend of the bride?
- More or less.
- More or less?
How do you know her?
She's the friend of a friend...
we ate dinner once together.
Same.
The concept of friendship
is a fuzzy one, isn't it.
Indeed.
That's how I meet Tanaka Mamoru.
Nothing special.
Two people chatting at an
mutual acquaintance's party.
- Here.
- Thanks.
I'm Tanaka Mamoru.
Yamada Teruko.
I'll call you Teru.
So... you'll be Mamo.
- Oh, sorry. Cheers.
- Cheers.
"Beautiful hands",
I thought that time.
Yes, please fill that in.
If you send it back to us...
we'll send you a gift.
On Fridays, there's a 90% chance
that Mamo will message me.
It has been 5 months, and at this point
think I understand him quite well.
Yamada.
Yamada!
- Yes?
- Do you have a minute?
You keep missing deadlines
and making mistakes.
You weren't like this before.
I'm sorry.
Please be more careful.
Got it.
Good job today.
See you.
- See you.
- Take care.
I got used to kill
time at the office...
so I could answer immediately
whenever he called me.
Well, it's normal to
be wrong sometimes.
Let's eat.
Hello?
Dinner?
I haven't eaten yet.
I had overtime today.
I'm on my way home,
and super hungry.
Uh? Sure!
Yeah it's fine.
I'll write when I'm there.
Bye.
- Thanks for helping me that day.
- It's nothing. Did you sleep?
Yeah.
Take something you
like, it's on me.
- Really?
- Yeah. Grilled crab, or blowfish.
The blowfish though.
Do you think it's real?
- Heard you're busy at work.
- It's the end of the month.
- Today wasn't bad, though.
- That's great.
To be honest, magazines layout...
it's always the same stuff.
You could do a quick job
and go home for the weekend.
But it's my job, so
I want to do it well.
That's right.
In this field, you
never stop to learn.
But you look like someone
that has good eye.
I still wish I could
do even better.
When I'm 33 I'll quit and
become a pro baseball player.
You said you wanted to
be a shrine carpenter!
Shrine carpenter?
- Did I say that?
- Yes!
Shrine! It's even harder
than normal carpenter!
- Pro baseball is hard, too!
- Everyone knows that!
Let this child dream.
Here's my dream: a 33
years old debutant!
From publishing. An
incredibile career change!
That's silly.
- Have you choosen?
- Yeah.
So...
Mackerel, fried eggplant...
and a bottle of shochu.
Not a bottle!
But you said anything I liked!
If you get drunk you
won't be able to go home.
- Excuse me!
- Coming!
Mackerel.
- And grilled eggplant.
- Fried.
Beer for me, and a
glass of shochu, right?
- A glass then.
- Okay.
I don't get why
people like Yuba.
It's like the membrane
you get on hot milk.
Yeah.
- It's raining.
- Yeah.
You made me stay
out until morning.
What? You called me!
- Why did you come?
- Uh?!
- It's cold.
- Yeah...
No taxis.
None.
Should we go on the main street?
Oh, here's one!
- Yamada, let's go home.
- Uh?
- To Setagaya, please.
- Okay.
Good morning.
What are we eating?
For lunch.
Do you have plans
for the afternoon?
Why?
Let's go somewhere.
Hot?
Ah! It's hot!
Tasty?
When you're in love
in your late 20s...
"I like you, let's date"
is not said with words.
It starts like this, drop
by drop, not all at once.
Don't!
After that day, Mamo started
calling me almost everyday.
And when he calls,
I always say yes.
If I miss the last
train, I'll just stay.
Ugh.
- Mamo!
- Uh?
- What time?
- It's 10:30.
Don't you have to
work this afternoon?
- I have to go, too.
- Hey...
Let's go to the zoo.
- What about work?
- Deadline is tomorrow, I have time.
Let's shower together.
- Like this? Feels good?
- Yeah.
- It's perfect.
- It is?
Feels good.
- I may quit my job.
- Why?
I think...
It's not a good fit.
I see.
You'll be fine.
Freedom!
Freedom?
You can enjoy your
unemployment insurance.
At 33 I'll quit
to be a zookeeper.
More realistic that pro
baseball player, right?
What's the matter?
Why are you crying?!
- Dunno.
- That's crazy.
- Uh?
- What?
That's rude.
Mamo says he wants to quit
at 33 to be a zookeeper...
but what I wonder is if
I'll be part of that future.
At the time, I
really believed...
we were going to have a
great future together.
That's why I was crying.
But if I had said that, Mamo
would have laughed even more.
"I don't get it",
he would've said.
You know, I don't think I had
any expectation for my life.
But God, instead of
letting me dying early...
actually granted
my greatest wish!
Listen, God's will is not
something we can understand...
so stop with this nonsense.
Isn't that guy pretty hot?
You think so?
You don't? Someone strong,
that can protect you.
Is that so?
I've always liked slender guys,
slim but elegant, like a cat...
I think they're cuter.
Always? You're making that up.
Yoko, how do you
think we fall in love?
We say "my type is"...
but we're just looking back
at the people we've loved...
and grouping them into
made-up categories.
Falling in love is something that
happens in an instant, you just feel it.
It has nothing to
do with reason.
You're daydreaming. Be careful
at work, or you'll be fired.
Well... I was.
What? They fired you?!
- Yeah.
- Uh?
What are you gonna do?
You know, Yoko...
I think luck in love is inversely
proportional to luck in your job.
I don't want my love
fortune to decrease...
so I won't look for a new job.
You say some really
dumb things sometimes.
I'd rather think
about marriage...
than looking for a job.
Wait, did you tell him?
I haven't, but I did tell him
I was thinking about resigning.
"You'll be fine" he said.
"That's freedom"
Freedom?
Wait, are you dating?
Perhaps.
Perhaps?
Yamada!
You can throw that away.
I'm having lunch.
Thanks.
- Cheers.
I used to come here
during my lunch break.
You did?
It's so silly.
Uh?
Nowadays, to be
fired for a man...
is very unusual.
I guess it is.
Honestly, I'm jealous.
Why?
Looking at you...
I realized I've never met
a person I truly loved.
I suppose it's not uncommon.
To never meet someone
you really really love.
You think so?
But yeah...
It's probably the reason our
society is still functional.
Woah, that's mean!
To be honest, I don't live just
to make the society function.
See, you're silly.
My mind has exactly two modes.
"In love" and "whatever".
So I don't care much
about anything...
except the person
I'm in love with.
What about yourself?
I'm getting married next month.
But I'll keep working.
Marriage is not
forever, nowadays.
I guess.
Donabe, stewpot...
for 2 people.
Ugh.
Marriage, uh?
Should have bought more beer.
- I'll go.
- It's fine, I wasn't asking.
Don't you want to have
a drink? I do. I'll go.
What are you doing?
It's 2 am, just
take a bath already.
Don't worry. How many
bottles? One? Two?
Same brand?
You can say anything to me.
Ask me to do this and
that... anything you need.
You don't have to hesitate, or
be polite, when you're with me.
I'm going.
Mamo what's the
matter? It's only 7am.
I have to leave,
I've got a meeting.
And we're leaving together.
What? If we leave now,
you'll be there at 8am.
Don't you start at 10?
Not today, I've got
a packed schedule.
You didn't mention
this meeting yesterday.
- Why didn't you tell me yesterday?
- Here, coffee.
Can I sleep a little bit more?
I'll lock the door when I leave.
I don't want people here
when I'm away, you know that.
The other day I cleaned and did the
laundry and you didn't say anything!
Fine, let's talk about my day.
You want to know about my meeting?
My magazine isn't doing well,
apparently it has too many words.
They want more images.
Casual stuff, like articles
about gourmet restaurants.
Get a young photographer, doing
street photography, and so on.
So we've been fighting.
It's not clear what's
the best way forward...
Each one of us was told to
come up with 5 new ideas.
After that day, Mamo
stopped calling me.
It looked like I wasn't going to
be part of his future, after all.
Since even just one month
after that day at the zoo...
I already wasn't part of it.
Teru, I'm leaving.
Wait, what?
You asked me to spend
New Year's Eve together!
That's why I'm here.
That was my plan.
But I was invited to a coworker's
party, it was so sudden.
Sudden? What does that mean?!
And Nakahara?
What about Nakahara?
He did come for you.
- He's inside.
- Is he?!
He's not coming with you?
He's staying here,
he'll be fine.
And he's not alone,
my mom is there.
And you can stay, too!
Well, it's time for
me go to. See you.
Wait! Are you really leaving?!
Hello there.
I'm very sorry.
You took the trouble to come.
Here, for you.
You shouldn't have!
Thank you very much.
"Top-grade sake".
- Should we open it?
- Yeah!
Let's open it!
That Yoko.
If only she was as
nice as you two...
my life would've been easier.
That's right.
People like her live a
peaceful life, though.
Not at all.
That kind of the
personality is the worst.
When she was in kindergarten....
we went to a department
store to buy a dress.
They had this cute
polka-dot dress.
I said: "You wanted a
dress like that, right?"
"I don't!" she said.
She started to cry.
She was disappointed that
I could see through her.
We ended up going home
without buying anything.
Sounds like something
Yoko would do.
See?
You know...
I wanted her to be a child
who can express her desires.
Well, she grew up
looking at me, after all.
- Delicious, thanks for this.
- You're welcome.
And cheers to Yoko, too.
Even if she's so selfish...
she has friends like you.
Please keep looking after her.
Well... goodnight.
Happy New Year.
- Happy New Year.
Why Gyoza, though?
It's chinese food, after all.
So what?
I dunno, ask Yoko.
Whatever.
Teruko...
Do you ever start feeling
lonely all of a sudden?
Sometimes, when I'm
drinking alone at home...
I suddenly realize
I feel lonely.
Oh... yeah.
And you'd like to make
small talk with someone.
Like "there's nothing on TV",
or "I saw a puppy today".
Yeah, like that.
You know...
I want to be the person Yoko can
call anytime she feels like that.
Honestly it would be fine
even if it's not always me.
Like...
just when no one
else is available.
"Oh, right, there's Nakahara!"
Even that would be fine.
Nakahara... that's pathetic.
You think so?
Really?
As for me... I'd like
to become one with Mamo.
I'd like to be one with him.
If that's not possible, his
mother... or his sister.
Or just a cousin!
Teruko, this is pathetic, too.
We sound like we're in a
meeting of the stalkers league.
What are you talking about?!
- Soon.
- Yeah.
I just want to be happy.
Uh?
Yeah...
Spring came, and Mamo
still hadn't contacted me.
You have experience in
a reception position...
that's great.
I did some part-time
in high school.
Great.
We get a lot of new customers this
time of the year, so be polite.
Got it.
- Can you do weekends and holidays?
- I can.
I used to come here to climb.
Sorry.
[Mamoru]
Sorry, I have to go.
- What?
- I'm sorry!
Wait a minute!
Hello?
I'm a little busy, why?
This is Teruko Yamada.
This is Sumire Tsukakoshi.
- Good evening.
- Nice to meet you.
Sumire is a cool name.
You think so? Thanks.
What do you do?
Administration in
an arts cram school.
Arts cram school?
So... how did you meet?
It was... end of last year?
- November?
- Yeah.
A mixer party. At
our age! Laughable.
Maribu... oh, Maribu is a
former pupil of my cram school.
He said "we don't have
enough people", so I went.
I was brough there by an intern,
everyone was like 20 years old.
That was mean. I'm 34. Well,
35 at the end of this month.
I was the oldest! Thank
god Tanaka was there.
Thank you for waiting.
Red tai carpaccio, and
the cheese selection.
Looks delicious! Let's eat!
Try this Red Tai. To die for!
- Incredible!
- Sublime!
Delicious.
- Wah, this Yuba is incredible!
- Really?!
So Teru, what do you do?
I'm not working right
now, isn't that great.
Really? That's cool.
Try some.
It's to die for!
Is it, uh?
- To die for!
- Isn't it?
- It is...
Oh, right... I'm
meeting a friend.
See you.
See you again, Teru.
Take care.
I'm going, then.
Why did you ask me to come?
No reason, it has
been a while.
I just wanted to have
a drink together.
Did it bother you?
It didn't.
She's your girlfriend?
It looks like you were
introducing me to your partner.
You've got a lover,
so why call me?
It's not like that.
You know...
You were acting weird.
No, don't say that.
Like a few weeks ago...
It was a little strange.
- Maybe I was too sensitive.
- Sorry, but...
I'm learning from Sumire.
As you saw she's not refined...
I feel comfortable around her.
See you.
Tsukakoshi Sumire...
Who's that?
Tsukakoshi Sumire.
Shabby underwear...
(Rapping)
Bad intestines...
Constipated all the time...
Smoking too much...
Black lungs, bad liver...
Dry back, always
feeling itchy...
but she can't scratch
because she's all stiff.
Even the pupils at her school...
spread weird rumors about her.
Having an affair with her boss.
And yet, I'm relieved.
She buys plants, but
they die right away.
Her balcony the
wreckage of a garden.
Cockroaches eggs from last
winter, hatching in her house!
Itchy back!
Serves you right!
You know...
you were acting pretty weird.
Serves you right!
Teru!
Teruko!
Coming!
It makes me so angry. Pathetic.
The way he acts... he reminds me
of my father, it's so irritating.
Your father?
You know, my mom...
was what in the old times
you'd have called a mistress.
- Really?
- Yeah.
So my father...
was more like an old man
who visits once in a while.
Once he showed my mom a picture
of his child at school sports day.
I wished he'd die.
- That much?
- Yeah.
And he looked down
on her, you know?
I can't look down on him?
My mom is the kind of woman who's
good for a man that is never home.
She always had a cold beer for him
in the fridge. Isn't that great?
Tasty?
A great thing about you...
is how diligently you starve
yourself when you're sad.
But please tell me when
you're planning to die.
I won't be able to
see Mamo if I die.
You're not even weird...
just plain creepy.
Anyway, to keep your
mind and body healthy...
you have to eat well, and work.
Let's see...
Teruko, you're next!
My dream is to be a
kindergarten teacher.
I love children, and
I'll be a great teacher.
Actually, you should get a
job with a lot of free time...
so you can spend it with Mamo.
Kindergarten teacher?
That's ridiculous!
- Come on!
- Yes.
Do you want one? I made it.
Hello?
Sumire?
What's the matter?
- Teru, here!
- Hello.
Good evening, Teru.
- So where do you come from?
- I'm from Tokyo.
Then I moved to Singapore.
- Where's Mamo?
- Takaka? I didn't call him.
You didn't?
Hello? Sorry for calling
you all of a sudden.
You're at work? Sorry.
It's not urgent, just...
I'm with Sumire right now.
Mamo!
Tanaka, why are you here?
Yamada called me.
Sumire, you told me to
invite Tanaka, right?
- Uh?
- Mamo, have a drink.
- Sit there?
- Sure.
- A new one.
- Uh?
- Ashtray.
- Ah, sure.
A White and a Red, please.
- Here!
- Put it there.
By the way, didn't you say
you had a holiday house?
Really?
We were talking
about a barbeque.
But not in the city, it's sad.
Like in the middle of Nature.
A place for summer trips?
It's not mine, a friend's
parents own it... near a lake.
We can use it if
we plan in advance.
Great! Let's go there then!
In Tanaka's holiday house!
No, no, it's not mine,
my friend's parents...
But you can borrow, right?
Next week! End of the month.
Uh... I'll ask my friend.
Teru, you're coming too, right?
I don't think...
If you don't come,
I won't either.
Yamada, please come! I'm
inviting my friends too.
- Okay, then.
- Huzzah!
It'll be super fun!
Let's bring fireworks!
I'm going home.
I'm sorry.
For what?
Nothing... forget it.
You liar.
I'm not a liar.
But sorry anyway.
It's fine either way.
- Yamada...
- What?
Are you going anywhere?
No beer... I'm buying some.
- No need.
- It's close.
- It's fine.
- But...
Yamada...
What?
Let's do it.
Give me a second.
You drank too much.
It's okay, let's stop.
Why though.
Whatever.
- You don't like me, uh?
- It's not that, come on.
That was a joke.
I've never been to
Nakameguro before.
Me neither.
I wouldn't go there
unless I had a reason to.
Actually, I never go anywhere
unless I have a reason to.
That relationship
was at a dead end.
- With Sumire?
- Yeah.
You know what I mean?
Not really.
I thought you were
that kind of man.
Uh?
Nothing.
I...
I'm not that cool.
Outstanding, fashionable,
or anything like that.
and I'm too thin.
Thin? What does that even mean?
I don't come across
as a kind person.
I'm not rich, and I can do my
job... but it's not that hard.
I don't think I'm the worst...
But if you divide society in
two: cool people, and not cool...
I would be in the
"not cool" group.
I guess.
Right?
Yeah.
That kind of man.
So why are you so nice to me?
- Nice?
- Yeah.
Like this evening.
You invited me to the
place where Sumire was.
That was just...
Well, you like her.
That's the reason.
I don't think I did fall
for her, I just said I did.
Is that so.
I thought so.
You weren't in love, you
just pretended to be.
Weird.
What's that.
I...
I'm being honest with
you, don't insult me.
Hear me?
- It hurts.
- Does it?
- It doesn't.
- Not funny.
What?
What's this?
Why are you hard now?!
I guess the Sake is gone.
- You're attractive, after all.
- After all?!
I knew you didn't
actually like her.
Someone like her? That's absurd.
- You think so?
- Yeah.
Since I'm enough for you, right?
Not Sumire... me.
Are you?
- What will you do?
- Mh?
What will you do?
Dunno.
Put her behind.
I will never forgive them.
Let's have fun anyway!
I'll prepare the meat.
Me too.
Nakahara, the charcoal.
Mamo rented an 8-seater...
but not everyone came.
Nakame's friend said "Was
it today? Sorry, I'm busy".
And he dodged Sumire.
Mamo just took the house
keys from his friend...
and didn't invite anyone else.
I think he wanted to
be alone with Sumire.
As for me, I wanted
to enjoy myself...
and I was in a summer trip mood.
And when I went to Yoko's
house to invite her...
Why should we get involved in his
attempt to woo a 30 y.o. woman?!
It'll be super fun, come on.
Nakahara, what about you?
Teru can't go there
by herself, right?
Are you coming?
- I'd prefer not to.
- Just go!
I don't want to.
I'm going.
So Nakahara was forced to come.
Just 4 people.
Done!
- So you're a photographer?
- Assistant, actually.
- So you have a lot of cameras?
- I guess so...
Not that many.
- How many?
- Like three.
How many?!
- Three.
- Isn't that a lot?
- Nakahara, you're pretty funny.
- Uh? How many is many?
- Well, 4 is many.
- Isn't that the same?!
No! 3 and 4 are very different!
- It's the same!
- It's not!
- It is!
- Meat is ready!
- And the vegetables.
Tanaka, this guy
is really weird.
- Why?
- I'm not weird!
- You are!
- I'm not.
You are. He said "I have
a lot of cameras...."
How many? I asked. He says 3,
but I think from 4 is many...
- But I don't know, and...
- Indeed.
Nakahara, explain...
Me? Why I have to explain?
This one is done.
- Here.
- Ouch, hot hot hot!
- Scary!
- Careful.
I'm out of meat.
Hot!
I'm in tears.
- The shrimps are delicious!
- Indeed.
- Did you try the chicken wings?
- Not yet.
The one with the stick that last
the longest will have good luck.
Go!
- Wait, she isn't your girlfriend?
- She is not.
I mean... I don't think
I'm allowed to say she is.
Uh? What do you mean?
Some relationships can only be
understood by the 2 people in them.
Right?
So...
you go to her when
she calls you...
and leave immediately
when she sends you away.
That's not a girlfriend,
she's just using you!
Now you're making it sound
like she's an awful person.
But she is!
Right?
You're just sleeping
together, aren't you?
I guess...
Ridiculous.
What? Am I wrong?
No, I think you're right.
Yeah, but...
Yoko is a kind person.
The fact she talks to someone like me,
even like that, it's enough for me.
So are you happy with this?
No, it's just...
You don't need to
worry about it.
Uh?
Why are you laughing?
Seriously, I'm talking
about your future.
Why do I have to talk
about this with you?
Why are you being so direct now?
Yoko isn't an awful
person, period.
She is awful.
- From what you said, she's awful.
- Okay, fine.
Uh?
Yoko is an awful woman.
End of the conversation.
Tanaka...
what do you think?
What's up with this guy?
You know, I think...
that not everyone can
express love in the same way.
Sometimes you're really in love,
so you can't say otherwise.
But if he's fine
with this, well...
Right, Nakahara?
Fine.
I'm making pasta.
You pissed me off.
So now I'll make
pasta for Nakahara.
I don't get it, what's this?
Tanaka, knives?
- Knives.
- Don't need a knife to make pasta.
- To cut the tomato.
- I didn't buy tomatoes.
We have asparagus!
Nakahara, we have asparagus.
Don't force yourself.
- Leave it.
- That's a waste.
Teru...
are you in love with Tanaka?
Uh? Why?
What do you like about him?
What are you talking about?
I'm not good at romance.
In the end for some reason I always
feel like I'm just doing it for myself.
- For yourself?
- Yeah.
We get along, so we go out...
but I feel I'm doing it just
because I like to socialize.
What do you mean?
Once I was going
out with this guy.
We would be on a date,
and I'd get hungry.
I'd say "I'm hungry" and
he'd reply: "I'm not".
But when he was hungry, then we'd
immediately go to a restaurant.
Uh? Just for that?
I wouldn't be bothered
by something like this.
It's not fine! It's detestable!
You think so?
But really...
that's the reason you and
Tanaka would make a good couple.
Why would you say that?
Hum...
Did you confess to Mamo?
- Yeah.
- Really?
- Just kidding.
- No, really.
I didn't, I'm serious.
Really?
- You really like him!
- No, no, I swear.
Okay, listen.
I really didn't.
After that trip, Sumire
often called me to hang out.
And every time, I invited Mamo.
But Mamo rarely called me.
Only Sumire called me.
And yet, I couldn't hate her.
- Good morning.
- Yo!
- Yo.
[Nakahara]
What did you want to tell me?
I think I stopped liking Yoko.
What?
I don't think I'll
see her again.
So maybe I won't see you either.
That's why I wanted to
have dinner together.
I don't get it.
Why did you stop liking her?
Well...
After that trip, I've
been thinking about it.
About what?
About me and Yoko.
I still don't get it.
That day Mamoru said:
"It's okay as long as
they're both fine with it".
- So?
- So...
I thought I was fine with it...
and same for Yoko.
And yet...
after what Sumire said
about it being awful...
It doesn't concern Sumire!
I'm not good enough for Yoko!
The other day I
suddenly remembered...
this story about a chinese
king I heard a long time ago.
- A king?
- Yeah.
He always had
unreasonable requests...
but his vassals didn't want to
defy him, so they went along.
His requests became
harsher and harsher...
to the point that they couldn't
tell if he was just torturing them.
As for me...
I thought the king
was being cruel.
But really...
now I think his vassals, who kept doing
what he asked, were even more cruel.
In other words...
I don't actually
understand it...
but I've been wondering
what love really is.
What was that?
What is love.
What is love, you ask.
Uh?
Listen...
You said you'd do anything for
Yoko, didn't you? Now you're scared?
You said that.
I want to be the person she
calls when she's lonely.
Even just that would be fine.
I said that.
There are people like you
and me who feel loneliness...
but Yoko doesn't.
That's why people like
us are attracted to her.
I'm sure Yoko also
feels lonely sometimes!
I don't think so.
Everyone does!
You're only saying this
so you can give up.
You think you're not going to get
her, just admit you're giving up!
That's right.
I'm not fine.
Everyone always
says "I'm fine"...
but honestly this is
too painful for me.
You see...
I love Yoko, I really do.
- Then you...
- Enough.
Enough!
That's it.
There's a limit, you know.
I'm free to decide to give up.
I'm going home.
It was nice to see you.
Fool.
You're a fool.
I just want to be happy.
Oh, shut up!
Hey!
Hi.
[Yoko]
- New hairstyle?
- Yeah.
A coworker said this
style suits me more.
What is it?
A man?
Yeah.
What about Nakahara?
Nakahara? I haven't
seen him lately.
He doesn't even
answer the phone.
Mom? Teru is here.
Can you bring something?
You are not coming in?
Listen...
You're okay with this?
With what?
You can't get in touch with
Nakahara, are you fine with that?
What? Why are you asking now?
My point is... you
treated him like dirt.
I feel bad for him.
It's your fault, why did you
ask him to go on that trip?
You don't care at all?
I don't get it, you invited
him in the first place.
You told him to come.
- He said yes.
- That's irresponsible!
He didn't want to come.
Nahakara really liked you.
So..?
Don't give me
that. You're awful.
What you're doing to Nakahara...
is no different from what
your father did to your mom.
Uh?!
When, exactly...
when did you meet my father?
You know nothing about him.
- What do you know?!
- I don't!
But you're not kind.
Listen... don't take it out with me just
because it didn't go well with Mamo!
You're just projecting!
Uh?! No, I'm not!
"I'll cherish him!"
"I'll always take
care of Mamoru!"
That has nothing
to do with this.
Why did you come here?
If you've only come to talk
about this silly stuff, leave.
Sorry I don't feel
down like you do.
It's not silly.
See you.
Wait!
What? You're not done yet?
Don't you ever feel lonely?
What?
I asked if you ever feel lonely!
Of course I do!
What kind of person
you think I am?
Whatever.
What was that.
Teru?
Want a rice cake?
Teruko?
Teruko!
Are you okay?
You look sad.
Do I?
Are you free later?
It's nothing, come on!
What are you worried about?
Humans are pretty good at this.
Keep yourself busy, and you'll
forget about him in no time.
Is that so?
For sure!
I'm divorced, you know.
And if I think about it now...
I have no idea why I even
loved him in the first place.
I don't even remember his face.
But I really love Mamo!
I love him!
See, you can said it out loud:
I'm in love with Mamo!
Fine, then.
He'll be with Sumire.
You're overthinking
it! Adults...
When I was young I
did overthink too!
Everyone does that.
Shut up.
- Hello?
- Hi.
Are you busy?
- Sorry, I don't feel well.
- Really?
Are you okay? A cold?
Probably.
Sorry... what did you need?
If it's about Sumire again...
maybe another time.
It's not.
I wanted to talk to you.
Uh?
I'm at your house.
Are you okay? Need
me to buy anything?
[Tanaka]
- Here.
- Thanks.
- I'll eat.
- Go ahead.
- What?
- Nothing.
- What?!
- Nothing!
You helped me that time,
when I had a fever.
- Do you remember?
- I do.
You made udon for me.
But...
Just the smell made me nauseous.
- Uh?! Why didn't you tell me?
- Yeah...
Sorry for bringing that up.
You know, that night...
I only had 327 yen
left to go back home.
I had to walk.
I'm joking. I went to a
friend's home and slept there.
Really? You should have
came back to my house!
Yeah.
Listen...
Let's not meet again.
I mean, we're not dating, so...
It's...
It's a little weird, you know.
Our relationship...
is strange.
- Strange?
- Yes.
We hang out with
Sumire, 3 people...
Isn't that weird?
But that's...
I know she's not great for me...
but I actually like Sumire.
She's unrefined...
she drinks too much,
and has bad skin.
I'm fine with that.
I like it.
I like her.
Okay?
Sumire was always saying:
"If Teru comes,
I'll be there too!"
That's why we were
always inviting you.
- So what?
- You know, Sakamoto...
- Yoko?
- Yeah, Yoko Sakamoto.
The girl Nakahara loves.
She called me.
- Yoko called you?
- Yeah.
"What you're doing
is nuts" she said.
That I was inviting you just
because I wanted to see Sumire.
She said I was nuts.
- When?
- Uh?
- When did she call you?
- The other day.
Maybe Nakahara
told her something.
- You think so?
- Yeah.
I only realized how awful
it was after she told me.
I didn't think at all
about how you'd feel.
But after thinking about it...
Well, I...
I see that when someone like you is
around, I act like a spoiled child.
I only realized
because they told me.
So...
Let's do this.
Let's stop meeting.
I'll try hard.
Woah, Mamo.
You sure are
confident, aren't you?
Uh?
Did you really think I'd be
in love with you forever?
You're really something.
I really liked you, and
you often called me...
so I was hoping we would
start a proper relationship.
When I fall in love, I'm really
into it. I'm that kind of person.
- But I've cooled down a long time ago.
- Really?
I think Yoko misunderstood the
reason I came to that summer trip.
I came because I wanted to be
introduced to your cool friend.
But he didn't even
come, what a shame.
Woah.
This is super embarassing.
I wasn't being arrogant, I only
said that because Yoko told me.
I see.
- That's embarassing.
- It is.
In a way, I'm glad.
This is great for me.
We can be friends.
You'd be great as a friend
that is not emotionally close.
I'm so glad.
I'm really happy you
don't actually love me.
Isn't it nice?
So introduce me
to some cool guy.
We could go out on a
double date, with Sumire.
I don't have a boyfriend...
So instead of saying we
shouldn't meet, help me find one!
Fine!
Let me try that.
Nice.
Your hands are so nice.
Your hands are so pretty.
What? Is that a good thing?
Hey.
How?
I looked up your name
and found out about this.
[Teruko]
And this one...
- Cheese.
- Cheese!
And seedless tomato.
- One of cheese.
- Yeah, one.
- Chees is good.
- It is.
Hey, look.
- Hey, Kanbayashi!
- Good evening.
- Hello.
I'm Sumire.
- Yamada Teruko.
- Hey.
This is Kanbayashi.
Nice to meet you.
Excuse me.
You really don't
have a girlfriend?!
- I don't.
- How's that possible?!
Is that by choice?
No, he's just so busy!
He even sends his laundry
to his parent's house!
- Really?!
- That's not the reason!
Money is more important
than time for me.
I see.
Bathroom.
Come on, Yamada...
- Don't stare at him.
- I'm not!
Bathroom!
- Are you ok?
- Yeah.
- Should we order something?
- I'm good.
- Please.
- Thanks.
Should we split, later?
Uh?
I think...
Mamo wants to be
alone with Sumire.
I see.
Well... okay then.
See you later then.
Are you really okay with this?
With what?
Going this far just so
you can keep seeing him?
Yeah.
But why?
Is that love?
Love?
What's that?
Even I don't undestand the
nature of my obsession with Mamo.
This is not romantic love.
It can't be love.
But it doesn't matter anymore.
Uh?
Where are you two going?
To another bar. See you!
Why?
Me and Mamo are not one yet.