TOEl COMPANY LTD.
SEVENTEEN NINJA
(Jushichinin no Ninja )
Planning by: AMAO Kanji
Screenplay by: IKEGAMI Kaneo
Photography by: WASHIO Motoya
Music by: KABURAGI So
Assistant Director: HONDA Tatsuo
Fight Choreography: TANI Toshio
CAST:
SATOMI Kotaro
MISHIMA Yuriko - SUSUKIDA Kenji
HARADA Koshiro - SHINAGAWA Ryuji
ABE Kusuo - HANAZAWA Tokue
OKUNI Ikko - KAGA Kunio - HORI Masao
AZUMA Chiyonosuke - KONOE Jushiro
OTOMO Ryutaro
Directed by: HASEGAWA Yasuto
EDO CASTLE - DECEMBER, 1631
Elder...
So you are here.
I am Chief Jingoza of the Third Iga Group,
serving the Shogunate.
This is top secert.
Come closer.
His Excellency's illness
has been determined
to be incurable.
He has 20 days left at best.
It will soon be Lord lemitsu's
time to reign as Shogun.
We must avoid any current upheavals.
Where do we go?
To Sumpu.
Sumpu...
Are you reffering to Lord Tadanaga?
Lord Tadanaga is His Excellency's son
and the younger brother to Lord lemitsu.
He is trying to bypass
Lord lemitsu to become Shogun.
He is gathering pacts
from the Tozama lords.
Upon His Excellency's death,
he plans to raise an army and attack Edo.
If the Edo Castle should go up in flames,
the country will be in upheaval.
Jingoza, we must nip it at it's bud.
Go to Sumpu with your group of Iga ninja
and steal the compact
before His Excellency dies.
Yes, sir.
Upon His Excellency's death...
we will provide our solid proof...
And force Lord Tadanaga
to commit suicide.
Is that clear?
There is only one reign
in this country for us.
Do you understand your assignment?
Needless to say...
Per the Iga Code under
the Shogunate Agents...
I shall abide by the order given to me.
Jihei!
Take four men with you
along the Koshu Highway.
Enter Suruga via
Kajikizawa and Fujigawa.
Shinsoku, Denpachi, Koroku, and Yaichi...
Follow Jihei's orders.
Saheiji!
Take the Atsuki Highway
to go to Ashigara.
Enter Suruga via Takenoshita.
Gensaku, Ittetsu, Magosuke...
You men follow Saheiji's orders.
Takei!
Take the Atsumi Highway to go to Ito.
Enter Suruga via Shuzenji and Izu.
Genshin, Umenosuke, Shume...
You men follow Tahei's orders.
Bunzo and Hanshiro who are left...
You will accompany me.
We will enter Suruga through
the backroads of Hakone.
Kozue, stay back in Edo to
prepare for the unexpected.
Follow the Elder's orders.
Be prepared for His Excellency's death.
You will probably have to
dash over to Suruga to notify us.
After the battle in Osaka...
Our Iga group of 60 men
has been reduced to just 16.
They say sacrifices must
be made for the future.
But we have lost a lot of
men over the past 17 years.
They were all invaluable men, too.
They were all your comrades.
Your parents, siblings, and relatives.
Even if it comes down to the last man...
We must fullfill our duties.
In the honor of the Iga ninja!
Let us meet in Sumpu!
Let's go!
MAIN WING
INUI GATE
That is the ninja
that was captured earlier.
He tried to make his
way through the outer moat.
They caught another one at the
Southeast Gate disguised as a vendor.
INUI GATE
FIRST GATE
It's another Shogunate ninja.
He will be taken to
Kimon (Demon's Gate ) Tower, too.
I don't like that place.
SECOND GATE
KIMON (DEMON'S GATE) TOWER
That's the fourth one.
We have Sir Saiga on our side.
He knows how the ninja operate.
Rain?
Bunzo and Hanshiro...
Shinsaku and Yoichi
haven't come back yet.
I ordered them to sneak
into the Main Wing tonight.
Chief...
Was there a calculated reason for it?
Chief!
No... there was none.
There was no calculated reason behind it.
Is the pact safe?
Men!
Remove that folding screen!
It will become a good
hiding spot for the ninja!
Increase the candlestands!
Leave the sliding doors open!
Keep the fires at a distance!
It will make you drowsy!
Stop!
Close the path by Southeast Tower!
That's their only way out!
Are things under control?
All the commotion in the castle is gone.
It appears they are dead...
Ishiwaki Shinsoku and Isshiki Yaichi...
They were both valuable men.
Cheif, the castle samurai should
have their guards down now.
Perhaps we should
send in someone else now.
It will be useless.
To get to this inner
moat of the Main Wing...
We have to cross this
outer moat from the Ote Gate.
Even if we succeed in
getting into the castle...
We will be caught by the castle guards.
If they close the path by Southeast Tower,
we will be cornered.
It's geographical features and defenses...
Makes it an impregnable fortress.
There is no way out alive.
Our enemy ninja is well aware of that.
Damn Saiga!
Saiga Magokuro of the
Negoro ninja from Kishu...
Lord Suruga has a
fine ninja in his service.
We are up against someone
who knows all the ninja tricks.
Our ordinary tactics won't work.
Chief...
Knowing that, you sent
those two men in there tonight?
I lost six men in all...
They were all excellent ninja.
But there was no other method.
Even if Saiga may not fall for it...
The castle guards may.
I'm hoping the Suruga
samurai will take the bait.
Tomorrow morning,
Narita Uji will transfer the pact
to the Kimon Tower.
Any objections?
The ninja would never
suspect that we would
transfer the valuable pact in this crisis.
Even if they were to
make it to the Main Wing,
they will panic if
they can't find the pact.
Saiga, what do you want?
Pardon my rudeness.
Please do not move the
pact from the Main Wing.
Did you eavesdrop?
Saiga, who do you
think you are speaking to?
Refrain!
You don't seem to realize it.
You are taking their bait.
Bait?
What are you talking about?
Those Shogunate ninja
can't make it to the Main Wing,
so as a desperate measure,
they have caused those riots
to intimidate you into moving
the pact to somewhere else.
Hold your tongue!
You are just a greenhorn!
How dare you insult us!
Forgive me for my insults, but...
Stop! Saiga.
It just goes to show
your background doesn't it?
You don't seem to understand
the hardships of the others.
All that matters to you is the pact.
But we must also think
about our lord's safety.
If more of these riots should
take place and the guards get
preoccupied with the pact,
then the Shogunate ninja could
very well get to the lord.
Then we will be faced with a crisis.
The death of all of us
here won't suffice as apolpgy.
Chamberlain, are you not prepared to die?
Saigo!
If you are not prepared to die
or to have the lord lose an arm
or leg, then you will never
accomplish your mission.
Saiga, refrain!
How dare you!
Ignore him.
A hired ninja would
not be able to understand.
In any event,
we are moving the pact to
Kimon Tower tomorrow.
I will send 15 or 16 of our most skilled
swordsmen to Kimon Tower.
Stop!
That's fine! Go to Ninomaru!
Farmer Jisaku and eleven
others from Udo village are here
to make the rice delivery.
Let the ones who have
been checked, pass.
Hey! Where are you going?
The tools to do the
repairs are outside the gate.
Go, quickly!
Excuse me!
Stop!
Don't let him escape!
Did you find it?
No, he might have dropped it in the moat.
Take him to Kimon Tower.
We will open up his stomach.
Ninja have a tendency to
hide it inside their stomach.
Remember that.
You Shogunate dog!
The pact was moved to Kimon Tower.
To move it a short distance
from the Main Wing to the
Kimon Tower...
Four men have been lost.
From the time we left Edo we
have lost eight men already.
All good men, too!
Chief...
Hanshiro, take out the
paper package on you.
The one you have been holding
dearly since you have left Edo.
I take it that the content is
my sister, Kozue's hairpin.
Chief...
Don't say anything.
I am not condemning you.
I have known for a while
now that you two are lovers.
After you safely complete
your assignment...
I was thinking of letting
you two get together.
But I am afraid that that
might not happen anymore.
From the start...
I knew this wasn't going to be easy.
But it turned out to be
harder than I anticipated.
Pull yourself together.
Come closer.
I need you to go Sumpu immediately.
His Excellency passed away this morning.
There will be chaos soon.
We have no time to waste.
Tell Jingoza to steal the pact immediately.
Yes, sir.
Aren't you the only kin of Jingoza?
Yes.
He has worked very hard for us.
We have asked the
impossible of him many times.
Though it was for the
peace of the country,
we have sent him through many trials.
And I am telling him
and his group to die now.
Elder...
Kozue, please be sure to tell him this.
I, Abe Bungo, will depart
Odawara tomorrow morning,
in reliance of him.
If he should fail to get that pact,
then I will kill Lord Tadanaga myself.
I will be sure to tell him that.
I will deliver the pact to you
before you arrive in Sumpu.
Chamberlain...
I hear you received
urgent news from Edo.
Yes, from Aoki Shuzen,
the Steward in Edo.
What did he have to say?
Elder Abe Bungo has
reported himself as being ill,
but is actually in Odawara.
He must be panicking since
the Shogun is near his death.
The Shogunate ninja must be frantic now.
We must be on our guard.
I want you to tell Saiga that.
Yes, sir.
What is this?
The identities of the
Shogunate ninja in town,
and their hideout.
"The Shogunate ninja sent,
are from Iga Group Three.
"They are Jingoza and 15 others.
"They are staying at Rakan-ji
Temple in Sumpu castletown."
RAKAN-JI
Is the back covered?
Yes, as you have ordered.
Good.
The ninja aren't showing up.
They won't show themselves so easily.
Be on the alert.
Hanshiro, is that you?
Yes.
Chief, the Suruga samurai
have this place covered.
Please leave immediately.
I know that.
But I can't escape.
The Negoro ninja have this place
secured with their "Death Trap".
He is a subservant for the temple.
Saiga...
That geezer is talking to someone.
But who?
After I am gone, you are
in charge of the Iga group.
Chief, I am not a leader.
No, you have to take charge.
Even if it comes down
to the very last man...
You must sneak into
Kimon Tower and steal the pact.
I'm counting on you to do it.
Ok.
I'm changing the plans.
When you get into the castle...
Don't make any moves for a whole day.
You must get their guard down,
or you won't make it out alive.
Hanshiro, don't mind me and escape.
He must have a comrade with him.
Find him.
Stop!
It's useless to go after him!
What a shame!
We only have one old man.
An old man?
Is that what he appears to you?
It's all right.
His leg should be broken.
How smart of you to
disguise yourself as a sexton.
Do you think I Saiga Magokuro, am blind?
I can see through your ninja disguise.
Am I wrong...
Chief Jingoza of Iga
Group Three Shogunate ninja?
So you have lost to the Negoro ninja?
Jingoza, do you want it?
The item you want is in there.
It's the pact!
Do you want to steal it?
But you can't run far with that leg.
Did he confess anything?
An Iga ninja wouldn't give
in and confess with torture.
Especially not the Iga Chief.
Why don't you just kill him?
You are mad to confine him
in the tower the pact is in!
Jingoza is the only strong
ninja in the Iga Group Three!
The others are worthless!
But they will come to save their chief.
That's when we will capture
every single one of them.
Now you know how
superior the Negoro ninja are.
There are 16 of them while
there is only one of me.
And look at the result.
They are in a very
disadvantagious situation.
I will beat them so that
they can never stand again.
Did you hear that Jingoza?
Every time I kill one of your
men, I will have you verify it.
I will make you feel defeat
to the core of your bones!
Saiga, I am fine with your plan, but...
Be sure to guard the pact well.
If you are so worried,
move it back to the Main Wing.
No. The pact will stay
in this Kimon Tower.
But, Steward...
It is your duty to protect
the lord and the pact.
Forget about the other ninja.
You can kill him when you want.
But the earlier the better.
He is skilled and smart...
What a shame.
I agree...
But he is a hard man to handle.
It might be best to get rid
of him after the job is done.
Will you say something?
Bunzo!
I don't get it.
What?
I just don't get it.
What else can I say?
Why did the Chief leave
Hanshiro in command?
Be it in age or skill...
There are others more capable.
I don't think I am
at all inferior to Hanshiro.
Are you discontent, Hanshiro?
No, not that.
But the Chief's order is final.
But...
He could have escaped
if he used me as a decoy.
But he became the
decoy and let me escape...
and told me to take command.
Are you saying that
was the Chief's compassion?
He is not one to be so ill-prepared!
He has sacrificed eight
men for this job already.
He wouldn't let himself
get caught so easily.
I think this is all part of his plan.
What do you think it is?
I don't know.
But I will follow his orders.
Isn't that our... Iga code?
If you have objections, speak up.
I won't force those
who are not convinced.
Even if I am alone,
I will follow the Chief's order
and carry out our mission.
Who is there?
Kozue!
Hanshiro...
Where is my brother?
I have bad news.
The Chief was captured
and taken to the castle.
Emergency!
Saiga!
Ah, Saiga!
There has been an urgent
notice from Hakone Station.
Abe Bungo has the gall to show up!
Saiga, where are you going?
How is Kozue?
The exhaustion from the trip
and the shocking news about
the Chief hit her hard...
I will relay the message
she brought to everyone.
His Excellency has passed away.
Elder Abe Bungo who is
staying in Odawara incognito,
will be entering the Sumpu
Castle the morning after tomorrow
as the official Shogunate envoy.
We have no time to waste.
We have to steal the pact before then...
On our Iga ninja honor!
Let us sneak into Sumpu Castle tonight!
I will go alone if I have to.
Saiga...
The night kite is up, just as I thought.
You probably can't see it.
About five miles beyond that
grove is the Iga night kite.
Probably around the
Shizuhata Mountain...
What is an Iga night kite?
They put a light on a black kite at night,
to notify their comrades of their location.
It's an Iga ninja signal.
We are safe while that light is up...
Hanshiro...
Time is moving.
Let us hear your order.
Listen up, everyone.
Will you die at the orders
of a greenhorn like me?
Jihei!
That goes without saying.
An Iga ninja dies at the order of the Chief.
That is our code.
Saheiji, I have no plan in mind.
I am leaving our fate
in the hands of heaven.
You are the Chief.
All you have to do is to tell us to die.
Denpachi, I am going
to be asking you to die.
I have been waiting for you to say that.
Magosuke...
I will do as you say.
Koroku, what about you?
All right, all right...
I am getting excited already.
I will go, too.
No, Kozue...
Hanshiro, I...
We have no time or
plan to save the Chief.
We have no chance of returning alive.
That is why we want at least you to live.
That is our last wish.
It is our farewell gift to the Chief.
Bunzo...
They cut it.
Are they coming now?
What?
What's the situation in the front?
The security is tight.
We won't be able to cross the moat.
What about the sides?
Same. It's impossible.
What about the water gate?
There are a lot of guards there, too.
It's geographically impossible
to sneak in from there.
There are a lot of guards
at the Southeast Gate, too.
We can go in through the Ushitora moat.
What? Ushitora moat?
The tower is far from there.
It's a perfect place to hide.
And the security is lax.
What about the moat?
There are no patrol boats.
I verified it.
Are there any lights in that area?
No. It's pitch dark.
That must be a trap.
Trap?
They are trying to lure us in.
There must be an army
waiting for us on the inside.
It appears that they
are taking us very lightly.
I lied that it was urgent business
and got the laborers to
return from the outskirts.
Interesting!
Shall we take advantage of the chaos?
Does it seem like they will
come in from Ushitora moat?
They won't fail so easily.
What do you mean?
A greenhorn as he may be,
but he is still an Iga ninja.
He will try to lure us
out by laying a trap first,
then enter through Ushitora
moat, where our trap is.
I hope you are well-prepared for them.
It's past the closing time!
We are aware of the regulations.
That is why we stayed
at the outskirts of town.
But we received an order
to deliver it by tonight.
Nonsense!
We weren't informed of it at all.
It must be a mistake!
You are the one who is mistaken!
Are you dreaming?
What insolence!
I won't stand for it!
Stop!
Let them come in!
Let them pass after
they have been checked.
Why don't we go in now,
through the Ushitora moat?
We might be able to outsmart them.
Wait!
We won't make it. Look.
The chaos will be over soon.
The guards from the other
location aren't coming over.
Let's go.
Wait.
Now's our time to sneak
in and raise a ruckus.
I'm very good at that.
Don't worry about my
oldtime wife and four children.
I'm starting to feel worn out.
Jingoza would have used me now.
Sorry.
When you get through, send us a signal.
Don't rush to your death.
Let's pull the last two men out.
Let's go.
Group Six, 12th horse.
Horse caretaker, Matsukichi!
Are you Matsukichi?
Next!
13th horse caretaker, Tatsuzo!
Hurry up! Get into line!
Stop!
Don't let him escape!
Let's go through Ushitora now.
I will cross this moat.
And go through the Inui Gate?
Let's outsmart them.
They wouldn't expect it.
But there are many guards.
Don't oppose me!
Or I will kill you!
Saiga...
I'm going to Ushitora.
I'm taking the men with me.
How was it?
There is a security lookout.
The tower has full view of it.
I see.
This is the only place.
Let's climb it.
It will be tough to climb that.
But it's worth a try.
Jihei...
Wait.
I said wait
What's up?
Someone is coming.
I see a shadow.
What's up, Jihei?
It's the Chief's sister.
Is that you, Kozue?
Hanshiro...
I told you not to come.
Let's get going, Jihei.
I'm old already.
Don't be weak-willed.
Climb.
I will only be in your way.
Just leave me and go.
All right, take Kozue down with you.
You have an important assignment to do.
Tell the Elder tonight...
that we will get it
before he arrives in Sumpu.
All right.
There is no opening.
At this point, we can only forge ahead.
What's wrong?
Be on the alert!
Shoot down anyone suspicious!
Jihei!
Kozue, please go ahead.
No. Let me help you.
I know myself best.
I have worked as a ninja for 30 years.
I am at my limits.
Jihei!
I envy Saheiji for dying in action earlier.
Don't give up. Let's hurry.
What is that?
There they are!
Jihei!
Kozue, hurry and escape!
He was a tough one.
Indeed. There's another one!
There's another one! Shoot!
Someone is coming!
Is this where the shots came from?
Yes... we saw a shadow by the moat.
It's dark in here.
If it's lighted, we can't see very well.
It turned out to be a stray dog.
Fool! That ninja upstart, country samurai,
will make insulting remarks again!
It's almost daybreak.
Hang on there a bit longer.
If nothing happens,
alert the security station.
Do you still think they will show up?
Just be prepared for them.
But it's getting lighted.
They will come!
They let two of their
comrades die last night!
They wouldn't back down so easily!
I'm going to check the
situation at the Inui Gate.
Stay on alert for a bit more.
Hey.
Any changes?
No, none at all.
Not a single rat appeared.
Nothing.
How is it at Ichinokido?
We sent someone over about daybreak.
Did someone go over to check after that?
Nothing after that?
That's right.
It will be bright shortly.
How disappointing...
What are those Iga ninja up to?
Did the tight castle security scare them?
Are they helpless without their Chief?
No, that can't be...
The tenth and eleventh men
were killed by the Inui Gate.
They have five men left.
What happened to them?
Why aren't they appearing
at the Ushitora moat?
FIRST GATE
Damn!
Fools!
What happened here?
Damn you!
We are up against ninja!
Don't let your guard down!
Search thoroughly!
Don't let them escape!
Search well!
Give me that!
Saiga!
A ninja was found dead by
the Inui Gate's outer moat?
We pulled him out of the
moat and brought him here.
Take his body to the Kimon Tower.
I will meet you there.
Hey! Clean that spear!
Search for the two ninja!
Oh, it's him.
How admirable of him.
He sunk himself with a rock.
That makes five... all in one night!
There are only two left.
They are lost without their chief.
This will be the end of
the Iga Ninja Group Three!
Open your eyes!
The Iga ninja have lost!
I, Negoro ninja,
can take on 15 or 16 Iga ninja alone!
Look there!
It's the end of the famous Iga ninja!
Look here and there!
I will line the last two here very soon, too!
You won't get them so easily.
Hah! Enough of the tough talk!
Saiga, why are you so irate?
You, yourself, know it.
The last ones that remain
are the strongest.
And they are already
on the castle grounds.
The castle samurai have
not found them yet.
Victory or defeat has
yet to be determined.
Enough talk!
A ninja's fight will continue
until the very last man.
I'm sure you know that.
Sir Saiga!
What is it?
A ninja on the outskirts of town?
Damn Iga! Bring him here!
Wait! I will go.
Throw the bodies in the well.
We need water.
Don't move... or it will get worse.
How long must we wait like this?
Just a while more.
If we wait, will we be able to get through?
Listen, Hanshiro...
I have a couple of plans in mind.
What is it?
I will attack a samurai
outside the storehouse
and steal his uniform.
It will be suspicious if
we go straight to Ninokido,
so we will turn back once at Ichinokido,
then somehow get to the Kimon Tower.
The other plan is to set
fire to the storehouse nearby
and dash to the bushes in the
chaos and wait for nightfall.
Hanshiro...?
I don't think we can even
make it to Ichinokido with that.
We will be discovered and killed.
Are we going to stay idle without a plan?
Staying here may
keep us from getting caught.
But without water, we will die.
We are the last of
the Iga Ninja Group Three!
Don't you want to escape out of here?
No.
Have you lost your nerve?
I'm not moving from here.
Listen, Hanshiro...
We still have energy left.
We are able to use
our ninja skills fully yet.
Let us get out of here.
Don't move from here.
That is my order.
You will...
You will dishonor our
group with a miserable end!
I won't take orders from you!
Have you forgotten our code?
If you don't follow orders, I will kill you.
Interesting!
Are you going to stop me?
A ninja has been caught!
It's Kozue...
What are we going to do, Hanshiro?
Are you going to let them kill her?
Search for the last ninja!
Search the area thoroughly!
Bring her here!
We caught another Iga ninja!
To think you were using
a woman as a messenger...
Woman! There are
15 ninja besides Jingoza!
Thirteen have already been killed.
And now we caught you.
Where is the last one?
Was he going to flee
back to Edo with you?
Or has he been hiding on the
castle grounds since last night?
Will you get it out of her?
Or shall I torture her?
It's useless.
What?
She won't talk even if her family is killed.
Fine!
I will put her through
the Negoro ninja torture!
I will give her a taste of our hell!
Take her to the torture room!
Sir Saiga!
What?
The Steward has
relieved the castle guards
from searching the storehouses!
What?!
FIRST GATE
Steward!
You must not relieve them!
Or all our efforts until
now will be for naught!
You have no proof that they
are hiding in those storehouses!
The incident at Ichinokido
is proof in itself!
They were all killed!
Which means there was a surviving ninja!
That is what you think.
They might sneak into the Main Wing.
They know that the pact is
being kept at the Kimon Tower.
Which means, they will have
to pass these storehouses.
How do you know that?
By the way Jingoza reacts...
That means nothing.
We can't rest the fate of
the 550,000-koku Suruga clan
on something unreliable as that!
Are there voices of discontent?
I have received numerous
complaints on your leadership.
Know your place as a newly hired vassal.
Tonight is a critical night.
The samurai must protect
the lord in the Main Wing.
Who knows what a
desperate ninja may do.
Please move the pact to
the Main Wing immediately.
Feeling a little timid?
Don't worry, I am not reducing
the guards at the Kimon Tower.
I have sent 15 or 16
skilled swordsmen as assistance.
That should be sufficient for a single ninja.
It's only for tonight anyway.
Steward!
You can have as many
foot soldiers as you want.
But they won't be of much help.
He is in there... I know it!
A ninja would find there
a perfect place to hide.
How do I capture him?
I can only rely on myself.
How can the 15 or 16
samurai possibly stop him?
Does it hurt, Hanshiro?
It's nothing serious.
I can still move.
If only we had water...
The salt on the wound
is what's causing it to sting.
It will alleviate the pain
if you could wash it out.
Forget about the water!
What's wrong, Bunzo?
Sorry... about what I said earlier.
I was just furious that
you weren't making a move.
You bear your thirst...
your pains from the injury...
and the pain of seeing
Kozue being taken away...
You are doing your best
to bear the unbearable.
You wasn't just doing
nothing and waiting here.
You were fighting
against Sumpu Castle, here.
Bunzo...
I used to think I was superior to you.
But you turned out to be
superior to me in everything.
I have lost to you.
How does it feel?
Shall I get to it now?
I will start with the horse taming method.
Then I will go on to more.
So confess now!
Who is the last ninja?
Where is he?
Talk!
So you won't talk?
All right...
Let's see you stick it out to the end then.
What's up with this?
Wait.
Let's call a dog.
Oh, it's a dog.
Don't move.
Or you will be shot.
That damn Saiga set a trap.
That fool!
Maybe I was too lenient with the whip.
Nail-peeling, finger-breaking,
skin-stripping...
You are better off dead
than going through our
Negoro ninja torture.
Will you bear through it all?
Kill me.
All right...
Let's go.
We all have our roles.
I will go out and cut off the lights.
The castle samurai think
there is only one man left.
If I go out, they won't expect another.
Dash to the Kimon Tower
during the chaos of it all.
Good luck.
Bye.
What happened?
So Bunzo has died...
What a shame.
He fought very well.
A great end for the
last man of the Iga group!
Why do you look at me like that?
Are you mocking me?
Mock me all you want!
But it's my victory!
As Shogunate ninja with a stipend,
you wouldn't understand how it is!
Do you know how hard I fought?
They mocked me for
my lowly ninja background
and blocked my every step!
They kept me out of the entire planning!
I fought within that great humiliation!
I fought against your
Iga ninja and my allies,
the Suruga samurai!
How foolish...
Foolish, you say?
You think I am foolish?
You were beaten by me.
We ninja are nothing but required to win.
Iga or Koga comes after the victory.
That is the way of the ninja.
I have won.
I will make the Negoro ninja
the agents for Suruga rule.
Saiga, unfortunately, that won't happen.
What?
I have won...
You have lost to my plan.
Your plan?
You didn't find it odd
that I was caught so easily.
As a matter of fact,
you let it get to your head.
And you lost all reasoning.
So the clansmen started
revolting against you.
In other words, you behaved
just the way I wanted you to.
This is an Iga technique
of causing revolting feelings.
Do you understand Saiga?
That was only until the match was met.
Look! I have won by myself!
The match hasn't been met yet.
Until the last man dies.
I can kill you off anytime.
I can't let you live anyway.
I'm not talking about myself!
Unfortunately, you were no match for us.
What?
Women aren't listed on
the Shogunate Ninja Register.
And you didn't know that.
There lies your miscalculation.
Then who is that woman?
Iga Kozue... my younger sister.
You are a very smart and skilled ninja.
I find that to be a shame.
Rather than regretfully dying in defeat,
go back to Kishu and leave
the Negoro name for future...
Say no more!
Where is the last man?
Are you going to ask me that?
I will kill him, too!
Guards!
Saiga, I came for the pact!
I see!
You must defeat a Negoro ninja first!
Take it by force!
This is it!
Chief!
Take this and go!
Please give this to the Shogunate envoy!
Please look after Kozue, too.
Chief!
Don't mind me and go!
Don't mind me or you
can't fullfill your assignment!
Go quickly!
Hanshiro, after you deliver this pact...
Don't go back to Edo.
Brother!
Go back to Iga with Kozue.
Hanshiro...
A ninja has no family happiness.
I want that sadness to end with my time.
I want at least the two of you to grasp
human happiness...
No matter how small it may be.
Do you understand?
I wish both of you happiness.
Now, go.
Go!
Brother...
Thank you for coming from afar.
Wait
What is your name again?
I'm Steward Narita Sukehachi.
I will remember your name.
Hattori!
Deliver this to Third Shogun lemitsu!
Don't rest along the way.
Run it all the way by horse!
Yes, sir!
Narita, lead the way.
LORD TADANAGA WAS CONFINED
IN KOFU IN JANUARY, 1632.
HE WAS THEN TRANSFERRED
TO TAKASAKI CASTLE IN JOSHU,
AND COMMITED SUICIDE IN DECEMBER.
THE SECRET OF THE
NINJA'S MERITORIOUS SERVICE
WAS LOST IN THE VILLAGE OF IGA,
AND NOT A TRACE REMAINS TODAY.
Special Thanks to "Toyo Ichi"
Subtitled and Mastered by Cannibal King
www.KuroTokagi.com