This film is based on a mysterious incident
my ex-girlfriend experienced.
Everything seems to be a lie.
Things here,
this place,
I myself,
and you.
Everything looks fake.
Somewhere in my head
I feel everything exists here.
But then again.
There's another part of me
wondering if it's real at all.
It used to be different.
How can I say...?
The sun looked like the sun.
How can I describe...?
The rhythm of nature...?
Something like that.
I thought my life was based on it.
But I don't know
when I started doubting.
I became numb.
I started wondering
whether it was there to begin with.
So...
I can't concentrate.
I can't create.
I can't write.
I feel like I lost something vital
in my heart.
Well... why don't you find a job?
Forget about scriptwriting for now.
When you're active,
you won't go weird in your head.
I believe so.
I wish I could work
on films, too.
But even if we don't want,
we have to earn for our living.
Otherwise our life is finished.
That's not true.
This is more important
than eating and drinking.
I know what you mean.
But we can't go on like this.
Right?
Everything is just reasonable.
What?
You actually know it,
don't you?
You can't work
on your new film
when you lost the vital thing
in your heart.
Right?
Cut!
Well...
I see you've got a problem,
but I can't see what it is.
This is not
what I want to express.
It doesn't convey what I want.
But you wrote those lines.
This is your script.
Now I understood,
after I played it by myself.
Can we start over?
If it was up to me,
oh, yes, we could,
but this is no longer
between you and me only.
We've already involved the crew.
What are we going to do with the 8 million
yen
we've already spent for this film?
Get into debt again?
That's impossible.
You've done something
like this before.
You've already got
another case like this.
What will happen if you quit
this project in the middle,
and cause another trouble?
It's fatal.
You'll never find an investor
for your project.
This project was already tough to
finance with what you did in the past.
It's a small world.
Everyone knows what you've done.
You seriously want to continue
making films, right?
We came all the way for this film.
Why don't we finish this one as it is?
Then you can start a new project
with your new ideas.
I think you should finish this film.
Am I wrong?
Stop being amateurish.
I can't stand it anymore.
It's already collapsing, isn't it?
Isn't it?
I can't protect you anymore.
Don't you understand?
I need a donut!
Get me a donut!
We have to cancel
today's shooting.
Ah, that's right...
Yeah, that's right...
Are you sleeping?
You must be exhausted.
Please take a good rest.
I'm sorry for this afternoon.
I was a bit tough on you.
But I believe in you.
Let's try our best
from tomorrow.
Don't worry.
Our film is already great
as it is.
Believe me.
I don't want
to disturb your sleep.
I won't drop by today.
Good night.
Please call me
if you need anything.
I'm so stupid.
Why am I keep crying?
No! No! No!
This is not the time.
I told you,
I don't feel alive.
Do you understand...?
Do you feel alive?
I don't.
I can't.
What is the rhythm
of nature?
I don't feel it anymore.
I don't want to say stuff
like this anymore.
Time is running out.
I can't breathe.
I wish everybody would die.
I'm a little tired.
I think I need a break for
about a month or so.
I'm tired
In both spiritual and physical way I'm tired
I think I have to take my time
and go through the points once again
Please don't look for me.
We are born to be happy,
not to be unhappy.
This moment, this state,
this is the ultimate happiness.
I was born to achieve this,
therefore I can stay like this.
I wasn't wrong, isn't it?
Get yourself together (flipped and written backwards)
I knew you'd be here.
Are you also alone?
Yes.
Don't you feel lonely?
No.
It's great we came all the way.
Yes.
I feel my true self here.
I don't think I can go
back to Tokyo.
Really...
Wherever you are,
you are no one but you.
Whether you are here
or there,
everything is just
the mirror of your mind.
You've already begun
to understand
that everything is just
reflecting your mind.
You are always creating
the world you see.
I have to go now.
Can I see you tomorrow?
I decided to stay here.
Really?
You've got someone waiting
for you over there.
You've got things
to do overthere.
Wherever you are,
this place is always with you.
You'll be all right
Can you see?
Please nod
if you can see this.
Don't worry,
you'll be all right.
Please wait for a while.
Try it again.
Set it to 200.
Watch out.
1, 2, 3.
Set it to max.
Max. Power.
Watch out.
1, 2, 3.
10:22 a.m.
Are you sure
you don't know her?
This is very important,
please tell us if you do.
Still nothing identifying her?
No...
We cannot find any relatives
Poor girl, but for us
it's another trouble...
Strange things happen.
It was a shock.
Two girls at once,
from different places in the same state.
I thought it's that stuff
on the media,
you know, strangers get together
through websites
and kill themselves together.
Sorry, you're not ready
to talk about this...
What separates the one coming back
from the one going?
Very mysterious...
How are you feeling?
Everybody is worried
and waiting in the hallway.
Shall I call them inside?
Do you want to see
anyone particular?
Shall we wait till
she settles down?
Please push this button
to call us. Okay?
We'll come check you later.
After this incident,
she started a new life
by breaking up with me,
her partner both
in private and work.
I heard she is working hard like
a different person supporting herself,
and planning her new film.
To be honest,
I think she made up most of this story
this impressive near-death experience
by her imagination
to change herself.
I feel it's too perfect
to be true.
What happened is exactly like the image
she had in her mind.
Anyway, after all, it doesn't matter
whether it was true or not.
I just sincerely hope
that she will be fine from now on.