It's a real storm
Hey, take this
Yes
Who's in charge of the body-fat scale?
I think it's Shimada san
Right
We're here from Dalian, China
I'm Shao Yen
Nice to meet you
Your Japanese is good
We've been studying night and day
As soon as the telephone lines
to Dalian are installed,
you can hire 3 young locals
like her for what you pay one
Japanese employee here
I understand
That sounds good
Excuse me
We're going forward with the plan to move
the Administration Dept. to Dalian
I see
I'm aware of the great job you've done
as the director of Administration
So, Sasaki san,
what will you do after
you leave Administration?
What?
What are your skills?
You tell me
What can you contribute
to our Tanita Corporation?
It's entirely up to you
Either you contribute your fullest here
or you leave our company
About that air conditioning estimate
Oh, that
Yes
I think we should accept
Uchida System's bid
What do you think, Director?
Can I have that?
What?
That
Right
Did you visit Hello Work?
No
You've got to stop by Hello Work
before you come here
Oh, right
Go before your luck runs out
Otherwise, you'll be stuck here
for life, like me
Reception Closed for Today
Hey
It's open
You sure carry a lot around
It's too heavy
I'm home
Honey!
When did you get home?
Just now
Don't surprise me like that
Did you get off work early?
Yeah
What are you doing?
Just making sure all the doors are locked
I see
That's all
Anything wrong?
No
But you could use the front door
You're right
Thanks for the food
Sure
I'm off
Off you go
Will you be home early again today?
No, I've got a busy day
I see
Takashi?
Not yet
He's a mess
I'm off
Off you go
See ya
I'm home
Welcome home
Hungry?
No thanks
I'm going to bed Don't vacuum
So, on to the topic of mastering
honorific diction
Keigo diction is the skillful use
of 3 different types
of honorific speech in order to show
respect to the other person
We want you to use respectful language
to your elders,
so we'll investigate
the meaning of each...
Sasaki, what is that?
Show me
Ridiculous
I profoundly despise anyone
who would sneak this into my classroom
Stand
But...
You have no right to attend my class
Go stand in the back
That's not mine
Is that an excuse?
It's true
I was just passing it on
I told you to stand
In the back, hurry
Teacher
What?
I saw you reading porn manga
on the train the other day
I was sitting in front of you
You were trying hard to hide it,
but I could see the cover,
"Weekly Eros Mania"
Why do you say that?
Because it's true
He's got balls
This is hardly the place
You're right
It's not fair
Quiet!
Back to the lesson
So, honorific diction
Let's conjugate standard
diction into honorific
OK? Start with "To see"
Sasaki, you're amazing!
He looked so scared What a laugh
Let's call him Ero-Bayashi
Excellent
Ero-Bayashi! Ero-Bayashi!
Ero-Bayashi!
What?
I'm sorry about before
Right
I went too far
I didn't think the other kids
would react like that
You came to say that?
Yes
All this way?
Forget it
You'll graduate in less than a year
It's not going to change
how we get along
But that manga really isn't mine
So I didn't think it was fair
that I was the only one
who had to stand
Sasaki, let's stop poking at
each other's wounds
You can ignore me
and I'll ignore you, too
You got that?
Let's stop
More distinction between crescendo
and decrescendo, OK?
Again, from here
That's right, continue
A little stronger here
What was that other piece in C Major,
that you learned to play so well?
Let's see...
We're sorry to keep you waiting
Will the person holding ticket number 86
please proceed to window...
Your hours are midnight to 9
in the morning
Security guard at a factory
There's never been
a single robbery there
So you don't have to worry
Sasaki san,
how about administrative work?
I'm much more suited to that
Well,
maybe this is perfect for you
Please
A manager at a Happy Mart store,
Monday through Friday,
from 7 AM through 3PM 850 Yen an hour
I wrote it in the form I gave you,
but I used to be Administrative Director
at Tanita
It's not easy to say this,
but it's 100% impossible you'll match
your former position
We're sorry to keep you waiting
Here you go
Here's this month's salary
Thanks
I think it's time for a new stove
Yeah
I guess it can wait 'til your Bonus
Where's Takashi?
He left this afternoon
for one of his classes
I see
I hope he's not getting into trouble
Right
Your qualifying exams are coming up?
Yeah
Hang in there
Maybe I'll play piano
I want to play piano
It's OK, right?
No
Why not?
It's just a whim
Maybe you should
play in music class at school
No means no
Welcome home
I'm home
I've saved your meal
Yeah, I'll eat it
Look
What?
You got your driver's license
But you won't use it
It's just a form of identification
An expensive form of identification
Use your insurance card
I like this one better
It's rice porridge today
Hello
It's cold today, isn't it?
Sure is
Please wait a little longer
Hello, hello
Thanks for your patience
Here you are
Sorry to keep you waiting
Hey, Kurosu?
I thought it was you, Sasaki
Long time no see
You haven't changed since high school
Neither have you
Sorry
Hello
Sure, OK
I'm meeting with a client right now
I'll talk to the Senior V.P. about
that myself
And don't worry about
the bid on the Municipal Hall
Sure, sure, thanks
You dropped this
Oh, thanks
You seem busy
You're in construction?
Something like that
What about you?
Healthcare equipment
Sounds great
Hey, what's that?
I think they're giving away food
You'd be surprised how many guys line up
Maybe I'll check it out
It's a rare chance to taste it
Are you by any chance, unemployed?
You can tell?
Yeah
Right
You are, too, right?
Yeah Got down-sized last week
I got downsized 3 months ago
What about that phone call?
That's just for show
I do it to calm my nerves
I know it's stupid
No, it was amazing
Aren't you going to eat that?
I already ate
Yeah...
It tastes lousy, right?
It's lousy
You can stay here as long as you want
Excuse me
I set up my phone
to ring 5 times an hour
I didn't know you could
It's not a very well-known feature,
so it fools most people
Oh, I see
Have you told your wife yet?
No
You hand her the monthly cash?
Yeah
That means you'll last for a while
Your severance pay?
Have they paid it all?
Not yet
Set up a separate bank account for it
Any irregular deposits will stand out
Unemployment insurance?
I'm just applying now
Make sure to submit
all the paperwork on time
One day late and you're disqualified
Oops
You're really amazing
Ero-Bayashi
Now, Kobayashi's totally lost
his authority over us
Yeah
This is like a revolution
A revolution!
Yeah
What's wrong?
You're the one that started it all
Kenji?
Welcome home
Kenji,
I'm making donuts
Why don't you come down?
I'm fine
Don't you want to eat donuts?
No thanks
Thanks for the food
Thanks
Hey Kenji
Your monthly lunch money
Put it in your bag
It's due tomorrow, right?
In China, a massive natural gas
development project...
Want a donut?
Let's examine China's current energy
sources breakdown
In fact, China is
the largest producer of coal
in the world,
and the world's
6th largest oil producer...
How about a donut?
In 1 990,
they depended on coal for 76% of
their energy,
and 17% on oil
But by 2002,
their coal dependency was reduced to 65%
and their oil dependency rose to 24% ...
You were having a nightmare
Kaneko Piano School
I'd like to pay for a month of lessons
Thank you
Did you come alone?
They said I'm in 6th grade now,
so I'm on my own
OK, we'll start next week
OK
Do you have a piano at home?
Yes, a small one
Come here
Can you play anything?
Try playing
Keep playing
I'm home
Welcome home
Takashi, you're home
That's rare
I don't have work today
Right
Do you want to shower first?
No, I'll eat now
Kenji, it's dinnertime
Come on down
Takashi, your book
I'll have a beer
I'll get it
Sure tasty
Let's eat
It's bad
I'm starting to
get home early these days
Yeah?
Think she knows?
What?
Has my wife figured it out?
Just because you get home
a little early? No
She stares at me
with eyes full of mistrust
I'm telling you, it's bad
I have to find a way to
make her trust me
Let me treat you to dinner
What do you want?
Please, come to my house
OK?
I'm home
Welcome
Hello
My daughter, Mika
Good evening
Junior High?
I'm in 8th grade
You're so tall
Hey, didn't you order sushi?
But you said a home cooked meal was fine
I guess I did
It's a delicious meal
Oh, no, a job-related call at this hour
Do you put in overtime every day, too?
Well, yes
Is the company doing that well?
All of us employees are working hard
My husband won't tell me
anything about it
The company's doing fine
You don't need to worry
I see
Sasaki san,
please look after my husband
I will
That was our president,
calling about that estimate
You're the one that wrote it up,
right, Sasaki?
You need to be more diligent
I covered for you this time
as best I could
Get it together, OK?
I will
Please, use this
Oh, thank you
You have it rough, don't you?
The Tokyo National Museum was...
I'm home
The main building was
constructed in 1 938
It is a magnificent edifice,
exuding authority
Stepping inside, visitors are...
Welcome home
I'm home
Didn't you eat dinner?
No
I thought I'd make tempura
It's been a while
You'll eat, right?
No, I already ate
I see
My boss invited me out after the meeting
I'm really wiped
I'm going to bed
I'll go to bed, too
Pull me up
Somebody, please pull me up
Sasaki Ryuhei, please
Yes
You're 46 years old?
What can you do?
I'm willing to do anything
That's too vague
We want to know your specific skills
What?
We want you to show us what you excel at
Right here?
Yes, right now
Do you mean like singing Karaoke?
What skills can you contribute
to this company?
That's what we want to see
Not right here, now...
Then how are we expected to
judge your merits?
I've worked in administration
so I'm confident of
my interpersonal skills
I see, what else?
What else...
Did you really do nothing to prepare,
figuring you might just get lucky?
No
I understand
Your Karaoke is fine Please sing
Start singing What's wrong?
You're good at it, right?
Use that pen instead of
a microphone and sing
When you think about it,
we're like a slowly sinking ship
The lifeboats are long gone,
the water's up to our mouths
We know it's hopeless,
but we're still looking for an exit
But then, we don't have the courage to
dive underwater, either
Tell me, Kurosu, why is it?
I'm prepared to accept anything
But why aren't
they prepared to accept us?
The lifeboats are gone
They loaded them up with women,
children and young people
They're gone
It folds up like this,
making a perfect space for bicycles
Your whole family could go car camping
It's really great Get away with
just the family
That's exactly what this car
is perfect for
This car is all the rage now
But most people find it
more attractive as a second car,
than as the family car
Check out this handy feature
The roof goes away?
Please, please
Please
I can't get rid of any
All gone
When's that giant earthquake coming?
The one that'll
turn everything upside down,
beat up all those arrogant bastards,
and make me Prime Minister,
so I can pass a No Helmet law
Yes, I understand
I'll notify my lawyer
Yes
Good bye, then
I won't contact you,
so please don't call me, either
OK
Good bye
I'm sorry
That's all for today's lesson
Thank you
Don't worry about me
But...
You're worried?
Sure, you are
I went and got a divorce
Our marriage was over,
so it doesn't really change anything
Once, he was a stranger, and now,
we're back to being strangers again
You're not going to see him again?
No, never again
That's what marriage is like
I understand
You do?
What do you understand?
How you feel
You do, huh?
Recently, I feel calmer being alone, too
When I'm with someone,
I end up saying the wrong thing
and we both get hurt
It's time for you to go home and study
See ya
Hey
What?
I need to ask you a favor
This is the Japanese version
You're signing up for
the American military?
Yeah
There's a new policy
You don't have to be an American
You saw it on TV, right?
It's news to me
I...
Already passed the paper test
Wait a minute
I only have to pass the physical exam
and the thought exam and I'm in
If you're in the military,
you go to war, right?
It depends
But you should have consulted us before
Have you told your father?
No
I see
The thing is, I'm still a minor,
so I need a parent to sign
Here and here
C'mon, sign
If you won't, forget it
There are organizations that'll
sponsor me instead of parents
Don't ask some strange organization
to sign for you
Then, sign
Kurosu?
Kurosu san passed away With his wife
The other afternoon From gas poisoning
Really?
A double suicide,
but one forced the other
Welcome home
I'm home
Honey, listen to him
and try not to get mad
What is it?
I want you to sign these papers
I absolutely forbid it
Why?
I raised you so you could lead
a happy life
This couldn't be farther from that goal
But in the military,
you can work for peace
That's just rationalizing
But it's true
Why should I alone be happy?
It's better to
make the whole world happy
The whole world?
What's that?
Who cares about that?
I'm not worried about the world,
I'm worried about you
Huh
That's why Japan's so hopeless
What?
It's the American military
that protects Japan
So what?
Think about it, at least a little
The reason I want to join
the American military
is to protect you and Mom and Kenji
That's how it works
Don't be a smartass
In this house, I protect you
That's how it works
You can't just do whatever you want
You're the one that needs to
think about it
I don't want your protection
Get out, then
Get out!
Forget it
I'll ask someone else
Takashi, wait!
Can't you figure out a better way
to talk to him!
Takashi, it's fine
if you want to leave us
But not for America
Stay in Japan and do what you can here,
OK?
What am I supposed to do?
You say you're protecting us, Dad
But what do you do, every day?
You can't even answer me
I have to get ready