Alright turn around
Ok!
Cute teddy bear!
Happy birthday
Thank you!
That's great.
Teddy bears are expensive. Luckily I found that one lying around outside.
Papa shhh!
What?
Nothing
Come on, blow out your candles
Ok?
Ready and...
Zombies! WHY!?
We've come to expose your fake happiness!
No matter how happy you are, you'll be one of us in seconds
That's just life!
Mama! Mama!
Someone save him!
Here
You were more worried about this little guy than yourself
That kindness is very beautiful
Cause he's my friend!
He's a very sincere bear
He looks cute and has the heart of a samurai
I'm sure he'll repay you for protecting him by protecting you
He's stretching!
He's yelling!
Little girl, I can talk too
And I will repay you as best I can!
Please save the teddy bear!
I was hoping you'd ask
Nuigulumar!
Nuigulumar Z
Thank you!
I've been searching for this little guy
He's my friend so I need to take him with me, sorry
That's ok
In exchange, I'll tell you how this world became full of zombies
It began 5 years ago in space
Far away, on the planet Domoho
A group of very small lifeforms escaped from the destruction of their planet
Searching for a new home, they arrived on Earth
Their cotton like forms descended upon the planet
Falling... like snow
Most of them fell into the ocean or onto the ground and disappeared
But their greatest warrior Dumava managed to survive
And drifted into a certain home
There he found the best place for him to live
Within a handmade teddy bear
A designer named Fuyuko Aiyukawa was making it for her daughter
Hey mama!
Don't surprise me like that!
Hey mama, what day is today?
Hm I don't know
It's my birthday!
Hey mama, what are you giving me?
You can't just directly ask like that
But
When we were still with dad with all the violence, there were never any presents
But since you got the divorce I've been wondering what kind of present you'd give me
What a selfish girl
Mama is that...?
So cute! A teddy bear!
Thank you mama!
You really do care about me
This is proof!
His face looks like it was punched, so I'll call him Punchy!
We'll never be apart!
At that moment, Kyoko's joy energized the warrior sleeping within
What is this feeling?
The energy from this girl needing me is awakening my cells
I lost my home and my purpose, but now I understand
I live to protect this princess
I swear on these button eyes!
PRINCESS!!!
Huh?
The cotton is still sticking out
What, so it wasn't done?
Sorry, I've been so busy
It's my first birthday with just us. You could have put me first
Sorry
Hey mama!
What is it?
You'll be here soon!?
Yeah yeah, that's right. I'm almost there. I know I know
Food? I just ate udon so I'm good
At that moment, with the worst timing a visitor came to Kyoko's house
Where are you now?
Hey mama, let's live with just to two of us
Now?
Thanks for waiting!
It's been a while sis!
Yumeko!
Sis?
You must be Kyoko
Thanks for letting me stay here!
Stay!? What's going on mama!?
Uhm that's...
I'm looking forward to staying with you
Ah! Coffee!
Dangerous!
Happy Birthday Kyoko
Ahhh oopsie
What did you do!?
Whoa a pretty dangerous human showed up
I ended up here, but where did Deparza go?
My best friend, Deparza!
Someone called out to me?
Could it be Dumuva?
You survived too?
What's with that getup?
Your parents'd be crying
It's a cosplay club. I hate it too
I betcha like this!
Stop! Help me!
Tony, c'mere
An old man with a stuffed animal?
You just said several keywords that should never be said to me
And you called me tiny. Take that BACK!!
I am the Knitted Vengeance Warrior, Charlie!
A monster!
Thank you for saving me!
I don't remember saving anyone
You will become my minion
Dumava
It seems we have taken different paths
This is the first step towards my ambition
Ugh why do I have to do homework on my birthday?
And an essay on my dreams. So lame
My dreams...
Until recently it was for papa who always bullied mama to get shot by tanks
But they got divorced so that kinda happened
Thank goodness
But that lolita woman
I don't want to spend a single second with her
Mr Tank, chase her out of my house!
At least give me my time with mama back
What?
What a cute teddy bear!
The couple little rough points make it even cuter
Hey, why are you cleaning in the middle of the night?
Sorry, I always used to do it that way at home
And that bear is my present!
The vacuum cleaner! I can't get it off!
Please turn it off! Turn it off!
You are way too clumsy!
What happened?
Hey mama, I don't want to live with that thing
You know my parents passed away recently right?
She has no other family
And I'm sure it will help having her around
They're totally black
Burnt toast at night?
Yumeko? More like Yume-ick-ko
I don't need an unfinished bear
Kyoko!
I'm sorry sis
I'll leave tomorrow
It's ok. I'm glad you came
She's going through a lot from the divorce and I can't help her on my own
I'm sure you'll be able to help her over time
I think the two of you are a bit similar
Really?
Yep. Your imaginative sides
I didn't think there was anyone like me in this world
...with some man.
There's no way that's true
That's just your lies
Isn't that just your guilty conscience talking?
Other than my sister who left home as soon as she could
No one in my family paid attention to me
I had no friends. I was always alone
Plus I never felt comfortable as a woman
I started wearing the boy's uniform to school
And I always just watched tokusatsu heroes
Heroes secretly fight against monsters to defend justice
I wanted to fight the lonely fight against darkness!
But as a woman I couldn't be a hero
I didn't want to be a tokusatsu heroine
The real me was just a clumsy girl
I just happened to read a Gothic Lolita magazine
And was shocked by the cute and incredible outfits that went beyond just 'clothes'
How elegant! How charming!
I instinctively knew what I wanted to wear, so I made it myself
Those were my battle clothes!
I had always walked in the shadows
But now I had discovered myself!
Good afternoon!
How is it?
What do you think?
But soon after my parents fell ill, and I went back to having no place of my own
In the end it was all a sweet dream
I can't get along with Kyoko either
I really am so powerless
You idiot!
The teddy bear talked!
That's right. A bunch of stuff happened and now I speak Japanese!
My movements are a bit awkward but never mind!
This is pretty hard work!
Sorry
I was listening all along, but there was nothing sweet there!
You're powerless? You can't become a hero?
You haven't done anything, don't make me laugh!
It's soft but somehow it hurt?
That's the result of training. Hero training.
I see
I'll make you into a hero
For the Princess
The Princess? Who?
So embarrassing
When you laugh your teeth really come out
I'm talking about Kyoko
All that matters is making Kyoko happy
But how?
Sew me up and finish me
Yumicko, you!
Me!?
It tickles. It tickles
You're good!
You're stupidly clumsy at everything else though
We're saying that sis sewed you up though
Lies are an important part of justice
Shut up and sew!
I put the finished Punchy and a birthday card in sis' handwriting
Next to Kyoko's pillow
Oh no, she's waking up!
Punchy!
All good
His teeth are out again. Pushing his nose up...
Mama... sorry
Papa...
Kyoko... she's lonely
I understand that feeling
Maybe I really can become her friend
That's good. Don't rush it. Let the love develop
It seems like a storm is coming after all
Japan's Zombie Incident
Cosplay Girl Bites Men
Thanks for waiting!
This zombie incident is pretty serious!
They say 7 people were bitten and infected by the cosplay girl
Nice. Getting bit by a girl is the way to go
If she showed up here, I'd be all for it
Master, you serious?
They're here
What now? If you want to get bit now's your chance
You know what, never mind!
Master save me!
It hurts!
Mama thank you
For what?
For finishing up Punchy
If you're happy, I am too
And actually I have one more present
Is that?
Manuscript paper
Kyoko, you have the ability to put your imagination into words
When something sad happens, I want you to be able to use that imagination to move past it
I want you to use your imagination to overcome harsh realities
You can do that
Right Yumeko?
Sorry!
You're awful! I told you not to bring Yumicko!
Kyoko, Yumeko is my sister
She is your blood relative too
Shake hands
What was that?
Just for today
Because mama told me to
I... am fine with just that
What terrible timing!
Those are real zombies!
Yumicko, run away! I'll save the Princess!
But!
Mama what's going on!?
Look out!
Yumicko!
Owwwwwie!
I knew it would turn out like that
Don't!
Mama!
I...
Sis!
Mama! Mama!
No way..
Mama... Mama...
It's your fault
She was shot protecting you!
Not me...
No! She...
I'll never forgive you
I'll never ever forgive you!
Kyoko...
Kyoko!
I am always kind to women, but against a super evil zombie, I'm going all out!
All out Punch! All out Hit!
Finishing Fart!
Hurry! Chase the Princess!
I'm sorry sis
Leave me alone!
PRINCESS!!
Kyoko!
What Princess?
You're as old fashioned as always
Who are you!?
Could you be... Deparza?
I'm afraid that since I've combined with a human I am no longer Deparza
I am the Knitted Vengeance Warrior, Charlie!
So you're behind these zombies!
But back when we fought together, you weren't evil like this!
I changed after seeing the darkness in humans
Listen! I will not leave even a single teddy bear alive!
No! I won't let you hurt Kyoko!
Then take my retribution!
Through my loyal servants
The Psychic, Kill Billy!
Gatling Lolita!
What!
The enemy is a lolita too!?
Hmph, comparing me with that shitty lolita makes my goth left arm hurt!
What the heck!
What is that esper kid gonna do? Spoon bending!?
Sorry. These aren't for bending!
Die by my spoons!
Yumicko! Hurry and dodge!
You will suffer for defying us!
You pink shit!
You're too naive!
No!
Princess!
Yumicko, leave this to me and run!
No! I failed to protect her!
If I can save Kyoko, I don't care if I die!
Don't do it!
If I can use my blood to distract them, I can save her!
They're here!
You're damn annoying!
Yumicko!
Are you ok? Hold on!
I don't regret it. My life was meaningless anyways
That's not true
As a woman, you have a true samurai spirit
You protected her and fought back!
Combine with me and become the hero you dreamed of!
Become the hero!
What?
What's wrong Billy? Finish her
I won't kill someone already on the verge of death
Are you disobeying me?
Sorry
I can really become a hero?
They won't call me a heroine?
I'll do my best. What do you want to look like?
Cute and fluffy
Make me a teddy bear like you Punchy
I want to be strong like that guy who finished me off!
And I want my face to look like his too!
What about the name?
Eh!? What should I... uhm... uhh...
Hurry up! We'll hit the ground soon!
It's a stuffed animal so...
Nuigulumar!
(TN: nuigurumi = stuffed animal)
Ok! got it!
Who are you?
Sharper than cotton and soft to hug. But I don't hug evil.
Nuigulumar arrives!
I won't let you touch the Princess!
Who is that!
Go!
Yes sir!
Curse you!
You are a brilliant foe, however...
When the time is ripe, we will take our revenge in a horrific fashion!
Remember this
Uhm
Princess, are you hurt?
Who are you?
Someone who understands the sadness inside you
I will be praying for the day you are healed
Wait!
Yumicko
We now have a shared destiny
We will continue to protect her from the shadows, just like sis wanted
Yeah
I swear on these button eyes!
With that the zombie attacks ceased
Charlie disappeared and remained disturbingly quiet
It seemed at first to be resolved
But rumours began circling of people becoming zombies due to stress or from catching a cold
And a sense of unease continued to spread
And so several years passed
So noisy!
Kyoko! I made dinner, want to eat?
I did it!
Punchy! She took it! Yay!
Um so today I tried making omurice!
You know Yumicko
No matter how many times you cook for me, I'll never eat it so it's just a waste
That's alright. Making it is my hobby
Stop being so polite
You're older than me. Pisses me off
That brat, she really makes me mad
I'd like to turn into Nuigulumar and teach her a lesson!
Hold it in!
If you get too mad you'll explode!
Like BOOM!
Listen, she just keeps getting further and further away from me
My patience is gonna wear out!
Ow!
If you hug me we'll combine!
Ahh! We half transformed!
She's back!
Say something?
Nope, nothing
Oh here!
Uh the deadline for the novel submission is coming soon so you should prepare your draft
I'm not writing a novel
I only believe in music
I don't care if it was my mom's will, it's stupid
Soy sauce!?
I'm amazed you can say that when you let my mom die
But what pisses me off most is that she saved you instead of me
That's-
I'm old enough now to understand
No one has ever wanted me around
That's not true!
It is!
The person who saved me never showed up either
I don't need this garbage anymore
Garbage?
I did my best to fix it!
You fixed it?
Sorry...
Figures. You and mama lied to me
You're the worst
Oww
Punchy we have to go after her
So mean! How could she call me garbage!?
The Princess has abandoned me. I'm going to pull out my cotton and die
How could she!
It hurts!
I might be at my limit living like this.
I forgot about work!
Where are you Kouji?
MB Company?
Oh it's here
You're performing here?
What's your band again?
No, it's not a performance it's a seminar
A seminar?
On the surface it's a health and cosmetics company
But apparently the president's seminars are amazing
Kyoko, hurry up
No way, I'm not interested in that religious stuff
No dumbass, it's not religious
It's a seminar
Shit, it's Yumicko. She's doing some sort of bike delivery job
Kyoko you're late!
They say after taking this seminar musicians and performers suddenly became successful
Let's check it out!
Hey, you're not my boyfriend. I told you no touching
Cheapskate. Free sex has always been a part of rock and roll
Kouji, you've got a good face and a good smile, but your brain needs work
Your teeth are covered in food too
You know, never mind
Seriously?
You two there
Please enter
Those lips...
Is he... Nuigulumar?
Well?
I'll go! I'm coming!
Nice! Let's go!
President, Kyoko is here
I see. This moment has finally come
Ugh, curry just doesn't fit the lolita style at all
I wish Kyoko understood what working was like
Excuse me. Your curry is here!
Hey Yumicko, is it really ok not to follow the Princess?
I have a bad feeling
She can do whatever she wants
You're just being overprotective
You fool!
A man protects without expecting anything in return!
I'm not a man!
But there's a smell, like some sort of animal
Are you talking about me!? I bathe properly!
No! I can sense Charlie!
Really?
Hey!
Who are you? You're suspicious!
Damn!
The curry! In my eyes!
Run away!
Stop!
So you're saying Charlie is here and Kyoko went in too?
Yeah
Looks like you need us after all Kyoko
There's a lot of artists here but none of them standout
You don't either
You suck
I am the president of MB Company
Charlie Takeshi
Are you not dissatisfied with your lives?
That's not right
You have talent. Everyone around you is an idiot
Don't you agree?
But that is only because you haven't unleashed your true power!
Look at me
A man like me who is 4 and a half feet tall (142 cm)
Runs a company that brings in 8 billion yen each year
And has 4 beautiful women around him
All this because of these cells, just like pure cotton
And I will share them with everyone
From... my body!
Now, suck them in
What's that. Gross!
Idiot. This is the happiness mist
Breathe it in
Is the mist working?
Now you can return to your true forms
For instance, the folk rock guy over there!
You mean me?
You sing love songs on the street corners
But actually you take advantage of people's anxiety!
You filthy criminal!
I'll give you a suitable form!
My face is melting!
Hey hey, that guy got turned into a zombie! Isn't this bad?
Nah, he just got too excited
Oho?
I see a beautiful girl over there
What do you see in the mist?
Me?
Punchy, we're busting in!
Roger!
She's an intruder!
After her!
Close #21!
Now, you will see a vision of what you desire!
I... want to disappear so...
I think I want a castle!
Huh? What's that?
Why is it so blurry?
Someone is there?
It's me?
And... Yumicko!?
Why am I in a swimsuit!? And a watermelon?!
That's good! You can split it!
Why am I splitting watermelons with Yumicko!?
And I look like I'm having way too much fun?
Good luck with your novel Kyoko! We have watermelon too!
And I've started writing a novel?
Happily?!
There's no way!
This is what you really want
No no no. No way!
It's all lies!
What a scam. You tiny fraud!
You called me tiny!?
It's an intruder!
Catch her!
An office?
The intruder! Hold it right there!
I'm trapped!
Farting is embarrassing! Too embarrassing!
I'm so embarrassed
Alright!
I was so embarrassed
Playtime is over!
Get moving!
Koushi!
I... I can't move!
Pull yourself together!
From now on this is your home!
Hey!
Don't leave me behind!
What's that? It's like smoke?
My face is burning
They're all turning into zombies!
This is bad Kouji. Let's run!
What's this door!?
Kouji!
The zombies are coming! They'll make me one too!
Oww! It hurts!
Kouji!
If someone was going to bite me
I'd want it to be you
Kyoko, take my base as a memento
Kyoko!
We've long been waiting to welcome you
By force!
Oww!
But that was my memento
Sorry!
Kyoko? Kyoko!!
You ok?
Billy, Kyoko is trying to escape. Catch her
Got it
Where are we?
We've ended up in some strange place with no one around
No! Someone is here!
Manga is so fun!
We can just do our work some other time
Eww who are these people?
We're the manga slacker family, and this is our meeting place
Manga slacker family?
Thanks to the seminar, we realized that lying around reading manga is way better than working
We're all failures at life anyways
Let's just ignore them and go
Yeah
That teddy bear is looking down at us!
Unforgivable!
They're reading manga while rolling after us!
And they're fast!
Now they've started break dancing! That's really disturbing!
Not good! This is bad! Dangerous!
He's here!
You really did come for me!
I always believed you'd come save me!
I always wanted to meet you again!
Nuigulumar! I wanted to see you!
Did she say Nuigulumar?
Princess... that's a terrible mistake
Yumicko!
That's...!
Good to see you
Hey!
What am I saying...
Stop bothering me
What are you doing here? It's dangerous!
Dangerous? I came because I was worried!
I skipped work...
That's not fair!
I see..
Well sorry, I was insensitive
Now hurry and run!
Let's go!
And you're older than me so stop being so polite!
What's wrong? Hurry up!
Yumicko? Yumicko!
[Shonen Attack]
Hurry up Yumicko!
What are you waiting for? Hurry!
I'm jealous. You have someone who cares for you
I don't have anyone like that
This is bad Yumicko. They're back!
Why I wonder...
It was such a shock
I've never seen Kyoko make a happy face like that before
So long as I was Nuigulumar, I thought Kyoko would never show me a face like that
I want to smash everything!
NUIGULUMAR!!!
What? What is this feeling?
What's happening?
President, I brought Kyoko
So we meet again, dear Kyoko
Don't call me dear
Don't make that face. So cold.
Billy, you too
That's not true
Billy, do you not agree perhaps?
With dear Kyoko becoming my wife?
What? Me? Your wife!?
So lucky!
We are all so jealous!
President! I was the first to pledge my loyalty to you!
I'll be your one and only wife!
Oh?
I don't remember making you my wife
A bullied girl on the brink of suicide
You should be happy enough that I made you a warrior!
I am forever grateful!
Remember that mist you breathed in?
When women inhale it they become hopelessly attracted to me
Isn't that right?
Yes!
He's an amazing man
There's no way!
I've... never fallen in love
Not with anyone
Help me
Damn I'm pissed!
That surprised me!
Where is this? Where is Kyoko!
Where's Punchy?
This is MB Company's surveillance room
Soon our plan to use all these brainwashed humans will begin
Plan? What are you going to do!?
I'll take over expwaining from here!
A baby?
I am the baby human, Hajime!
I once wanted to become terrorist
But now I've become the most harmwess of cweatures
Harmless? Really?
Big sis
Soon I'm gonna rewease a lot of zombies into Tokyo
It will be sooo twagic
Zombies into the city?
No one could do something so horrible!
But he can do it
Babies are so innocent after all
Hajime, I'll show you something good
So press the button!
Ok!
Oh no!
All that's left is the button for the front entrance
But Punchy and Kyoko are both in danger too
Who will you save?
You coward!
Now, come on
Pretty!
Come on
The mist is working now
Now, let's begin the marriage
First...
I met someone named Yumicko here
Could you let her go?
What a coincidence
I've got someone connected to her here
Here!
That's!
Punchy!
Princess, I'm sorry you are seeing me like this!
I couldn't protect you!
It talked!?
Listen, as proof of our love
I want you to execute that monster with your own hands
Execute!?
My hand is moving on it's own!
Shoot him. Blow him to bits!
Deparza why!?
Why do you have so much hate towards humans!?
I hate their shallowness
Never mind upbringing, even just from the size or position of the eyes, a human's fate can be determined.
I felt sad for Takeshi
Takeshi lived in poverty with his uncle
One day, he stole his uncle's money
And bought a knitted teddy bear
As a present
For a girl he had a crush on
But
It was a trap
While this happened
The cotton like alien descended
They combined
And became a knitted teddy bear!
Their purpose:
To bring disaster to all humans!
If I'm unhappy, I'm going to make all of humanity equally unhappy!
Using all the power I have attained!
Now, execute him Kyoko!
Princess, you are just being deceived by the mist
Focus your imagination on your true feelings
Overcome your own thoughts!
Imagination?
That's right. To me that teddy bear was...
Proof of love
The ones who made it were mama and...
Yumicko
Punchy!
I can't!
No!
What are you doing Kyoko!?
I don't love you
Yes! Thanks!
Nice moves!
You betrayed me!
This debt may be repayed later
But I don't want to be part of a creep's plans
Until now, my life may have been dictated by my powers
But from now on, I live my own life!
Traitor!
Let's go!
Emergency. Emergency.
Billy has escaped
Capture him immediately
Emergency. Emergency.
Billy has escaped
Miss Lolita, Billy has escaped
Damn, that bitch Kyoko ran off
What'll you do? You must be worried to death
That's not true!
Huh?
Kyoko has the strength and kindness to stand up for herself
I believe in her!
That kinda pisses me off
Hajime, time to make you a maniac
Huh? A maniac?
A beauty is eating messily. That's your fetish right?
Don't get worked up over that!
Oh no! I accidentally got some on my boobs!
No!
The zombies are dancing to the beat!
The whythm makes them more viowent!
It's hell's Awa Dance Festival dance
Awa Dance Festival?
There's an Awa Dance Festival event happening nearby
The tragedy will start there!
Then I'll do the Awa Dance too!
You ok Yumicko?
Little baby, it's nappy time!
This is terrible!
I'm so excited we're getting a new shopping mall here!
Me too, it's great that they're hosting this Awa Dance Festival for the opening
And J.A. is doing an action show too!
Really? An action show!
My chest feels so hot
Let's do our best!
Yeah!
It sounds like the Awa rhythm, and it's getting closer
What's that!?
The dead are dancing towards us!
Kyoko
What is it?
There's something I have to tell you
I am not a man
I'm a woman
Yes, I know
And... I'm not Nuigulumar
Then who is?
That person you call Yumicko. I attacked and injured her before
No... I may have killed her
What do you mean?
But she revived, in order to save you
We need to quickly escape and deal with the situation outside!
I know, but there's one thing I have to settle first
I can't fight otherwise
Take all of this you traitor!
Go ahead first! I'll follow after!
Hurry!
Don't try and act cool!
Billy!
It's nothing! Hurry up and go!
Yumicko! Save Billy!
Coming to me only when you need my help is a bad habit you know.
I want to talk with you as equals
So I won't be so polite anymore, Kyoko
Yumicko...
I'm not protecting you because sis asked me to
It's frustrating but...
It's because I love you
Punchy, Billy and sis are the same
So thinking that no one wants you
Is just selfish and childish
Be more honest with yourself
If you need help, say it properly
Help me
More politely
Deep down, I knew that I had already accepted you for a long time now
I'm sorry
So please, save Billy!
I don't care what happens to me
Please!
Ok
Nuigulumar!
Here we go!
You bitch!
You damn bitch!
This is how it should be, mama
It's not over yet!
If you don't hold on tight you'll fall
I know that
I've always wanted to
Get ready
I'm so happy for you two
We've arrived
Thank you
Billy!
Are you ok? Hang on Billy!
Somehow...
Yumicko
I'm going to go do what a hero must do
We're going Punchy!
Roger Yumicko!
Excuse me, this one is very cute
Yes that is our most popular item at the-
Help me!
Excuse me! Please, I need help! Hey!
Stop!
The proper etiquette for those who have died once is not to trouble the living
If you can't accept that, I'll be your opponent!
Damn
Punchy!
Roger! Yumicko!
Nuigulumar!
She did it!
Yumicko!
Damnit, that Nuigulumar bitch
Will you all make Nuigulumar suffer for me?
Of course!
Why?
I wasn't asking you. You keep screwing up
I'm done with you
But I loved you...
Then we'll be going
Hey! Hey, you ok?
Lolita? Hey!
Lolita!
Leave her!
You are too soft
You should just be silent and combine with me Deparza
I will finish this myself
Worthless insects
I will exterminate you all at once
Now, let's activate our given power!
Yes!
Embarrassing...
Really embarrassing
Same
Incredibly embarrassing...
Embarrassing...
I've been charged full of embarrassment energy!
Let's get more embarrassed
No...
I hate this. This is awful
Our power is fully charged
Everyone, pour the power into your breasts
This is too awful
They stripped... Look out, they're coming this way!
Not good
Run! Run!
A laser attack too? That's not fair!
Yumicko!
Kyoko!
What do you think? Now I can fly!
Charlie you bastard!
You shit!
You toyed with my fucking maiden's heart!
Look out!
How dare you!
I can't. We can't transform anymore
You cannot stop me
When this secret weapon on my back explodes
All of humanity will die miserably!
Why not just let them live?
Just because you are unhappy? That's stupid!
Everyone has problems. They work hard to move past them!
I don't care!
Deparza! Please, show yourself!
Regain your noble warrior spirit!
Deparza is gone
He died within me!
What? No! You're lying!
He's alive! Aliiive!
Within minutes, you will all be dead
No, I won't let you
Even if it's impossible!
I will defeat Charlie
Even if it's impossible, I will chase after him
For Kyoko, and for everyone
I'll make the impossible possible!
Yumicko
At an important time like this, I can't do anything
That's not true
We need to find his weakpoint
Weakpoint?
There!
Use this guitar to control the zombies!
Me!?
I've never played live before
But I guess I have to!
More! More violently!
Put your heart into it!
More! With feeling!
Thank you Kyoko!
We did it! The zombies stopped!
But, now what do we do?
You have a talent for writing right?
Try and release your imagination. I'll turn that image into reality
Turn imagination into reality?
That's right
I'll try
Now, picture it
When something sad happens, I want you to be able to use that imagination to move past it
You can do that
Stop!
I still believe! My friend is still alive inside him!
Look out!
Yumicko once more transforms into Nuigulumar
With all of us together, I know she can do it
I will make her transform
Keep going. Imagine the future you want
Yumicko into Nuigulumar
Together
What was that!?
Deparza stop!
Dumuva, I feel the same!
If I'm going to combine, I want it to be with you
Deparza!
Come back to me!
Dumuva, I'm coming!
No, Deparza!
Deparza!
Dumuva, here I come!
Welcome back!
I'm back. I'm so happy
Deparza!
Dumuva!
I'm happy too
I missed you
Yumicko will definitely win
She won't lose to him
She too has wings
And... She can fly!
That hero's name...
Her name is...
Nuigulumar!
Z!
I won't let you!
We maidens shall be forever!
I'm a goth till I die!
Lolita!
Oh no! The bomb, that was close!
Kyoko, I won't lose
Dear friends wandering through space, lend us your strength!
Please, join with us!
My friends!!!
Everyone...
Damn!
Everyone disappear!
I won't let you!
Rolling Punchy Deparza Attack!!
Curse you!
My friends, the cotton alien lifeforms
You got rid of Charlie and the bomb didn't you?
You sacrificed yourselves and protected us
Thank you
She did it!
Nuigulumar... Yumicko and Punchy won!
They did it!
Billy!
Billy hang on!
Are you ok? Billy!
It wasn't pointless was it?
My being born into this world. Kyoko
That's right
You saved everyone
Thank you
I'm so glad I met you
Billy!
Let's...
Go home
After that, Kyoko fulfilled her mama's wish and wrote a book
That story which was based on her experiences won the grand prize in the teen novel contest!
I made myself a big salad!
Punchy is late
Yes, he is. It's your birthday and your prize winning celebration too!
Yuckyko, you did give him the right address, right?
You are pretty ditzy
Who's ditzy! I told him the right place
We'll see
Should I stop calling you Yumicko?
It's fine!
It's a good memory now, and I'm just happy you are doing your best
Hey, you serious?
I'm going on a journey.
They've made up now, so it's a good opportunity
I see
If you are going, I will go with you
Really!? Great!
Yumicko and the Princess don't need teddy bears anymore
And if they ever do need us, we'll appear and combine
So manly
Don't move! This is a stick up!
Gimme all your money!
A robber!
Oh no! Let's go Punchy!
Roger Yumicko!
Nuigulumar!
I was finally able to transform as Yumicko!
Not judging moments of clumsyness, the healing and fighting teddy bear!
The delightful hero, Nuigulumar arrives!
I will protect the Princess
I swear on these button eyes!