Aimi?!
It's OK, Dad. Hurry back.
They won't kill you now.
Dad! Hurry!
Here's one, dad.
For rent:
2BR apartment, 70,000/mo.
That one...
It doesn't look bad...
But it's a 35 year-old building,
a long way from the station...
Well, we have to compromise
on some things, don't we?
Mr. Yamato?
Yes.
I've been expecting you,
I'm Ebisu, the Building Manager.
This way, please.
It's old, but it's been well maintained.
It's very comfortable.
I live with my wife
on the first floor.
We've been here, how long?
Three years now...
Is the young lady in high school?
Yes. In Grade 11.
I see...
Excuse me.
Let's see... 301...
Come in.
The building's owner
lives out in the country.
It was built by a relative of his.
I understand he inherited it
when the first owner died.
Is it sound-proof?
I can't have thin walls.
I write at home,
so it can't be too noisy.
Write? You mean novels
or something?
No, I'm a freelance journalist.
I write about nice Italian restaurants'
or popular dating spots.
Dumb stuff like that.
I see...
Well, Aimi?
I like it...
Thank you very much!
I never thought
you'd decide so fast!
Oh, I'm so happy!
So you'll move in a week from now?
We'll be waiting.
Until then...
It's more than 35 years old...
Aimi!
Thus I first encountered
"the haunted apartments".
There I experienced fear...
...and more than that,
a grief that was deep and dark.
TALES OF TERROR
"The Haunted Apartments"
Show him in.
Mr. Yamato,
these are the residents.
How do you do.
I'm Hotei, from 103.
My wife, Masami.
How do you do.
Izumo, from 201, and my wife
We're right below you.
If you need anything, just ask.
I'm Kotobuki, from 203.
This is my boyfriend.
What?
How do you do.
Oh... I'm Yamato.
This is my daughter...
"Ai"
Is something wrong?
Aimi: Summer Clothes
Your name's Aimi?
What a pretty name!
It sure is! It suits her.
Well, everyone...
Let us help. It's the 3rd floor
and there's no elevator.
Many hands make light work!
Uh, thank you.
Wait, slow down a bit...
Are you OK? Shall I take it?
No, I'm fine. Sorry.
Where should we put this?
Uh, let me see...
In that corner for now.
You OK?
I've got it. You can let go.
301?
Yes.
I'm Takashi Izumo, from 201.
How do you do.
You're the first person my age here.
Isn't there a girl about my age?
With long hair, kind of pale...
There's no one like that.
Hello.
They all seem nice.
Too damn nice.
That's why I hate apartments.
But it's my fault. I'm useless.
I'm sorry.
Don't apologize.
It'll be fine.
I just hate to think of the house
we lived in with mom...
...belonging to someone else.
This place is fine.
Mom...
...as of today, this is our home.
...the truth is...
...I don't want to be here!
Aimi...
Aimi!
Coming.
What?
Here.
We're not unpacked yet.
That's OK.
Dad...
I've told you before...
...it's not your fault Mom died.
We're starting over now.
So...
...won't you quit drinking?
Dad?
Please...
Certificate of Commendation
Um, I've just moved into 301...
Come on you two!
Quick! Get in!
Come on!
In you get!
Um...
It's not our fault.
Be back by midnight.
You have to be inside this rope
by 12 o'clock at night.
Why?
It's a regulation here.
Regulation?
Make absolutely sure
you don't break it.
Oh, and you'd better
tell your father, too.
Having to be back by midnight...
that's weird.
A curfew!
You'd think this was a school dorm!
Really!
Um...
...here.
The manager gave me your new address.
It's near my school.
Thank you.
What did you mean,
"It's not our fault"?
There's something weird
about that building.
It's got funny rules,
and those rocks out front...
And there's a girl my age there,
but they say there isn't.
You saw her?
That building is cursed.
I remember when
we first moved in there...
Coming!
It's the Manager.
Oh, yes...
Everything's all right?
Uh, yes, we're fine.
Make sure you observe the curfew.
And here's the building circular.
And your daughter's name...
...and the name of the daughter
of the building's first owner...
...are exactly the same!
So his daughter was named...
I suggest you don't say her name
when you're on this property.
I thought that was crazy,
so I didn't pay it any mind.
Papa! Dinner.
"A-chan"! Eat your carrots,
will you?
You too, "Takkun".
Chew your food.
Let's eat!
Papa! Leave the TV off
while we're eating.
It's OK.
No!
Let's do what Mama says.
This looks good!
Eat up those carrots.
What's wrong?
Hm?
Nothing, nothing.
Papa, wake up...
What's that noise?
Papa...
It's OK.
Takumi!
Takkun?
There's something strange
about this place!
Let's move!
We can't afford to.
We'd lose our deposit.
That's mine!
Both of you, be quiet!
Takumi!
Ai!
What are you doing?!
Papa, help!
Let go!
I can't!
What are you talking about!
Ai!
Let go!
Papa, pull him off!
Takumi! Takumi!
Mariko!
There's no choice!
Don't be stupid!
He's killing Ai!
No, Mama!
Forgive me!
No! No!
Never say my name again.
Those are "the haunted apartments"
It's haunted by the daughter
of the man who had it built.
About 30 years ago,
when she was 17...
...she vanished on her way
home from school.
They say she loved her home
so much...
...she came back to it as a ghost.
That's who you saw.
She's very lonely,
so she calls other spirits.
And if a resident
doesn't get home by midnight...
...it's as if they'd betrayed her.
She kills them.
That's crazy!
No one believed it at first.
But the people
who didn't get back by 12...
...or the people who moved out...
...all died mysteriously,
right after midnight.
In 30 years, 13 families have died.
But you're alive, and a day's passed
since you moved out.
There's one rule that saves us.
A "rule"?
When someone new moves in,
the oldest tenants can leave.
The residents figured that out
over the years.
We'd been there the longest,
and then you moved in.
We've been set free.
At last I can say my girl's name.
They're 12 years old.
They're in middle school.
Hello.
Aren't you going in?
Um...
...have you ever violated curfew?
Come home after midnight?
Nobody who lives here
ever does that.
That's why we're alive.
We get to leave next.
I'm scared.
I don't want to go in there.
Why is all this happening to me?!
Two years ago, my mother died
in a car accident.
Then my dad fell apart.
And now...
I'm sick of all this!
It's OK, it won't all be bad forever.
One day you'll get out of here.
And if anything scares you,
just yell out the window.
I'm right below you.
I'll come running.
Come on.
This is stupid!
"Haunted apartments"!
You don't believe it?
Supernatural phenomena
are just products of the mind.
A moving curtain looks like someone.
You think your own shadow's a ghost.
Enough nonsense. Time for bed.
Yuichi, Noriko and Takashi Izumo
Notice of transfer: Osaka
I asked the Department Head
to wait till tomorrow for an answer.
But I doubt we'll have anyone new
moving in right away.
Should I refuse the transfer?
Wait a minute!
What if we end up
like Mr. and Mrs. Hotei in 103?
I couldn't live like that!
And how would we put Takashi
through university?
That's OK.
No, it's not!
I'm fed up with having my life run
by this apartment building!
Here.
Thanks.
You get home from school real late.
Is your dad OK there alone?
My dad doesn't believe in ghosts.
You saw Mrs. Hotei, from 103...
They have money problems.
Mr. Hotei used to work at
a blue-chip company.
He refused a transfer because of
this building, and got in trouble.
He had to quit.
New jobs are hard to find these days.
My parents don't want that.
We're going to Osaka.
Osaka?
Dad's accepting a transfer.
But if you do that...
We won't know till we try.
We'll survive. I know we will.
We might even lift the curse.
Then you'll be free.
So if we do manage to stay alive...
...can I see you again?
Will you think about it?
They're crazy!
Yeah! They're next in line...
They're even willing
to sacrifice their son!
Takashi! This is the last.
It's all yours.
Um...
...here.
My mother made it.
I've kept it as a good-luck charm.
I can't take that!
I want to see you again.
Thank you.
Well...
I'd better go buy some things
for dinner.
Aw, Mom! What are you doing?
We'll be OK, won't we? That curse
can't reach all the way to Osaka...
...Can it?
Let's go out somewhere
where there's lots of people.
We'll be fine.
As long as we're here, we're fine.
We have to get out of here!
Dad? Mom?
Mom?
Takashi! Help!
Dad?!
Takashi!
Dad?
Dad!
Takashi! Help me!
You can kill me!
But let her go!
Just let her out of that building!
Please!
I'm saved!
Takashi, are you all right?
She disappeared.
Really?
I'm all right. I'm safe.
Thanks to you.
Takashi...
Where's the charm I gave you?
Sir?
Madam?
...after discussion
with his lawyers.
In other news, a family of three
have died mysteriously...
...in an all-night restaurant.
Just after midnight this morning,
in "F" restaurant in Osaka...
...Yuichi Izumo, his wife Noriko
and son Takashi...
...were found dead at their table,
their hands linked.
Mr. and Mrs. Izumo had been stabbed,
and their son strangled...
...but no weapon was found.
No witnesses have emerged,
although the restaurant was busy.
All three were apparently
in good health...
...before a brief power failure
ay exactly 12 midnight.
Aimi!
I'm coming in.
What happened?
"Haunted apartments"...
Did they die?
Yes. All three of them.
How?
The husband and wife were stabbed.
Young Takashi was strangled.
The poor thing!
You suffer the most being strangled.
Could I have some water?
Sorry to be so much trouble.
I'm the one to say that.
But Shizu...
...finally we're the ones
who get to leave next.
Yes...
But I wonder how many nights
there'll be until that happens...
Whose turn is it?
Mine.
How?
I was taken by the enemy...
...and strangled.
Proceed. Give vent to your rage.
Couldn't it be me tonight?
Kill me if you have to kill anyone.
My wife has done nothing!
That's why we kill her.
Lieutenant...
...vengeance is best taken on
the one its object loves best.
Please! Stop killing my wife!
Please!
Once we begged you.
"Don't leave us," we said.
"We want to go back to Japan!"
But to save yourself...
...you abandoned us.
You left us there.
I was wrong!
At least don't strangle her!
Please!
I see... all right...
We'll strangle her every night.
Umihiko...
Forgive me!
Would it be better
if I just killed you myself?
You promised me, remember?
You said once we got out of here...
...We'd go back up home
to Miyazaki.
Let's pray...
...that real, real soon...
...a new tenant will move in here.
But the night will come again,
won't it?
Kotobuki
'Morning, Sho.
The Izumis died. I knew they would.
They did?
It was on TV.
What's your problem?
This is your fault!
You're the one
who brought me here!
You wrecked my whole life!
If this place wasn't cursed,
would you move out?
What are you talking about?
Would I still be with an old cow
like you if it wasn't?!
Money.
For Pachinko.
What's that?
That's not enough.
I've only got 1,000 more.
You're broke too!
You're awful!
Anyway, Akemi...
What?
Come out with me for once!
Sorry, I've got a cat.
I have to catch the last bus.
It won't starve in one night!
It'll die of loneliness.
So will I!
Silly!
Take care. See you again!
Thanks!
Thank you!
What's with her?
Don't worry. She's always like that.
Good night!
Hey, you!
Sorry! It's an emergency!
Tanashi, and hurry!
What's going on?!
An accident maybe...
Who'd have an accident
at this time of night!
I'll get out.
That's 1,290.
Oh, damn that Sho!
I'm sorry, this is all I have.
I can't do that, ma'am...
OK, here. Take these.
Look, lady...
Oh, come on! It's only 190!
Hey! Officer! Over here! Officer!
Hey, you! Stop!
Hey!
Hold it!
Stop!
Hold it, you!
Where'd she go?
What's wrong?
We're a bit worried.
Akemi's not back yet.
She's usually here by now.
We hear her come in.
What do you want?!
Where's Akemi?
How would I know?
She's not answering her phone.
Where am I?!
Sho! Help me!
Help me!
Akemi!
Sho!
Akemi! Akemi!
What are you doing?!
Get on, quick!
Here goes! How long have we got?
Less than four minutes!
Sho...
...I could die happy right now.
What are you talking about?!
Hang on, will you!
Everyone, get inside the line.
Hurry! Get inside!
There!
Quick! You've got to hurry!
Faster!
Hurry!
Come on!
Come on! You can do it!
Yes! Come on!
Five seconds...
Sho?
Sho! Sho!
Isn't it great Akemi made it!
Yeah!
And now we have no food at all!
The water's been shut off.
What?!
It has?
You shouldn't have married me.
I don't mind.
So what about dinner?
Bon appétit!
It's good!
It sure is!
You're working hard.
Hello. Are you going out?
Could I talk to you?
About what?
I drink myself to sleep
every night...
...so I don't see "things".
My daughter's terrified.
What are they like?
School Study Excursion
"Osaka"...
I'd like to go...
...and visit his grave.
"Ai Takamatsu, 17, in Grade 11,
has been reported missing".
"Her father Shigeaki says
that on the night of the 6th...
...she did not return to school".
"'I'm sure something happened
on her way home.' he said."
On her way home...
Just getting home, Ai?
It must be nice
to always look so young!
Look! My cat's gone and died again!
Um... "Ai"?
Oh, you're not her...
Did Ai live in that building?
A beautiful young girl, she was.
Just like you.
She went missing, didn't she?
Coming home from school.
That's a lie.
I saw her!
She came home that day.
No one believed me, but I saw her!
She came home?
What do you want?!
Mr. Yamato, I certainly hope
you're not betraying us.
Betraying you?
You're writing an article
about this building, aren't you!
You were an ace reporter
for a weekly scandal magazine...
Shouldn't I?
People are dying here!
Of course I'm writing about it.
Oh, I get it...
You want some of the money,
do you?
If I make anything, I'll share it.
OK?
It's not the damn money!
If people find out about this place,
no one'll move in.
We'll never get out.
We're all linked by fate.
No one acts on his own!
Go away.
Go away!
Leave!
Get out of here!
Aimi, get inside.
Go!
What happened?
"Don't write," they say.
Dad...
Ghost stories always draw people.
This place'll be famous.
This might be my last chance.
I'll leave this here.
She comes here...
It's Yamato.
Did you read the article I sent?
You didn't get it?
Really?
Just a second...
Task Error
What the hell?!
Sorry...
I'll bring it right over.
You old bastard!
You're not leaving.
You're not going anywhere.
What the hell?!
Kill him!
Back away!
Dad?
Are you OK?
They've gone crazy!
Are we going to get killed?
Aimi! Get stuff that burns!
I'm letting go!
Quick, dad!
Here goes...
Aimi? Are you OK?
It's nearly 12.
They can't come out here.
You get away.
I can find the source of the
curse by midnight.
That'll stop them.
Get going!
Quick!
Let go.
I...
...want to be free.
Please!
Ai...
It must have been agony...
...being closed in there.
And so lonely...
Aimi!
It's OK, dad. Hurry back.
They won't kill you now.
Dad!
Hurry, Dad!
Aimi!
Dad...
It's your fault
they went crazy like like that.
You shouldn't do things
that people really don't want you to.
I was wrong.
I'm sorry.
The real line...
...is here.
Serves you right.
Dad, no!
The same thing...
...happened to you.
I'm back.
Ai, you're home!
Come here...
Stop it, Dad!
No!
Ow!
You bitch!
Everyone's gone.
But...
...I'm not going anywhere.
I'll be with you...
...forever.
Aimi
Mei Kurokawa
Aimi's Father
Mitsuru Fukikoshi